<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liturgies on Shared Prayers</title>
    <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liturgies on Shared Prayers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Maundy Thursday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-maundythurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-maundythurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 274ff.)&lt;br&gt;
9 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-these-prayers&#34;&gt;Share These Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/images/qr/holywk-maundyth.gif&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.sharedprayer.net/litugies/holywk-maundythurs&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to scan this QR code to pray with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/MaundyTh_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Set out a bowl of water and a clean towel. Light a candle. Sit with them before you and then begin by remembering God’s forgiveness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-penitential-order&#34;&gt;A Penitential Order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord who forgives all our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God’s mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the commandments of God to God’s people: I am the Lord your God who brought you out of bondage. You shall have no other gods but me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any idol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not invoke with malice the Name of the Lord your God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the Sabbath Day and keep it holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honor your father and your mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not be a false witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not covet anything that belongs to your neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. &lt;em&gt;(Hebrews 4:14, 16 NRSV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-may-be-kept&#34;&gt;Silence may be kept.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done, and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us, forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen us in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy God,&lt;br&gt;
Holy and Mighty,&lt;br&gt;
Holy Immortal One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have mercy upon us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-proper-to-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty Father, whose dear Son, on the night before he suffered, instituted the Sacrament of his Body and Blood: Mercifully grant that we may receive it thankfully in remembrance of Jesus Christ our Lord, who in these holy mysteries gives us a pledge of eternal life; and who now lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Exodus 12:1-14 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Exodus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord said to Moses and Aaron in the land of Egypt: This month shall mark for you the beginning of months; it shall be the first month of the year for you. Tell the whole congregation of Israel that on the tenth of this month they are to take a lamb for each family, a lamb for each household. If a household is too small for a whole lamb, it shall join its closest neighbour in obtaining one; the lamb shall be divided in proportion to the number of people who eat of it. Your lamb shall be without blemish, a year-old male; you may take it from the sheep or from the goats. You shall keep it until the fourteenth day of this month; then the whole assembled congregation of Israel shall slaughter it at twilight. They shall take some of the blood and put it on the two doorposts and the lintel of the houses in which they eat it. They shall eat the lamb that same night; they shall eat it roasted over the fire with unleavened bread and bitter herbs. Do not eat any of it raw or boiled in water, but roasted over the fire, with its head, legs, and inner organs. You shall let none of it remain until the morning; anything that remains until the morning you shall burn. This is how you shall eat it: your loins girded, your sandals on your feet, and your staff in your hand; and you shall eat it hurriedly. It is the passover of the Lord. For I will pass through the land of Egypt that night, and I will strike down every firstborn in the land of Egypt, both human beings and animals; on all the gods of Egypt I will execute judgements: I am the Lord. The blood shall be a sign for you on the houses where you live: when I see the blood, I will pass over you, and no plague shall destroy you when I strike the land of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day shall be a day of remembrance for you. You shall celebrate it as a festival to the Lord; throughout your generations you shall observe it as a perpetual ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 116:1,10-17&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Dilexi, quoniam&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 759)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1  I love the Lord, because he has heard the voice of my supplication, *&lt;br&gt;
because he has inclined his ear to me whenever I called upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 How shall I repay the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
for all the good things he has done for me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 I will lift up the cup of salvation *&lt;br&gt;
and call upon the Name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 I will fulfill my vows to the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
in the presence of all his people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Precious in the sight of the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
is the death of his servants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 O Lord, I am your servant; *&lt;br&gt;
I am your servant and the child of your handmaid; you have freed me from my bonds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 I will offer you the sacrifice of thanksgiving *&lt;br&gt;
and call upon the Name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 I will fulfill my vows to the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
in the presence of all his people,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 In the courts of the Lord’s house, *&lt;br&gt;
in the midst of you, O Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hallelujah!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;1 Corinthians 11:23-26 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s first letter to the church at Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I received from the Lord what I also handed on to you, that the Lord Jesus on the night when he was betrayed took a loaf of bread, and when he had given thanks, he broke it and said, ‘This is my body that is for you. Do this in remembrance of me.’ In the same way he took the cup also, after supper, saying, ‘This cup is the new covenant in my blood. Do this, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of me.’ For as often as you eat this bread and drink the cup, you proclaim the Lord’s death until he comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 13:1-17, 31b-35 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before the festival of the Passover, Jesus knew that his hour had come to depart from this world and go to the Father. Having loved his own who were in the world, he loved them to the end. The devil had already put it into the heart of Judas son of Simon Iscariot to betray him. And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God, got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to wipe them with the towel that was tied around him. He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, ‘Lord, are you going to wash my feet?’ Jesus answered, ‘You do not know now what I am doing, but later you will understand.’ Peter said to him, ‘You will never wash my feet.’ Jesus answered, ‘Unless I wash you, you have no share with me.’ Simon Peter said to him, ‘Lord, not my feet only but also my hands and my head!’ Jesus said to him, ‘One who has bathed does not need to wash, except for the feet, but is entirely clean. And you are clean, though not all of you.’ For he knew who was to betray him; for this reason he said, ‘Not all of you are clean.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he had washed their feet, had put on his robe, and had returned to the table, he said to them, ‘Do you know what I have done to you? You call me Teacher and Lord—and you are right, for that is what I am. So if I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also ought to wash one another’s feet. For I have set you an example, that you also should do as I have done to you. Very truly, I tell you, servants are not greater than their master, nor are messengers greater than the one who sent them. If you know these things, you are blessed if you do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he had gone out, Jesus said, ‘Now the Son of Man has been glorified, and God has been glorified in him. If God has been glorified in him, God will also glorify him in himself and will glorify him at once. Little children, I am with you only a little longer. You will look for me; and as I said to the Jews so now I say to you, “Where I am going, you cannot come.” I give you a new commandment, that you love one another. Just as I have loved you, you also should love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you-may-access-a-homily-online-at-the-church-website-or-you-may-want-to-use-the-following-meditation&#34;&gt;You may access a homily online at the church website. Or you may want to use the following meditation.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This word about the love of Jesus is always the beginning of any time.  By remembering the Passover and the Last Supper and the footwashing, we are not trying to get back to an old time.  In the face of the suffering and death with which the world is filled, our trying would not come to much.  But God’s word comes to us now.  To our time.  Even when we cannot meet for the holy supper together, this word — which takes these three nights to say — comes to us: Jesus Christ is our forgiveness.  He is the Lamb whose blood marks the doors of our houses and bodies.  In the power of the Spirit, he has washed our feet and our lives.  And he turns us toward our neighbors.  In this word — and in the cross proclaimed tomorrow and the resurrection proclaimed on Saturday night — Easter comes out to hold us already.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;this-is-the-time-when-we-wash-feet-recalling-jesus-washing-his-disciples-feet-the-washing-of-his-disciples-feet-was-a-demonstration-of-christs-love-for-us-and-was-followed-immediately-with-a-new-commandment-that-we-love-one-another-as-he-loved-them-as-we-work-together-to-suppress-the-death-toll-of-the-covid-19-virus-washing-our-hands-is-an-expression-of-love-for-our-neighbor-here-you-may-wash-your-hands-using-the-water-in-the-bowl&#34;&gt;This is the time when we wash feet, recalling Jesus washing his disciples’ feet. The washing of his disciples’ feet was a demonstration of Christ’s love for us, and was followed immediately with a “new commandment”: that we love one another as he loved them. As we work together to suppress the death toll of the Covid-19 virus, washing our hands is an expression of love for our neighbor. Here you may wash your hands, using the water in the bowl.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United with Christians around the globe on this Maundy Thursday, let us pray for the church, the earth, our troubled world, and all in need, responding to each petition with the words, Your mercy is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, holy God, for the church. Gather all the baptized around your presence in the Word. Strengthen the body of your people even when we cannot assemble for worship. Grant Bishop Stokes and all our clergy faithfulness and creativity for their ministry in this time, and accompany those preparing for baptism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-1&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, bountiful God, for this good earth and for the flowering of springtime. Save dry lands from destructive droughts. Protect the waters from pollution. Allow in this time the planting of fields for food. Make us into care-givers of your plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-2&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, bountiful God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, sovereign God, for our nation. Inspire all people to live in peace and concord. Grant wisdom and courage to heads of state and to legislators as they face the coronavirus. Lead our elected officials to champion the cause of the needy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-3&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, sovereign God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, faithful God, for you accompany suffering humanity with love. Abide wherever the coronavirus has struck. Visit all who mourn their dead; all who have contracted the virus; those who are quarantined or stranded away from home; those who have lost their employment; those who fear the present and the future. Support physicians, nurses, and home health aides; medical researchers; and the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-4&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, faithful God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, gracious God, for you care for the needy. We beg you to feed the hungry, protect the refugee, embrace the distressed, house the homeless, nurse the sick, and comfort the dying. Especially we pray for those on our parish prayer list&amp;hellip; and for those others we name before you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-5&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, gracious God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, loving God, that your Son knelt before us, your unworthy servants. Preserve our lives, comfort our anxiety, and receive now the petitions of our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-longer-period-of-silence&#34;&gt;A longer period of silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, loving God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, eternal God, for all who have died in the faith, especially Marilyn and Donald, and those whom we name before you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-6&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, bring us with them into your everlasting glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hear us, eternal God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive, merciful God, our prayers, for the sake of Jesus Christ, the host of our meal of life, who died and rose that we might live with you, now and forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord’s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-final-rite-of-the-maundy-thursday-services-is-the-stripping-of-the-altar-herehttpsbuildfaithorgmaundy-thursday-at-home-you-will-find-a-suggestion-for-how-you-might-live-into-this-rite-at-home&#34;&gt;The final rite of the Maundy Thursday services is the stripping of the altar. &lt;a href=&#34;https://buildfaith.org/maundy-thursday-at-home/&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you will find a suggestion for how you might live into this rite at home.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-three-days-continue-tomorrow-with-the-service-for-good-friday&#34;&gt;The Three Days continue tomorrow with the service for Good Friday.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Wednesday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-epwed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-epwed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Wednesday, 8 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-these-prayers&#34;&gt;Share These Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/images/qr/holywk-epwed.gif&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.sharedprayer.net/litugies/holywk-epwed&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to scan this QR code to pray with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyWed_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will bless the Lord who gives me counsel; my heart teaches me, night after night.  I have set the Lord always before me; because he is at my right hand, I shall not fall.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 16:7,8)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praised, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 70&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Deus, in adjutorium&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 682&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Be pleased, O God, to deliver me; *&lt;br&gt;
O Lord, make haste to help me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Let those who seek my life be ashamed&lt;br&gt;
and altogether dismayed; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who take pleasure in my misfortune&lt;br&gt;
draw back and be disgraced.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Let those who say to me &amp;ldquo;Aha!&amp;rdquo; and gloat over me turn back, *&lt;br&gt;
because they are ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Let all who seek you rejoice and be glad in you; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who love your salvation say for ever,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Great is the Lord!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 But as for me, I am poor and needy; *&lt;br&gt;
come to me speedily, O God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 You are my helper and my deliverer; *&lt;br&gt;
O Lord, do not tarry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 50:4&amp;ndash;9a NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has given me&lt;br&gt;
the tongue of a teacher,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that I may know how to sustain&lt;br&gt;
the weary with a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning by morning he wakens&amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;
wakens my ear&lt;br&gt;
to listen as those who are taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has opened my ear,&lt;br&gt;
and I was not rebellious,&lt;br&gt;
I did not turn backward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave my back to those who struck me,&lt;br&gt;
and my cheeks to those who pulled out the beard;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not hide my face&lt;br&gt;
from insult and spitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God helps me;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have not been disgraced;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;therefore I have set my face like flint,&lt;br&gt;
and I know that I shall not be put to shame;&lt;br&gt;
he who vindicates me is near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who will contend with me?&lt;br&gt;
Let us stand up together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are my adversaries?&lt;br&gt;
Let them confront me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the Lord God who helps me;&lt;br&gt;
who will declare me guilty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hebrews 12:1&amp;ndash;3 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Hebrews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight and the sin that clings so closely, and let us run with perseverance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus the pioneer and perfecter of our faith, who for the sake of the joy that was set before him endured the cross, disregarding its shame, and has taken his seat at the right hand of the throne of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him who endured such hostility against himself from sinners, so that you may not grow weary or lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 13:21-32 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At supper with his friends, Jesus was troubled in spirit, and declared, &amp;ldquo;Very truly, I tell you, one of you will betray me.&amp;rdquo; The disciples looked at one another, uncertain of whom he was speaking. One of his disciples&amp;ndash; the one whom Jesus loved&amp;ndash; was reclining next to him; Simon Peter therefore motioned to him to ask Jesus of whom he was speaking. So while reclining next to Jesus, he asked him, &amp;ldquo;Lord, who is it?&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;It is the one to whom I give this piece of bread when I have dipped it in the dish.&amp;rdquo; So when he had dipped the piece of bread, he gave it to Judas son of Simon Iscariot. After he received the piece of bread, Satan entered into him. Jesus said to him, &amp;ldquo;Do quickly what you are going to do.&amp;rdquo; Now no one at the table knew why he said this to him. Some thought that, because Judas had the common purse, Jesus was telling him, &amp;ldquo;Buy what we need for the festival&amp;rdquo;; or, that he should give something to the poor. So, after receiving the piece of bread, he immediately went out. And it was night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he had gone out, Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Now the Son of Man has been glorified, and God has been glorified in him. If God has been glorified in him, God will also glorify him in himself and will glorify him at once.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&amp;rsquo; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord God, whose blessed Son our Savior gave his body to be whipped and his face to be spit upon: Give us grace to accept joyfully the sufferings of the present time, confident of the glory that shall be revealed; through Jesus Christ your Son our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glory to God whose power, working in us, can do infinitely more than we can ask or imagine:  Glory to him from generation to generation in the Church, and in Christ Jesus for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Ephesians 3:20,21)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Tuesday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-eptue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-eptue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Tuesday, 7 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-these-prayers&#34;&gt;Share These Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/images/qr/holywk-eptue.gif&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.sharedprayer.net/litugies/holywk-eptue&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to scan this QR code to pray with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyTue_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours is the day, O God, yours also the night; you established the moon and the sun.  You fixed all the boundaries of the earth; you made both summer and winter.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 74:15,16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praised, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 71:1-14&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;In te, Domine, speravi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 683&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 In you, O Lord, have I taken refuge; *&lt;br&gt;
let me never be ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 In your righteousness, deliver me and set me free; *&lt;br&gt;
incline your ear to me and save me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Be my strong rock, a castle to keep me safe; *&lt;br&gt;
you are my crag and my stronghold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Deliver me, my God, from the hand of the wicked, *&lt;br&gt;
from the clutches of the evildoer and the oppressor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 For you are my hope, O Lord God, *&lt;br&gt;
my confidence since I was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 I have been sustained by you ever since I was born;&lt;br&gt;
from my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb you have been my strength; *&lt;br&gt;
my praise shall be always of you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 I have become a portent to many; *&lt;br&gt;
but you are my refuge and my strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 Let my mouth be full of your praise *&lt;br&gt;
and your glory all the day long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Do not cast me off in my old age; *&lt;br&gt;
forsake me not when my strength fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 For my enemies are talking against me, *&lt;br&gt;
and those who lie in wait for my life take counsel together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 They say, &amp;ldquo;God has forsaken him;&lt;br&gt;
go after him and seize him; *&lt;br&gt;
because there is none who will save.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 O God, be not far from me; *&lt;br&gt;
come quickly to help me, O my God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Let those who set themselves against me be put to shame and be disgraced; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who seek to do me evil be covered with scorn and reproach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 But I shall always wait in patience, *&lt;br&gt;
and shall praise you more and more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 49:1&amp;ndash;7 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to me, O coastlands,&lt;br&gt;
pay attention, you peoples from far away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord called me before I was born,&lt;br&gt;
while I was in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb he named me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He made my mouth like a sharp sword,&lt;br&gt;
in the shadow of his hand he hid me;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he made me a polished arrow,&lt;br&gt;
in his quiver he hid me away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he said to me, &amp;ldquo;You are my servant,&lt;br&gt;
Israel, in whom I will be glorified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I said, &amp;ldquo;I have labored in vain,&lt;br&gt;
I have spent my strength for nothing and vanity;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yet surely my cause is with the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
and my reward with my God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the Lord says,&lt;br&gt;
who formed me in the womb to be his servant,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to bring Jacob back to him,&lt;br&gt;
and that Israel might be gathered to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for I am honored in the sight of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
and my God has become my strength&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is too light a thing that you should be my servant&lt;br&gt;
to raise up the tribes of Jacob and to restore the survivors of Israel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will give you as a light to the nations,&lt;br&gt;
that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
the Redeemer of Israel and his Holy One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to one deeply despised, abhorred by the nations,&lt;br&gt;
the slave of rulers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kings shall see and stand up,&lt;br&gt;
princes, and they shall prostrate themselves,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because of the Lord, who is faithful,&lt;br&gt;
the Holy One of Israel, who has chosen you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;1 Corinthians 1:18&amp;ndash;31 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from Paul&amp;rsquo;s first letter to the church in Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message about the cross is foolishness to those who are perishing, but to us who are being saved it is the power of God. For it is written,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I will destroy the wisdom of the wise,&lt;br&gt;
and the discernment of the discerning I will thwart.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the one who is wise? Where is the scribe? Where is the debater of this age? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world? For since, in the wisdom of God, the world did not know God through wisdom, God decided, through the foolishness of our proclamation, to save those who believe. For Jews demand signs and Greeks desire wisdom, but we proclaim Christ crucified, a stumbling block to Jews and foolishness to Gentiles, but to those who are the called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God and the wisdom of God. For God&amp;rsquo;s foolishness is wiser than human wisdom, and God&amp;rsquo;s weakness is stronger than human strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider your own call, brothers and sisters: not many of you were wise by human standards, not many were powerful, not many were of noble birth. But God chose what is foolish in the world to shame the wise; God chose what is weak in the world to shame the strong; God chose what is low and despised in the world, things that are not, to reduce to nothing things that are, so that no one might boast in the presence of God. He is the source of your life in Christ Jesus, who became for us wisdom from God, and righteousness and sanctification and redemption, in order that, as it is written, &amp;ldquo;Let the one who boasts, boast in the Lord.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 12:20-36 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those who went up to worship at the festival were some Greeks. They came to Philip, who was from Bethsaida in Galilee, and said to him, &amp;ldquo;Sir, we wish to see Jesus.&amp;rdquo; Philip went and told Andrew; then Andrew and Philip went and told Jesus. Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;The hour has come for the Son of Man to be glorified. Very truly, I tell you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains just a single grain; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Those who love their life lose it, and those who hate their life in this world will keep it for eternal life. Whoever serves me must follow me, and where I am, there will my servant be also. Whoever serves me, the Father will honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now my soul is troubled. And what should I say&amp;ndash; `Father, save me from this hour&amp;rsquo;? No, it is for this reason that I have come to this hour. Father, glorify your name.&amp;rdquo; Then a voice came from heaven, &amp;ldquo;I have glorified it, and I will glorify it again.&amp;rdquo; The crowd standing there heard it and said that it was thunder. Others said, &amp;ldquo;An angel has spoken to him.&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;This voice has come for your sake, not for mine. Now is the judgment of this world; now the ruler of this world will be driven out. And I, when I am lifted up from the earth, will draw all people to myself.&amp;rdquo; He said this to indicate the kind of death he was to die. The crowd answered him, &amp;ldquo;We have heard from the law that the Messiah remains forever. How can you say that the Son of Man must be lifted up? Who is this Son of Man?&amp;rdquo; Jesus said to them, &amp;ldquo;The light is with you for a little longer. Walk while you have the light, so that the darkness may not overtake you. If you walk in the darkness, you do not know where you are going. While you have the light, believe in the light, so that you may become children of light.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus had said this, he departed and hid from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&amp;rsquo; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, by the passion of your blessed Son you made an instrument of shameful death to be for us the means of life: Grant us so to glory in the cross of Christ, that we may gladly suffer shame and loss for the sake of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill us with all joy and peace in believing through the power of the Holy Spirit.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Romans 15:13)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Monday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-epmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-epmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Monday, 6 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-these-prayers&#34;&gt;Share These Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/images/qr/holywk-epmon.gif&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.sharedprayer.net/litugies/holywk-epmon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to scan this QR code to pray with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyMon_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let my prayer be set forth in your sight as incense, the lifting up of my hands as the evening sacrifice.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 141:2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praised, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 36.5–11&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Dixit injustus&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 632&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Your love, O Lord, reaches to the heavens, *&lt;br&gt;
and your faithfulness to the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Your righteousness is like the strong mountains,&lt;br&gt;
your justice like the great deep; *&lt;br&gt;
you save both man and beast, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 How priceless is your love, O God! *&lt;br&gt;
your people take refuge under the shadow of your wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 They feast upon the abundance of your house; *&lt;br&gt;
you give them drink from the river of your delights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 For with you is the well of life, *&lt;br&gt;
and in your light we see light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 Continue your loving-kindness to those who know you, *&lt;br&gt;
and your favor to those who are true of heart.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 Let not the foot of the proud come near me, *&lt;br&gt;
nor the hand of the wicked push me aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 42:1&amp;ndash;9 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my servant, whom I uphold,&lt;br&gt;
my chosen, in whom my soul delights;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have put my spirit upon him;&lt;br&gt;
he will bring forth justice to the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will not cry or lift up his voice,&lt;br&gt;
or make it heard in the street;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a bruised reed he will not break,&lt;br&gt;
and a dimly burning wick he will not quench;&lt;br&gt;
he will faithfully bring forth justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will not grow faint or be crushed&lt;br&gt;
until he has established justice in the earth;&lt;br&gt;
and the coastlands wait for his teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says God, the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
who created the heavens and stretched them out,&lt;br&gt;
who spread out the earth and what comes from it,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who gives breath to the people upon it&lt;br&gt;
and spirit to those who walk in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the Lord, I have called you in righteousness,&lt;br&gt;
I have taken you by the hand and kept you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have given you as a covenant to the people,&lt;br&gt;
a light to the nations,&lt;br&gt;
to open the eyes that are blind,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to bring out the prisoners from the dungeon,&lt;br&gt;
from the prison those who sit in darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the Lord, that is my name;&lt;br&gt;
my glory I give to no other,&lt;br&gt;
nor my praise to idols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, the former things have come to pass,&lt;br&gt;
and new things I now declare;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before they spring forth,&lt;br&gt;
I tell you of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hebrews 9:11&amp;ndash;15 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Hebrews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Christ came as a high priest of the good things that have come, then through the greater and perfect tent (not made with hands, that is, not of this creation), he entered once for all into the Holy Place, not with the blood of goats and calves, but with his own blood, thus obtaining eternal redemption. For if the blood of goats and bulls, with the sprinkling of the ashes of a heifer, sanctifies those who have been defiled so that their flesh is purified, how much more will the blood of Christ, who through the eternal Spirit offered himself without blemish to God, purify our conscience from dead works to worship the living God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason he is the mediator of a new covenant, so that those who are called may receive the promised eternal inheritance, because a death has occurred that redeems them from the transgressions under the first covenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;  &lt;em&gt;John 12:1&amp;ndash;11 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him. Mary took a pound of costly perfume made of pure nard, anointed Jesus&amp;rsquo; feet, and wiped them with her hair. The house was filled with the fragrance of the perfume. But Judas Iscariot, one of his disciples (the one who was about to betray him), said, &amp;ldquo;Why was this perfume not sold for three hundred denarii and the money given to the poor?&amp;rdquo; (He said this not because he cared about the poor, but because he was a thief; he kept the common purse and used to steal what was put into it.) Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Leave her alone. She bought it so that she might keep it for the day of my burial. You always have the poor with you, but you do not always have me.&amp;rdquo; When the great crowd of the Jews learned that he was there, they came not only because of Jesus but also to see Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. So the chief priests planned to put Lazarus to death as well, since it was on account of him that many of the Jews were deserting and were believing in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&amp;rsquo; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified: Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through Jesus Christ your Son our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, and the love of God, and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit, be with us all evermore. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(2 Corinthians 13:14)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday of the Passion --- Palm Sunday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/palmsunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 16:59:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/palmsunday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 270)&lt;br&gt;
5 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-these-prayers&#34;&gt;Share These Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/images/qr/liturgies-palmsunday.gif&#34; alt=&#34;http://www.sharedprayer.net/litugies/palmsunday&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invite someone to scan this QR code to pray with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearA_RCL/HolyWk/APalmSun_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Palms or other greens may be gathered to carry in procession. Choose a Celebrant and a reader. Light a candle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-liturgy-of-the-palms&#34;&gt;The Liturgy of the Palms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand&#34;&gt;The People stand.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed is the King who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace in heaven and glory in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;br&gt;
Assist us mercifully with your help, O Lord God of our salvation, that we may enter with joy upon the contemplation of those mighty acts, whereby you have given us life and immortality; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from Matthew’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they had come near Jerusalem and had reached Bethphage, at the Mount of Olives, Jesus sent two disciples, saying to them, ‘Go into the village ahead of you, and immediately you will find a donkey tied, and a colt with her; untie them and bring them to me. If anyone says anything to you, just say this, “The Lord needs them.” And he will send them immediately.’ This took place to fulfil what had been spoken through the prophet, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell the daughter of Zion,&lt;br&gt;
Look, your king is coming to you,&lt;br&gt;
humble, and mounted on a donkey,&lt;br&gt;
and on a colt, the foal of a donkey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disciples went and did as Jesus had directed them; they brought the donkey and the colt, and put their cloaks on them, and he sat on them. A very large crowd spread their cloaks on the road, and others cut branches from the trees and spread them on the road. The crowds that went ahead of him and that followed were shouting,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hosanna to the Son of David!&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is the one who comes in the name of the Lord!&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest heaven!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he entered Jerusalem, the whole city was in turmoil, asking, ‘Who is this?’ The crowds were saying, ‘This is the prophet Jesus from Nazareth in Galilee.’ &lt;em&gt;(Matthew 21.1–11 NRSV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing-of-the-palms&#34;&gt;The Blessing of the Palms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give him thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right to praise you, Almighty God, for the acts of love by which you have redeemed us through your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. On this day he entered the holy city of Jerusalem in triumph, and was proclaimed as King of kings by those who spread their garments and branches of palm along his way. Let these branches be for us signs of his victory, and grant that we who bear them in his name may ever hail him as our King, and follow him in the way that leads to eternal life; who lives and reigns in glory with you and the Holy Spirit, now and for ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-procession&#34;&gt;The Procession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us go forth in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the name of Christ. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hymn 154: All glory, laud, and honor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;hear-this-hymn-playedhttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvh3a8fttrade&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3a8fTTrAdE&#34;&gt;Hear this hymn played&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;while-singing-take-your-palms-and-if-possible-process-out-and-around-your-residence-if-it-is-better-to-stay-inside-process-around-your-living-spaces-bringing-jesus-into-every-space-upon-reaching-the-point-furthest-from-the-worship-space-stop-and-pray-the-following-collect&#34;&gt;While singing, take your palms and, if possible, process out and around your residence. If it is better to stay inside, process around your living spaces, bringing Jesus into every space. Upon reaching the point furthest from the worship space, stop and pray the following Collect:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified: Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;on-the-return-of-the-procession-we-say-aloud&#34;&gt;On the return of the procession, we say aloud:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 118:1-2, 19-29&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Confitemini Domino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; *&lt;br&gt;
his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Let Israel now proclaim, *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;His mercy endures for ever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Open for me the gates of righteousness; *&lt;br&gt;
I will enter them; I will offer thanks to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 &amp;ldquo;This is the gate of the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
he who is righteous may enter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 I will give thanks to you, for you answered me *&lt;br&gt;
and have become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 The same stone which the builders rejected *&lt;br&gt;
has become the chief cornerstone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 This is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s doing, *&lt;br&gt;
and it is marvelous in our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 On this day the Lord has acted; *&lt;br&gt;
we will rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 Hosannah, Lord, hosannah! *&lt;br&gt;
Lord, send us now success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
we bless you from the house of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27 God is the Lord; he has shined upon us; *&lt;br&gt;
form a procession with branches up to the horns of the altar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 &amp;ldquo;You are my God, and I will thank you; *&lt;br&gt;
you are my God, and I will exalt you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; *&lt;br&gt;
his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-find-their-seats-and-remain-standing&#34;&gt;The people find their seats and remain standing.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-liturgy-of-the-word&#34;&gt;The Liturgy of the Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-1&#34;&gt;The People stand.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation&#34;&gt;Salutation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-proper-to-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty and everliving God, in your tender love for the human race you sent your Son our Savior Jesus Christ to take upon him our nature, and to suffer death upon the cross, giving us the example of his great humility: Mercifully grant that we may walk in the way of his suffering, and also share in his resurrection; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 50:4–9 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has given me&lt;br&gt;
the tongue of a teacher,&lt;br&gt;
that I may know how to sustain&lt;br&gt;
the weary with a word.&lt;br&gt;
Morning by morning he wakens—&lt;br&gt;
wakens my ear&lt;br&gt;
to listen as those who are taught.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord God has opened my ear,&lt;br&gt;
and I was not rebellious,&lt;br&gt;
I did not turn backwards.&lt;br&gt;
I gave my back to those who struck me,&lt;br&gt;
and my cheeks to those who pulled out the beard;&lt;br&gt;
I did not hide my face&lt;br&gt;
from insult and spitting.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord God helps me;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have not been disgraced;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have set my face like flint,&lt;br&gt;
and I know that I shall not be put to shame;&lt;br&gt;
he who vindicates me is near.&lt;br&gt;
Who will contend with me?&lt;br&gt;
Let us stand up together.&lt;br&gt;
Who are my adversaries?&lt;br&gt;
Let them confront me.&lt;br&gt;
It is the Lord God who helps me;&lt;br&gt;
who will declare me guilty?&lt;br&gt;
All of them will wear out like a garment;&lt;br&gt;
the moth will eat them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 31.9–16&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;In te, Domine, speravi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 623)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Have mercy on me, O Lord, for I am in trouble; *&lt;br&gt;
my eye is consumed with sorrow,&lt;br&gt;
and also my throat and my belly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 For my life is wasted with grief, and my years with sighing; *&lt;br&gt;
my strength fails me because of affliction,&lt;br&gt;
and my bones are consumed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 I have become a reproach to all my enemies&lt;br&gt;
and even to my neighbors,&lt;br&gt;
a dismay to those of my acquaintance; *&lt;br&gt;
when they see me in the street they avoid me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 I am forgotten like a dead man, out of mind; *&lt;br&gt;
I am as useless as a broken pot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 For I have heard the whispering of the crowd; fear is all around; *&lt;br&gt;
they put their heads together against me;&lt;br&gt;
they plot to take my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 But as for me, I have trusted in you, O Lord. *&lt;br&gt;
I have said, &amp;ldquo;You are my God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 My times are in your hand; *&lt;br&gt;
rescue me from the hand of my enemies,&lt;br&gt;
and from those who persecute me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 Make your face to shine upon your servant, *&lt;br&gt;
and in your loving-kindness save me.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Philippians 2:5–11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the letter to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus,&lt;br&gt;
who, though he was in the form of God,&lt;br&gt;
did not regard equality with God&lt;br&gt;
as something to be exploited,&lt;br&gt;
but emptied himself,&lt;br&gt;
taking the form of a slave,&lt;br&gt;
being born in human likeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And being found in human form,&lt;br&gt;
he humbled himself&lt;br&gt;
and became obedient to the point of death—&lt;br&gt;
even death on a cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore God also highly exalted him&lt;br&gt;
and gave him the name&lt;br&gt;
that is above every name,&lt;br&gt;
so that at the name of Jesus&lt;br&gt;
every knee should bend,&lt;br&gt;
in heaven and on earth and under the earth,&lt;br&gt;
and every tongue should confess&lt;br&gt;
that Jesus Christ is Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-passion&#34;&gt;The Passion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;separate-passion-reading-booklets-are-provided-herehttpsisgdpassionmatthew-the-congregation-may-be-seated-for-the-first-part-of-the-passion-at-the-verse-which-mentions-the-arrival-at-golgotha-all-stand&#34;&gt;Separate Passion reading booklets are provided &lt;a href=&#34;https://is.gd/PassionMatthew&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The congregation may be seated for the first part of the Passion. &lt;strong&gt;At the verse which mentions the arrival at Golgotha all stand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Passion of our Lord according to MATTHEW&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Matthew 26:14–27:66 (RCL Year A)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dramatis personæ: 	People, Judas, Narrator, Jesus, Peter, High Priest, Witness/Servant/Pilate’s Wife, Pilate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The Passion of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	One of the twelve, who was called Judas Iscariot, went to the chief priests and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	What will you give me if I betray him to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	They paid him thirty pieces of silver. And from that moment he began to look for an opportunity to betray him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day of Unleavened Bread the disciples came to Jesus, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt; 	Where do you want us to make the preparations for you to eat the Passover?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Go into the city to a certain man, and say to him, “The Teacher says, My time is near; I will keep the Passover at your house with my disciples.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So the disciples did as Jesus had directed them, and they prepared the Passover meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was evening, he took his place with the twelve; and while they were eating, he said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly I tell you, one of you will betray me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And they became greatly distressed and began to say to him one after another,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt; 	Surely not I, Lord?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	The one who has dipped his hand into the bowl with me will betray me. The Son of Man goes as it is written of him, but woe to that one by whom the Son of Man is betrayed! It would have been better for that one not to have been born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Judas, who betrayed him, said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	Surely not I, Rabbi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You have said so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	While they were eating, Jesus took a loaf of bread, and after blessing it he broke it, gave it to the disciples, and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Take, eat; this is my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he took a cup, and after giving thanks he gave it to them, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Drink from it, all of you; for this is my blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for the forgiveness of sins. I tell you, I will never again drink of this fruit of the vine until that day when I drink it new with you in my Father’s kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When they had sung the hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives. Then Jesus said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You will all become deserters because of me this night; for it is written,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I will strike the shepherd,&lt;br&gt;
the sheep of the flock will be&lt;br&gt;
scattered.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after I am raised up, I will go ahead of you to Galilee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Peter said to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	Though all become deserters because of you, I will never desert you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly I tell you, this very night, before the cock crows, you will deny me three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	Even though I must die with you, I will not deny you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And so said all the disciples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Jesus went with them to a place called Gethsemane; and he said to his disciples,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Sit here while I go over there and pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	He took with him Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, and began to be grieved and agitated. Then he said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	I am deeply grieved, even to death; remain here, and stay awake with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And going a little farther, he threw himself on the ground and prayed,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	My Father, if it is possible, let this cup pass from me; yet not what I want but what you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he came to the disciples and found them sleeping; and he said to Peter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	So, could you not stay awake with me one hour? Stay awake and pray that you may not come into the time of trial; the spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he went away for the second time and prayed,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	My Father, if this cannot pass unless I drink it, your will be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he came and found them sleeping, for their eyes were heavy. So leaving them again, he went away and prayed for the third time, saying the same words. Then he came to the disciples and said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Are you still sleeping and taking your rest? See, the hour is at hand, and the Son of Man is betrayed into the hands of sinners. Get up, let us be going. See, my betrayer is at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	While he was still speaking, Judas, one of the twelve, arrived; with him was a large crowd with swords and clubs, from the chief priests and the elders of the people. Now the betrayer had given them a sign, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	The one I will kiss is the man; arrest him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At once he came up to Jesus and kissed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	Greetings, Rabbi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Friend, do what you are here to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then they came and laid hands on Jesus and arrested him. Suddenly, one of those with Jesus put his hand on his sword, drew it, and struck the slave of the high priest, cutting off his ear. Then Jesus said to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Put your sword back into its place; for all who take the sword will perish by the sword. Do you think that I cannot appeal to my Father, and he will at once send me more than twelve legions of angels? But how then would the scriptures be fulfilled, which say it must happen in this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At that hour Jesus said to the crowds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Have you come out with swords and clubs to arrest me as though I were a bandit? Day after day I sat in the temple teaching, and you did not arrest me. But all this has taken place, so that the scriptures of the prophets may be fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then all the disciples deserted him and fled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who had arrested Jesus took him to Caiaphas the high priest, in whose house the scribes and the elders had gathered. But Peter was following him at a distance, as far as the courtyard of the high priest; and going inside, he sat with the guards in order to see how this would end. Now the chief priests and the whole council were looking for false testimony against Jesus so that they might put him to death, but they found none, though many false witnesses came forward. At last two came forward and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Witness:&lt;/em&gt;	This fellow said, “I am able to destroy the temple of God and to build it in three days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The high priest stood up and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	Have you no answer? What is it that they testify against you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But Jesus was silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	I put you under oath before the living God, tell us if you are the Messiah, the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You have said so. But I tell you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on you will see the Son of Man&lt;br&gt;
seated at the right hand of Power&lt;br&gt;
and coming on the clouds of heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the high priest tore his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	He has blasphemed! Why do we still need witnesses? You have now heard his blasphemy. What is your verdict?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	He deserves death.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then they spat in his face and struck him; and some slapped him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Prophesy to us, you Messiah! Who is it that struck you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Now Peter was sitting outside in the courtyard. A servant-girl came to him and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servant:&lt;/em&gt;	You also were with Jesus the Galilean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But he denied it before all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know what you are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When he went out to the porch, another servant-girl saw him, and she said to the bystanders,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servant:&lt;/em&gt;	This man was with Jesus of Nazareth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he denied it with an oath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know the man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	After a little while the bystanders came up and said to Peter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Certainly you are also one of them, for your accent betrays you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he began to curse, and he swore an oath,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know the man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At that moment the cock crowed. Then Peter remembered what Jesus had said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Before the cock crows, you will deny me three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And he went out and wept bitterly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When morning came, all the chief priests and the elders of the people conferred together against Jesus in order to bring about his death. They bound him, led him away, and handed him over to Pilate the governor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Judas, his betrayer, saw that Jesus was condemned, he repented and brought back the thirty pieces of silver to the chief priests and the elders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	I have sinned by betraying innocent blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	What is that to us? See to it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Throwing down the pieces of silver in the temple, he departed; and he went and hanged himself. But the chief priests, taking the pieces of silver, said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	It is not lawful to put them into the treasury, since they are blood money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	After conferring together, they used them to buy the potter’s field as a place to bury foreigners. For this reason that field has been called the Field of Blood to this day. Then was fulfilled what had been spoken through the prophet Jeremiah, “And they took the thirty pieces of silver, the price of the one on whom a price had been set, on whom some of the people of Israel had set a price, and they gave them for the potter’s field, as the Lord commanded me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Jesus stood before the governor; and the governor asked him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Are you the King of the Jews?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You say so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But when he was accused by the chief priests and elders, he did not answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Do you not hear how many accusations they make against you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But he gave him no answer, not even to a single charge, so that the governor was greatly amazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now at the festival the governor was accustomed to release a prisoner for the crowd, anyone whom they wanted. At that time they had a notorious prisoner, called Jesus Barabbas. So after they had gathered, Pilate said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Whom do you want me to release for you, Jesus Barabbas or Jesus who is called the Messiah?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	For he realized that it was out of jealousy that they had handed him over. While he was sitting on the judgment seat, his wife sent word to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wife:&lt;/em&gt;	Have nothing to do with that innocent man, for today I have suffered a great deal because of a dream about him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Now the chief priests and the elders persuaded the crowds to ask for Barabbas and to have Jesus killed. The governor again said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Which of the two do you want me to release for you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Barabbas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt; 	Then what should I do with Jesus who is called the Messiah?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Let him be crucified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Why, what evil has he done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	(shouting) Let him be crucified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So when Pilate saw that he could do nothing, but rather that a riot was beginning, he took some water and washed his hands before the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	I am innocent of this man’s blood; see to it yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the people as a whole answered,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	His blood be on us and on our children!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So he released Barabbas for them; and after flogging Jesus, he handed him over to be crucified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the soldiers of the governor took Jesus into the governor’s headquarters, and they gathered the whole cohort around him. They stripped him and put a scarlet robe on him, and after twisting some thorns into a crown, they put it on his head. They put a reed in his right hand and knelt before him and mocked him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Hail, King of the Jews!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	They spat on him, and took the reed and struck him on the head. After mocking him, they stripped him of the robe and put his own clothes on him. Then they led him away to crucify him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they went out, they came upon a man from Cyrene named Simon; they compelled this man to carry his cross. And when they came to a place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull), they offered him wine to drink, mixed with gall; but when he tasted it, he would not drink it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SILENCE		   (The Congregation stands at this time.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And when they had crucified him, they divided his clothes among themselves by casting lots; then they sat down there and kept watch over him. Over his head they put the charge against him, which read, “This is Jesus, the King of the Jews.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then two bandits were crucified with him, one on his right and one on his left. Those who passed by derided him, shaking their heads and saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	You who would destroy the temple and build it in three days, save yourself! If you are the Son of God, come down from the cross.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	In the same way the chief priests also, along with the scribes and elders, were mocking him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	He saved others; he cannot save himself. He is the King of Israel; let him come down from the cross now, and we will believe in him. He trusts in God; let God deliver him now, if he wants to; for he said, “I am God’s Son.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The bandits who were crucified with him also taunted him in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	From noon on, darkness came over the whole land until three in the afternoon. And about three o’clock Jesus cried with a loud voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Eli, Eli, lema sabachthani?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	That is, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?” When some of the bystanders heard it, they said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	This man is calling for Elijah.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At once one of them ran and got a sponge, filled it with sour wine, put it on a stick, and gave it to him to drink. But the others said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to save him.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then Jesus cried again with a loud voice and breathed his last. At that moment the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. The earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened, and many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised. After his resurrection they came out of the tombs and entered the holy city and appeared to many. Now when the centurion and those with him, who were keeping watch over Jesus, saw the earthquake and what took place, they were terrified and said,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly this man was God’s Son!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Many women were also there, looking on from a distance; they had followed Jesus from Galilee and had provided for him. Among them were Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James and Joseph, and the mother of the sons of Zebedee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was evening, there came a rich man from Arimathea, named Joseph, who was also a disciple of Jesus. He went to Pilate and asked for the body of Jesus; then Pilate ordered it to be given to him. So Joseph took the body and wrapped it in a clean linen cloth and laid it in his own new tomb, which he had hewn in the rock. He then rolled a great stone to the door of the tomb and went away. Mary Magdalene and the other Mary were there, sitting opposite the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The next day, that is, after the day of Preparation, the chief priests and the Pharisees gathered before Pilate and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	Sir, we remember what that impostor said while he was still alive, “After three days I will rise again.” Therefore command the tomb to be made secure until the third day; otherwise his disciples may go and steal him away, and tell the people, “He has been raised from the dead,” and the last deception would be worse than the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	You have a guard of soldiers; go, make it as secure as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So they went with the guard and made the tomb secure by sealing the stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There follows a great silence. Please remain standing if you are able.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;text-adapted-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Text adapted from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we journey this week with Christ and celebrate the paschal mystery of his death and resurrection, let us earnestly pray to God for those following the way of the cross and for all peoples everywhere, saying: Lord have mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the holy catholic church throughout the world, sharing the death and resurrection of Christ, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Justin, Archbishop of Canterbury, for Michael, Presiding Bishop of the Episcopal Church, for &lt;em&gt;William&lt;/em&gt; our bishop, for all bishops, presbyters and deacons and all who minister in Christ, and for all the holy people of God, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all catechumens and their sponsors, for all seeking baptism, confirmation, or reaffirmation, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all nations, peoples, tribes, clans, and families, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all nations and their leaders, including Donald, our President; members of the U.S. Congress, &lt;em&gt;Phil,&lt;/em&gt; our Governor, and &lt;em&gt;John, our Mayor&lt;/em&gt;; for justice, mercy, and peace in all the world, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who are tempted, oppressed, afflicted, or in need, especially&amp;hellip; let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all those who have suffered and have been affected by the Covid-19 Virus; for healing in mind, body, spirit and community;  for our governing bodies that they may respond with dignity and respect for all citizens, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the dying and the dead, remembering&amp;hellip; and for those who mourn, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our families, friends, and companions, and for all those we love, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remembering the blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;blessed Thomas&lt;/em&gt;, and all the saints, let us offer ourselves and one another to the living God through Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, Lord our God, who sent your Son among us to bear the pain and grief of humankind. Receive the prayers we offer this day for all those in need in every place and as we near the holy mountain grant us strength on our journey; through Jesus Christ our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-and-absolution&#34;&gt;Confession and Absolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prayer-over-the-people&#34;&gt;Prayer Over the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, we pray you graciously to behold this your family, for whom our Lord Jesus Christ was willing to be betrayed, and given into the hands of sinners, and to suffer death upon the cross; who lives and reigns for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dismissal&#34;&gt;Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
