<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive on Shared Prayers</title>
    <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive on Shared Prayers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist, Rite II (The Second Sunday in Lent, Covid-tide)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-current/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-current/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this season of coronavirus infections, please demonstrate your love for your friends and neighbors by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wearing a mask (covering both mouth and nose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remaining six feet apart from anyone you don’t live with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refraining from touching, hugging and shaking hands &amp;ndash; even during the Peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singing is only permitted outdoors, six feet apart, wearing masks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service bulletins you have touched must be taken home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the service everyone must disperse with no lingering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No sharing of common objects such as pens, paper, water bottles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling ill or think you may have been exposed to someone ill within the last two weeks, &lt;em&gt;please stay home&lt;/em&gt; and participate with us online instead of in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-penitential-order&#34;&gt;A Penitential Order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord who forgives all our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-decalogue&#34;&gt;The Decalogue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-_officiant_-and-the-people-call-and-respond&#34;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Officiant&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;People&lt;/strong&gt; call and respond:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the commandments of God to God&amp;rsquo;s people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the Lord your God who brought you out of bondage. You shall have no other gods but me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any idol.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not invoke with malice the Name of the Lord your God.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the Sabbath Day and keep it holy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honor your father and your mother.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit murder.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit adultery.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not steal.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not be a false witness.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not covet anything that belongs to your neighbor.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said, “The first commandment is this: Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God is the only Lord. Love the Lord your God with all your heart, with all your soul, with all your mind, and with all your strength. The second is this: Love your neighbor as yourself. There is no other commandment greater than these.” &lt;em&gt;(Mark 12:29-31)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon or Celebrant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-may-be-kept&#34;&gt;Silence may be kept.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-deacon-or-lay-person-using-the-preceding-form-remains-kneeling-and-substitutes-us-for-you-and-our-for-your&#34;&gt;A deacon or lay person using the preceding form remains kneeling, and substitutes “us” for “you” and “our” for “your.”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation-and-collect&#34;&gt;Salutation and Collect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, whose glory it is always to have mercy: Be gracious to all who have gone astray from your ways, and bring them again with penitent hearts and steadfast faith to embrace and hold fast the unchangeable truth of your Word, Jesus Christ your Son; who with you and the Holy Spirit lives and reigns, one God, for ever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Genesis 17:1-7, 15-16&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Abram was ninety-nine years old, the Lord appeared to Abram, and said to him, “I am God Almighty; walk before me, and be blameless. And I will make my covenant between me and you, and will make you exceedingly numerous.” Then Abram fell on his face; and God said to him, “As for me, this is my covenant with you: You shall be the ancestor of a multitude of nations. No longer shall your name be Abram, but your name shall be Abraham; for I have made you the ancestor of a multitude of nations. I will make you exceedingly fruitful; and I will make nations of you, and kings shall come from you. I will establish my covenant between me and you, and your offspring after you throughout their generations, for an everlasting covenant, to be God to you and to your offspring after you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God said to Abraham, “As for Sarai your wife, you shall not call her Sarai, but Sarah shall be her name. I will bless her, and moreover I will give you a son by her. I will bless her, and she shall give rise to nations; kings of peoples shall come from her.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm&lt;/strong&gt; 22:22-30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deus, Deus meus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 Praise the Lord, you that fear him; *&lt;br&gt;
stand in awe of him, O offspring of Israel;&lt;br&gt;
all you of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s line, give glory.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;23 For he does not despise nor abhor the poor in their poverty;&lt;br&gt;
neither does he hide his face from them; *&lt;br&gt;
but when they cry to him he hears them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 My praise is of him in the great assembly; *&lt;br&gt;
I will perform my vows&lt;br&gt;
in the presence of those who worship him.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;25 The poor shall eat and be satisfied,&lt;br&gt;
and those who seek the Lord shall praise him: *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;May your heart live for ever!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the Lord, *&lt;br&gt;
and all the families of the nations shall bow before him.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;27 For kingship belongs to the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
he rules over the nations.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 To him alone all who sleep in the earth bow down in worship; *&lt;br&gt;
all who go down to the dust fall before him.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;29 My soul shall live for him;&lt;br&gt;
my descendants shall serve him; *&lt;br&gt;
they shall be known as the Lord’s for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 They shall come and make known to a people yet unborn *&lt;br&gt;
the saving deeds that he has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Romans 4:13-25&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s epistle to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the promise that he would inherit the world did not come to Abraham or to his descendants through the law but through the righteousness of faith. If it is the adherents of the law who are to be the heirs, faith is null and the promise is void. For the law brings wrath; but where there is no law, neither is there violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason it depends on faith, in order that the promise may rest on grace and be guaranteed to all his descendants, not only to the adherents of the law but also to those who share the faith of Abraham (for he is the father of all of us, as it is written, “I have made you the father of many nations”) —in the presence of the God in whom he believed, who gives life to the dead and calls into existence the things that do not exist. Hoping against hope, he believed that he would become “the father of many nations,” according to what was said, “So numerous shall your descendants be.” He did not weaken in faith when he considered his own body, which was already as good as dead (for he was about a hundred years old), or when he considered the barrenness of Sarah’s womb. No distrust made him waver concerning the promise of God, but he grew strong in his faith as he gave glory to God, being fully convinced that God was able to do what he had promised. Therefore his faith “was reckoned to him as righteousness.” Now the words, “it was reckoned to him,” were written not for his sake alone, but for ours also. It will be reckoned to us who believe in him who raised Jesus our Lord from the dead, who was handed over to death for our trespasses and was raised for our justification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Holy Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Mark 8:31-38&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus began to teach his disciples that the Son of Man must undergo great suffering, and be rejected by the elders, the chief priests, and the scribes, and be killed, and after three days rise again. He said all this quite openly. And Peter took him aside and began to rebuke him. But turning and looking at his disciples, he rebuked Peter and said, “Get behind me, Satan! For you are setting your mind not on divine things but on human things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He called the crowd with his disciples, and said to them, “If any want to become my followers, let them deny themselves and take up their cross and follow me. For those who want to save their life will lose it, and those who lose their life for my sake, and for the sake of the gospel, will save it. For what will it profit them to gain the whole world and forfeit their life? Indeed, what can they give in return for their life? Those who are ashamed of me and of my words in this adulterous and sinful generation, of them the Son of Man will also be ashamed when he comes in the glory of his Father with the holy angels.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-nicene-creed&#34;&gt;The Nicene Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;the Father, the Almighty,&lt;br&gt;
maker of heaven and earth,&lt;br&gt;
of all that is, seen and unseen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
the only Son of God,&lt;br&gt;
eternally begotten of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
God from God,&lt;br&gt;
Light from Light, true God from true God,&lt;br&gt;
begotten, not made,&lt;br&gt;
of one Being with the Father.&lt;br&gt;
Through him all things were made.&lt;br&gt;
For us and for our salvation&lt;br&gt;
he came down from heaven:&lt;br&gt;
by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,&lt;br&gt;
and was made man.&lt;br&gt;
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;&lt;br&gt;
he suffered death and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again&lt;br&gt;
in accordance with the Scriptures;&lt;br&gt;
he ascended into heaven&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and his kingdom will have no end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,&lt;br&gt;
who proceeds from the Father and the Son.&lt;br&gt;
With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.&lt;br&gt;
He has spoken through the Prophets.&lt;br&gt;
We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.&lt;br&gt;
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.&lt;br&gt;
We look for the resurrection of the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and the life of the world to come. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the response to the prompt, &amp;ldquo;Lord in your mercy” is, &lt;strong&gt;“Hear our prayer.”&lt;/strong&gt; The final verse and response, as we “offer ourselves and one another to the living God through Christ,” is &lt;strong&gt;“To you, O Lord.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;passing-the-peace-is-primarily-a-liturgical-practice-not-a-social-one-while-the-threat-of-covid-19-is-prominent-the-peace-will-be-brief-please-do-not-move-around-or-make-contact-shaking-hands-hugs-with-others-instead-you-are-invited-to-look-to-the-person-on-either-side-of-you-and-wish-them-peace-with-a-bow-or-a-wave&#34;&gt;Passing the Peace is primarily a liturgical practice, not a social one. While the threat of Covid-19 is prominent, the peace will be brief. Please do not move around or make contact (shaking hands, hugs) with others. Instead you are invited to look to the person on either side of you and wish them peace with a bow or a wave.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves to God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;at-outdoor-liturgies-an-offertory-may-be-sung&#34;&gt;At outdoor liturgies, an offertory may be sung:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;offertory-hymn&#34;&gt;Offertory Hymn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessed Assurance&lt;/em&gt; (LEVAS 184)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;br&gt;
Blessed assurance, Jesus is mine!&lt;br&gt;
O what a foretaste of glory divine!&lt;br&gt;
Heir of salvation, purchase of God,&lt;br&gt;
Born of His spirit, washed in His blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refrain:&lt;br&gt;
This is my story, this is my song,&lt;br&gt;
Praising my savior all the day long;&lt;br&gt;
This is my story, this is my song,&lt;br&gt;
Praising my savior all the day long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;br&gt;
Perfect submission, perfect delight,&lt;br&gt;
Visions of rapture now burst on my sight;&lt;br&gt;
Angels descending, bring from above&lt;br&gt;
Echoes of mercy, whispers of love. [Refrain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;br&gt;
Perfect submission, all is at rest,&lt;br&gt;
I in my savior am happy and blest;&lt;br&gt;
Watching and waiting, looking above,&lt;br&gt;
Filled with His goodness, lost in His love. [Refrain]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-a&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presider and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy and gracious Father: In your infinite love you made us for yourself; and, when we had fallen into sin and become subject to evil and death, you, in your mercy, sent Jesus Christ, your only and eternal Son, to share our human nature, to live and die as one of us, to reconcile us to you, the God and Father of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stretched out his arms upon the cross, and offered himself in obedience to your will, a perfect sacrifice for the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night he was handed over to suffering and death, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we proclaim the mystery of faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ has died.&lt;br&gt;
Christ is risen.&lt;br&gt;
Christ will come again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We celebrate the memorial of our redemption, O Father, in this sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving. Recalling his death, resurrection, and ascension, we offer you these gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctify them by your Holy Spirit to be for your people the Body and Blood of your Son, the holy food and drink of new and unending life in him. Sanctify us also that we may faithfully receive this holy Sacrament, and serve you in unity, constancy, and peace; and at the last day bring us with all your saints into the joy of your eternal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this we ask through your Son Jesus Christ. By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receiving Communion during Covid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remain where you are, standing or seated in prayer. After the presider has received the Sacrament in both kinds, donned a mask, and carefully sanitized hands, the presider will bring the sacrament to each person in turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold out your cupped hands to receive the bread. The presider will drop the host into your hands without making contact. (If you prefer to receive gluten-free bread, please tell the presider so.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait until the presider has moved away to remove your mask, consume the host, and replace you mask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communion will be offered in one kind only (just the bread). This is still full communion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross your arms over your chest. The presider will offer you a blessing instead, again without touching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are invited to utter the &lt;em&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/em&gt; while communion is being distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prayer-for-spiritual-communion&#34;&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In union, O Lord, with your faithful people at every altar of your Church, where the Holy Eucharist is now being celebrated, I desire to offer to you praise and thanksgiving. I remember your death, Lord Christ; I proclaim your resurrection; I await your coming in glory. Since I cannot receive you today in the Sacrament of your Body and Blood, I beseech you to come spiritually into my heart. Cleanse and strengthen me with your grace, Lord Jesus, and let me never be separated from you. May I live in you, and you in me, in this life and in the life to come. Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(from &lt;em&gt;The Prayer Book for the Armed Services&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457-1&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal God, heavenly Father,&lt;br&gt;
you have graciously accepted us as living members&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
and you have fed us with spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
in the Sacrament of his Body and Blood.&lt;br&gt;
Send us now into the world in peace,&lt;br&gt;
and grant us strength and courage&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
with gladness and singleness of heart;&lt;br&gt;
through Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayer-over-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayer over the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-processional-hymn-will-only-be-sung-at-liturgies-meeting-outdoors&#34;&gt;The Processional Hymn will only be sung at liturgies meeting outdoors.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;processional-hymn&#34;&gt;Processional Hymn&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lift Every Voice and Sing&lt;/em&gt; (LEVAS 1)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1&lt;br&gt;
Lift ev’ry voice and sing,&lt;br&gt;
Till earth and heaven ring,&lt;br&gt;
Ring with the harmonies of liberty;&lt;br&gt;
Let our rejoicing rise&lt;br&gt;
High as the list’ning skies,&lt;br&gt;
Let it resound loud as the rolling sea.&lt;br&gt;
Sing a song full of the faith that the dark past has taught us;&lt;br&gt;
Sing a song full of the hope that the present has brought us;&lt;br&gt;
Facing the rising sun&lt;br&gt;
Of our new day begun,&lt;br&gt;
Let us march on till victory is won.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2&lt;br&gt;
Stony the road we trod,&lt;br&gt;
Bitter the chast’ning rod,&lt;br&gt;
Felt in the days when hope unborn had died;&lt;br&gt;
Yet with a steady beat,&lt;br&gt;
Have not our weary feet&lt;br&gt;
Come to the place for which our fathers sighed?&lt;br&gt;
We have come over away that with tears has been watered;&lt;br&gt;
We have come, treading our path through the blood of the slaughtered;&lt;br&gt;
Out from the gloomy past,&lt;br&gt;
Till now we stand at last&lt;br&gt;
Where the white gleam of our bright star is cast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3&lt;br&gt;
God of our weary years,&lt;br&gt;
God of our silent tears,&lt;br&gt;
Thou who hast brought us thus far on the way;&lt;br&gt;
Thou who hast by thy might,&lt;br&gt;
Led us into the light,&lt;br&gt;
Keep us forever in the path, we pray.&lt;br&gt;
Lest our feet stray from the places, our God, where we met thee;&lt;br&gt;
Lest our hearts, drunk with the wine of the world, we forget thee,&lt;br&gt;
Shadowed beneath Thy hand,&lt;br&gt;
May we forever stand,&lt;br&gt;
True to our God, true to our native land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to minimize the possibility of infecting others,&lt;br&gt;
please exit the campus immediately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist, Rite II (Major Feasts in Covid-tide)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-feasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-feasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Holy Eucharist&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;for Sundays and Major Feasts during Covid-tide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 355ff.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lessons can often be found at &lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/&#34;&gt;lectionarypage.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this season of coronavirus infections, please demonstrate your love for your friends and neighbors by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wearing a mask (covering both mouth and nose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remaining six feet apart from anyone you don’t live with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refraining from touching, hugging and shaking hands &amp;ndash; even during the Peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singing is only permitted outdoors, six feet apart, wearing masks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service bulletins you have touched must be taken home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the service everyone must disperse with no lingering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No sharing of common objects such as pens, paper, water bottles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling ill or think you may have been exposed to someone ill within the last two weeks, &lt;em&gt;please stay home&lt;/em&gt; and participate with us online instead of in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God’s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord who forgives all our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy God,&lt;br&gt;
Holy and Mighty,&lt;br&gt;
Holy Immortal One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have mercy upon us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation-and-collect&#34;&gt;Salutation and Collect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day-is-used-here&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day is used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Psalm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Holy Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-nicene-creed&#34;&gt;The Nicene Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;the Father, the Almighty,&lt;br&gt;
maker of heaven and earth,&lt;br&gt;
of all that is, seen and unseen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
the only Son of God,&lt;br&gt;
eternally begotten of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
God from God,&lt;br&gt;
Light from Light, true God from true God,&lt;br&gt;
begotten, not made,&lt;br&gt;
of one Being with the Father.&lt;br&gt;
Through him all things were made.&lt;br&gt;
For us and for our salvation&lt;br&gt;
he came down from heaven:&lt;br&gt;
by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,&lt;br&gt;
and was made man.&lt;br&gt;
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;&lt;br&gt;
he suffered death and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again&lt;br&gt;
in accordance with the Scriptures;&lt;br&gt;
he ascended into heaven&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and his kingdom will have no end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,&lt;br&gt;
who proceeds from the Father and the Son.&lt;br&gt;
With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.&lt;br&gt;
He has spoken through the Prophets.&lt;br&gt;
We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.&lt;br&gt;
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.&lt;br&gt;
We look for the resurrection of the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and the life of the world to come. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-3&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;passing-the-peace-is-primarily-a-liturgical-practice-not-a-social-one-while-the-threat-of-covid-19-is-prominent-the-peace-will-be-brief-please-do-not-move-around-or-make-contact-shaking-hands-hugs-with-others-instead-you-are-invited-to-look-to-the-person-on-either-side-of-you-and-wish-them-peace-with-a-bow-or-a-wave&#34;&gt;Passing the Peace is primarily a liturgical practice, not a social one. While the threat of Covid-19 is prominent, the peace will be brief. Please do not move around or make contact (shaking hands, hugs) with others. Instead you are invited to look to the person on either side of you and wish them peace with a bow or a wave.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves to God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-4&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-a&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presider and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy and gracious Father: In your infinite love you made us for yourself; and, when we had fallen into sin and become subject to evil and death, you, in your mercy, sent Jesus Christ, your only and eternal Son, to share our human nature, to live and die as one of us, to reconcile us to you, the God and Father of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stretched out his arms upon the cross, and offered himself in obedience to your will, a perfect sacrifice for the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night he was handed over to suffering and death, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we proclaim the mystery of faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ has died.&lt;br&gt;
Christ is risen.&lt;br&gt;
Christ will come again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We celebrate the memorial of our redemption, O Father, in this sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving. Recalling his death, resurrection, and ascension, we offer you these gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctify them by your Holy Spirit to be for your people the Body and Blood of your Son, the holy food and drink of new and unending life in him. Sanctify us also that we may faithfully receive this holy Sacrament, and serve you in unity, constancy, and peace; and at the last day bring us with all your saints into the joy of your eternal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this we ask through your Son Jesus Christ. By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receiving Communion during Covid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remain where you are, standing or seated in prayer. After the presider has received the Sacrament in both kinds, donned a mask, and carefully sanitized hands, the presider will bring the sacrament to each person in turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold out your cupped hands to receive the bread. The presider will drop the host into your hands without making contact. (If you prefer to receive gluten-free bread, please tell the presider so.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait until the presider has moved away to remove your mask, consume the host, and replace you mask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communion will be offered in one kind only (just the bread). This is still full communion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross your arms over your chest. The presider will offer you a blessing instead, again without touching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are invited to utter the &lt;em&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/em&gt; while communion is being distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prayer-for-spiritual-communion&#34;&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In union, O Lord, with your faithful people at every altar of your Church, where the Holy Eucharist is now being celebrated, I desire to offer to you praise and thanksgiving. I remember your death, Lord Christ; I proclaim your resurrection; I await your coming in glory. Since I cannot receive you today in the Sacrament of your Body and Blood, I beseech you to come spiritually into my heart. Cleanse and strengthen me with your grace, Lord Jesus, and let me never be separated from you. May I live in you, and you in me, in this life and in the life to come. Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(from &lt;em&gt;The Prayer Book for the Armed Services&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457-1&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal God, heavenly Father,&lt;br&gt;
you have graciously accepted us as living members&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
and you have fed us with spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
in the Sacrament of his Body and Blood.&lt;br&gt;
Send us now into the world in peace,&lt;br&gt;
and grant us strength and courage&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
with gladness and singleness of heart;&lt;br&gt;
through Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayer-over-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayer over the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to minimize the possibility of infecting others,&lt;br&gt;
please exit the campus immediately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist, Rite II (Covid-tide)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-weekday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-weekday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Holy Eucharist&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;for weekdays during Covid-tide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 355ff.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/CalndrsIndexes/TxtIndexLFF.html&#34;&gt;The lessons for weekdays will normally correspond to the remembrance of a particular saint.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this season of coronavirus infections, please demonstrate your love for your friends and neighbors by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wearing a mask (covering both mouth and nose)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remaining six feet apart from anyone you don’t live with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refraining from touching, hugging and shaking hands &amp;ndash; even during the Peace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Singing is only permitted outdoors, six feet apart, wearing masks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service bulletins you have touched must be taken home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the service everyone must disperse with no lingering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No sharing of common objects such as pens, paper, water bottles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are feeling ill or think you may have been exposed to someone ill within the last two weeks, &lt;em&gt;please stay home&lt;/em&gt; and participate with us online instead of in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God’s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord who forgives all our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy God,&lt;br&gt;
Holy and Mighty,&lt;br&gt;
Holy Immortal One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have mercy upon us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation-and-collect&#34;&gt;Salutation and Collect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day-is-used-here&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day is used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Psalm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Holy Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;
The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Priest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-deacon-or-lay-person-using-the-preceding-form-remains-kneeling-and-substitutes-us-for-you-and-our-for-your&#34;&gt;A deacon or lay person using the preceding form remains kneeling, and substitutes “us” for “you” and “our” for “your.”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-3&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;passing-the-peace-is-primarily-a-liturgical-practice-not-a-social-one-while-the-threat-of-covid-19-is-prominent-the-peace-will-be-brief-please-do-not-move-around-or-make-contact-shaking-hands-hugs-with-others-instead-you-are-invited-to-look-to-the-person-on-either-side-of-you-and-wish-them-peace-with-a-bow-or-a-wave&#34;&gt;Passing the Peace is primarily a liturgical practice, not a social one. While the threat of Covid-19 is prominent, the peace will be brief. Please do not move around or make contact (shaking hands, hugs) with others. Instead you are invited to look to the person on either side of you and wish them peace with a bow or a wave.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves to God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-4&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-a&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer A&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presider and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy and gracious Father: In your infinite love you made us for yourself; and, when we had fallen into sin and become subject to evil and death, you, in your mercy, sent Jesus Christ, your only and eternal Son, to share our human nature, to live and die as one of us, to reconcile us to you, the God and Father of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stretched out his arms upon the cross, and offered himself in obedience to your will, a perfect sacrifice for the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night he was handed over to suffering and death, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we proclaim the mystery of faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ has died.&lt;br&gt;
Christ is risen.&lt;br&gt;
Christ will come again.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Presider continues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We celebrate the memorial of our redemption, O Father, in this sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving. Recalling his death, resurrection, and ascension, we offer you these gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanctify them by your Holy Spirit to be for your people the Body and Blood of your Son, the holy food and drink of new and unending life in him. Sanctify us also that we may faithfully receive this holy Sacrament, and serve you in unity, constancy, and peace; and at the last day bring us with all your saints into the joy of your eternal kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this we ask through your Son Jesus Christ. By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receiving Communion during Covid:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please remain where you are, standing or seated in prayer. After the presider has received the Sacrament in both kinds, donned a mask, and carefully sanitized hands, the presider will bring the sacrament to each person in turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold out your cupped hands to receive the bread. The presider will drop the host into your hands without making contact. (If you prefer to receive gluten-free bread, please tell the presider so.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait until the presider has moved away to remove your mask, consume the host, and replace you mask.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communion will be offered in one kind only (just the bread). This is still full communion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not wish to receive communion physically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross your arms over your chest. The presider will offer you a blessing instead, again without touching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are invited to utter the &lt;em&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/em&gt; while communion is being distributed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prayer-for-spiritual-communion&#34;&gt;Prayer for Spiritual Communion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In union, O Lord, with your faithful people at every altar of your Church, where the Holy Eucharist is now being celebrated, I desire to offer to you praise and thanksgiving. I remember your death, Lord Christ; I proclaim your resurrection; I await your coming in glory. Since I cannot receive you today in the Sacrament of your Body and Blood, I beseech you to come spiritually into my heart. Cleanse and strengthen me with your grace, Lord Jesus, and let me never be separated from you. May I live in you, and you in me, in this life and in the life to come. Amen.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(from &lt;em&gt;The Prayer Book for the Armed Services&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457-1&#34;&gt;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth. (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal God, heavenly Father,&lt;br&gt;
you have graciously accepted us as living members&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
and you have fed us with spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
in the Sacrament of his Body and Blood.&lt;br&gt;
Send us now into the world in peace,&lt;br&gt;
and grant us strength and courage&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
with gladness and singleness of heart;&lt;br&gt;
through Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayer-over-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayer over the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deacon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In order to minimize the possibility of infecting others,&lt;br&gt;
please exit the campus immediately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
