<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive on Shared Prayers</title>
    <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive on Shared Prayers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to School Blessings</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/blessingbackpacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/blessingbackpacks/</guid>
      <description>These blessings are meant to include all students, teachers, and staff beginning a new academic year. All who wish to participate are invited to stand at the front. Tokens of their work for this year (backpacks, computers, datebooks, etc.) may be placed before the altar before the service or at this time. A bowl of olive wood crosses or similar tokens might be placed among the other items in front of the altar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-current/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-current/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministration at the Time of Death (f)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/atdeath-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/atdeath-f/</guid>
      <description>When a person is near death, the Minister of the Congregation should be notified, in order that the ministrations of the Church may be provided. A Prayer for a Person near Death  Almighty God, look on this your servant, lying in great weakness, and comfort her with the promise of life everlasting, given in the resurrection of your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
 Litany at the Time of Death When possible, it is desirable that members of the family and friends come together to join in the Litany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ministration at the Time of Death (m)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/atdeath-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/occasions/atdeath-m/</guid>
      <description>When a person is near death, the Minister of the Congregation should be notified, in order that the ministrations of the Church may be provided. A Prayer for a Person near Death  Almighty God, look on this your servant, lying in great weakness, and comfort him with the promise of life everlasting, given in the resurrection of your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.
 Litany at the Time of Death When possible, it is desirable that members of the family and friends come together to join in the Litany.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist, Rite II (Major Feasts in Covid-tide)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-feasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-feasts/</guid>
      <description>Holy Eucharist
for Sundays and Major Feasts during Covid-tide
according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 355ff.)
The lessons can often be found at lectionarypage.net.
 Preparing for the Liturgy During this season of coronavirus infections, please demonstrate your love for your friends and neighbors by wearing a mask (covering both mouth and nose) and maintaining six feet of social distancing from those not living in your house if you have not been vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist, Rite II (Covid-tide)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-weekday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/he-covid-weekday/</guid>
      <description>Holy Eucharist
for weekdays during Covid-tide
according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 355ff.)
The lessons for weekdays will normally correspond to the remembrance of a particular saint.
 Preparing for the Liturgy During this season of coronavirus infections, please demonstrate your love for your friends and neighbors by wearing a mask (covering both mouth and nose) and maintaining six feet of social distancing from those not living in your house if you have not been vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>