<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holy Week at Home 2020 on Shared Prayers</title>
    <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Holy Week at Home 2020 on Shared Prayers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ante-Communion, Rite II  --- Easter Sunday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-easter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-easter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Sunday of the Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 355)&lt;br&gt;
12 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearA_RCL/HolyWk/APalmSun_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Choose an Officiant and a reader. Light a candle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God’s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ is Risen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord is risen indeed, Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-94356&#34;&gt;BCP 94/356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;canticle-20-glory-to-god-_gloria-in-excelsis_&#34;&gt;Canticle 20: Glory to God, &lt;em&gt;Gloria in excelsis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to God in the highest,&lt;br&gt;
and peace to God’s people on earth.&lt;br&gt;
Lord God, heavenly King,&lt;br&gt;
almighty God and Father,&lt;br&gt;
we worship you,&lt;br&gt;
we give you thanks,&lt;br&gt;
we praise you for your glory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
only Son of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
Lord God, Lamb of God,&lt;br&gt;
you take away the sin of the world:&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us;&lt;br&gt;
you are seated at the right hand of the Father:&lt;br&gt;
receive our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For you alone are the Holy One,&lt;br&gt;
you alone are the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
you alone are the Most High,&lt;br&gt;
Jesus Christ, with the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
in the glory of God the Father. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation-and-collect&#34;&gt;Salutation and Collect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, who through your only-begotten Son Jesus Christ overcame death and opened to us the gate of everlasting life: Grant that we, who celebrate with joy the day of the Lord&amp;rsquo;s resurrection, may be raised from the death of sin by your life-giving Spirit; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Jeremiah 31:1-6 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the prophet Jeremiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, says the Lord, I will be the God of all the families of Israel, and they shall be my people. Thus says the Lord: The people who survived the sword found grace in the wilderness; when Israel sought for rest, the Lord appeared to him from far away. I have loved you with an everlasting love; therefore I have continued my faithfulness to you. Again I will build you, and you shall be built, O virgin Israel! Again you shall take your tambourines, and go forth in the dance of the merrymakers. Again you shall plant vineyards on the mountains of Samaria; the planters shall plant, and shall enjoy the fruit. For there shall be a day when sentinels will call in the hill country of Ephraim:&lt;br&gt;
“Come, let us go up to Zion,&lt;br&gt;
to the Lord our God.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 118:1-2, 14-24&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Confitemini Domino&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP	760)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; *&lt;br&gt;
his mercy endures for ever.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2 Let Israel now proclaim, *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;His mercy endures for ever.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 The Lord is my strength and my song, *&lt;br&gt;
and he has become my salvation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;15 There is a sound of exultation and victory *&lt;br&gt;
in the tents of the righteous:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 &amp;ldquo;The right hand of the Lord has triumphed! *&lt;br&gt;
the right hand of the Lord is exalted!&lt;br&gt;
the right hand of the Lord has triumphed!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;17 I shall not die, but live, *&lt;br&gt;
and declare the works of the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 The Lord has punished me sorely, *&lt;br&gt;
but he did not hand me over to death.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;19 Open for me the gates of righteousness; *&lt;br&gt;
I will enter them;&lt;br&gt;
I will offer thanks to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 &amp;ldquo;This is the gate of the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
he who is righteous may enter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;21 I will give thanks to you, for you answered me *&lt;br&gt;
and have become my salvation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 The same stone which the builders rejected *&lt;br&gt;
has become the chief cornerstone.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;23 This is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s doing, *&lt;br&gt;
and it is marvelous in our eyes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All say together:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;24 On this day the Lord has acted; *&lt;br&gt;
we will rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Acts 10:34-43 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Acts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter began to speak to Cornelius and the other Gentiles: &amp;ldquo;I truly understand that God shows no partiality, but in every nation anyone who fears him and does what is right is acceptable to him. You know the message he sent to the people of Israel, preaching peace by Jesus Christ&amp;ndash;he is Lord of all. That message spread throughout Judea, beginning in Galilee after the baptism that John announced: how God anointed Jesus of Nazareth with the Holy Spirit and with power; how he went about doing good and healing all who were oppressed by the devil, for God was with him. We are witnesses to all that he did both in Judea and in Jerusalem. They put him to death by hanging him on a tree; but God raised him on the third day and allowed him to appear, not to all the people but to us who were chosen by God as witnesses, and who ate and drank with him after he rose from the dead. He commanded us to preach to the people and to testify that he is the one ordained by God as judge of the living and the dead. All the prophets testify about him that everyone who believes in him receives forgiveness of sins through his name.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canticle 13&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;A Song of Praise – Benedictus es, Domine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord God of our fathers; *&lt;br&gt;
you are worthy of praise; glory to you.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to you for the radiance of your holy Name; *&lt;br&gt;
we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you in the splendor of your temple; *&lt;br&gt;
on the throne of your majesty, glory to you.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to you, seated between the Cherubim; *&lt;br&gt;
we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, beholding the depths; *&lt;br&gt;
in the high vault of heaven, glory to you.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to you, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit; *&lt;br&gt;
we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 20:1-18 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on the first day of the week, while it was still dark, Mary Magdalene came to the tomb and saw that the stone had been removed from the tomb. So she ran and went to Simon Peter and the other disciple, the one whom Jesus loved, and said to them, “They have taken the Lord out of the tomb, and we do not know where they have laid him.” Then Peter and the other disciple set out and went toward the tomb. The two were running together, but the other disciple outran Peter and reached the tomb first. He bent down to look in and saw the linen wrappings lying there, but he did not go in. Then Simon Peter came, following him, and went into the tomb. He saw the linen wrappings lying there, and the cloth that had been on Jesus’ head, not lying with the linen wrappings but rolled up in a place by itself. Then the other disciple, who reached the tomb first, also went in, and he saw and believed; for as yet they did not understand the scripture, that he must rise from the dead. Then the disciples returned to their homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mary stood weeping outside the tomb. As she wept, she bent over to look into the tomb; and she saw two angels in white, sitting where the body of Jesus had been lying, one at the head and the other at the feet. They said to her, “Woman, why are you weeping?” She said to them, “They have taken away my Lord, and I do not know where they have laid him.” When she had said this, she turned around and saw Jesus standing there, but she did not know that it was Jesus. Jesus said to her, “Woman, why are you weeping? Whom are you looking for?” Supposing him to be the gardener, she said to him, “Sir, if you have carried him away, tell me where you have laid him, and I will take him away.” Jesus said to her, “Mary!” She turned and said to him in Hebrew, “Rabbouni!” (which means Teacher). Jesus said to her, “Do not hold on to me, because I have not yet ascended to the Father. But go to my brothers and say to them, ‘I am ascending to my Father and your Father, to my God and your God.’” Mary Magdalene went and announced to the disciples, “I have seen the Lord”; and she told them that he had said these things to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-renewal-of-baptismal-vows&#34;&gt;The Renewal of Baptismal Vows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you reaffirm your renunciation of evil and renew your commitment to Jesus Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in God the Father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in God, the Father almighty, creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in Jesus Christ, the Son of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in God the Holy Spirit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints, the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body, and the life everlasting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you continue in the apostles’ teaching and fellowship, in the breaking of bread, and in the prayers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you persevere in resisting evil, and, whenever you fall into sin, repent and return to the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you proclaim by word and example the Good News of God in Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you seek and serve Christ in all persons, loving your neighbor as yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you strive for justice and peace among all people, and respect the dignity of every human being?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May Almighty God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has given us a new birth by water and the Holy Spirit, and bestowed upon us the forgiveness of sins, keep us in eternal life by his grace, in Christ Jesus our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Offciant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joined by the newly baptized in Christ, and filled with joy on this queen of feasts, let us offer prayers to God who fills the darkness of the world with the light of Christ, responding, Glory and praise to you O Living God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That Christ may fill us with the joy and happiness of his holy resurrection, and that we may enter the chamber of the divine wedding feast and rejoice without limit with the angels and saints. In the name of Christ, we pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Anglican Cycle of Prayer, we pray for the Peace of Jerusalem and the People of the Land of the Holy One; and in the Diocese of New Jersey, we pray for Clergy in Transition, members and ministry of the Committee on Deceased members, the Board of Consultation, and the Episcopal Church Women. In the name of Christ, we pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Justin, Archbishop of Canterbury; Michael, Presiding Bishop of the Episcopal Church; William, our diocesan bishop; John, our Deacon; Todd, our Rector; and all other ministers; in the name of  Christ, we pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this country, all nations and their leaders, including Donald, our President; members of the U.S. Congress, Phil, our Governor, and John, our mayor. In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the Borough of Glassboro and its residents including students, faculty and staff of Rowan University and Glassboro Public Schools. In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For justice, mercy, and peace in all the world. In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who are tempted, oppressed, afflicted, or in need.  We pray for all those on our parish prayer list&amp;hellip; In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the dying and the dead, and for those who mourn, remembering the faithfully departed from our parish family: Marilyn and Donald. In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That our Savior may grant us triumph over our visible and invisible enemies and that with Christ we may crush beneath our feet the prince of darkness and all evil powers. In the name of Christ, we pray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory and praise to you, O living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remembering our most glorious and blessed Virgin Mary, blessed Thomas, and all the saints, let us offer ourselves and one another to the living God through Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, O Lord our God, who destroyed death and brought life and immortality to light. Hear our prayers which we offer in the hope of eternal glory, and grant that we who have received new life in baptism may live for ever in the joy of the resurrection. Glory to you, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, now and always and unto the ages of ages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Friday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-goodfri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-goodfri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 276ff.)&lt;br&gt;
10 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/GoodFri_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Light a candle. Sit or kneel in silent prayer before a cross or a crucifix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God’s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-stands-and-begins-the-liturgy-with-the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Officiant stands and begins the liturgy with the Collect of the Day.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be our God,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, we pray you graciously to behold this your family, for whom our Lord Jesus Christ was willing to be betrayed, and given into the hands of sinners, and to suffer death upon the cross; who now lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 52:13––53:12 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, my servant shall prosper;&lt;br&gt;
he shall be exalted and lifted up,&lt;br&gt;
and shall be very high.&lt;br&gt;
Just as there were many who were astonished at him&lt;br&gt;
—so marred was his appearance, beyond human semblance,&lt;br&gt;
and his form beyond that of mortals—&lt;br&gt;
so he shall startle many nations;&lt;br&gt;
kings shall shut their mouths because of him;&lt;br&gt;
for that which had not been told them they shall see,&lt;br&gt;
and that which they had not heard they shall contemplate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who has believed what we have heard?&lt;br&gt;
And to whom has the arm of the Lord been revealed?&lt;br&gt;
For he grew up before him like a young plant,&lt;br&gt;
and like a root out of dry ground;&lt;br&gt;
he had no form or majesty that we should look at him,&lt;br&gt;
nothing in his appearance that we should desire him.&lt;br&gt;
He was despised and rejected by others;&lt;br&gt;
a man of suffering and acquainted with infirmity;&lt;br&gt;
and as one from whom others hide their faces&lt;br&gt;
he was despised, and we held him of no account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely he has borne our infirmities&lt;br&gt;
and carried our diseases;&lt;br&gt;
yet we accounted him stricken,&lt;br&gt;
struck down by God, and afflicted.&lt;br&gt;
But he was wounded for our transgressions,&lt;br&gt;
crushed for our iniquities;&lt;br&gt;
upon him was the punishment that made us whole,&lt;br&gt;
and by his bruises we are healed.&lt;br&gt;
All we like sheep have gone astray;&lt;br&gt;
we have all turned to our own way,&lt;br&gt;
and the Lord has laid on him&lt;br&gt;
the iniquity of us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was oppressed, and he was afflicted,&lt;br&gt;
yet he did not open his mouth;&lt;br&gt;
like a lamb that is led to the slaughter,&lt;br&gt;
and like a sheep that before its shearers is silent,&lt;br&gt;
so he did not open his mouth.&lt;br&gt;
By a perversion of justice he was taken away.&lt;br&gt;
Who could have imagined his future?&lt;br&gt;
For he was cut off from the land of the living,&lt;br&gt;
stricken for the transgression of my people.&lt;br&gt;
They made his grave with the wicked&lt;br&gt;
and his tomb with the rich,&lt;br&gt;
although he had done no violence,&lt;br&gt;
and there was no deceit in his mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet it was the will of the Lord to crush him with pain.&lt;br&gt;
When you make his life an offering for sin,&lt;br&gt;
he shall see his offspring, and shall prolong his days;&lt;br&gt;
through him the will of the Lord shall prosper.&lt;br&gt;
Out of his anguish he shall see light;&lt;br&gt;
he shall find satisfaction through his knowledge.&lt;br&gt;
The righteous one, my servant, shall make many righteous,&lt;br&gt;
and he shall bear their iniquities.&lt;br&gt;
Therefore I will allot him a portion with the great,&lt;br&gt;
and he shall divide the spoil with the strong;&lt;br&gt;
because he poured out himself to death,&lt;br&gt;
and was numbered with the transgressors;&lt;br&gt;
yet he bore the sin of many,&lt;br&gt;
and made intercession for the transgressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 22&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Deus, Deus meus&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 610)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 My God, my God, why have you forsaken me? *&lt;br&gt;
and are so far from my cry and from the words of my distress?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 O my God, I cry in the daytime, but you do not answer; *&lt;br&gt;
by night as well, but I find no rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Yet you are the Holy One, *&lt;br&gt;
enthroned upon the praises of Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Our forefathers put their trust in you; *&lt;br&gt;
they trusted, and you delivered them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 They cried out to you and were delivered; *&lt;br&gt;
they trusted in you and were not put to shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 But as for me, I am a worm and no man, *&lt;br&gt;
scorned by all and despised by the people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 All who see me laugh me to scorn; *&lt;br&gt;
they curl their lips and wag their heads, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 &amp;ldquo;He trusted in the Lord; let him deliver him; *&lt;br&gt;
let him rescue him, if he delights in him.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Yet you are he who took me out of the womb, *&lt;br&gt;
and kept me safe upon my mother&amp;rsquo;s breast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 I have been entrusted to you ever since I was born; *&lt;br&gt;
you were my God when I was still in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 Be not far from me, for trouble is near, *&lt;br&gt;
and there is none to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 Many young bulls encircle me; *&lt;br&gt;
strong bulls of Bashan surround me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 They open wide their jaws at me, *&lt;br&gt;
like a ravening and a roaring lion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 I am poured out like water; all my bones are out of joint; *&lt;br&gt;
my heart within my breast is melting wax.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 My mouth is dried out like a pot-sherd; my tongue sticks to the roof of my mouth; *&lt;br&gt;
and you have laid me in the dust of the grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 Packs of dogs close me in, and gangs of evildoers circle around me; *&lt;br&gt;
they pierce my hands and my feet; I can count all my bones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 They stare and gloat over me; *&lt;br&gt;
they divide my garments among them; they cast lots for my clothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18 Be not far away, O Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
you are my strength; hasten to help me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Save me from the sword, *&lt;br&gt;
my life from the power of the dog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20 Save me from the lion&amp;rsquo;s mouth, *&lt;br&gt;
my wretched body from the horns of wild bulls.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 I will declare your Name to my brethren; *&lt;br&gt;
in the midst of the congregation I will praise you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22 Praise the Lord, you that fear him; *&lt;br&gt;
stand in awe of him, O offspring of Israel; all you of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s line, give glory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 For he does not despise nor abhor the poor in their poverty;&lt;br&gt;
neither does he hide his face from them; *&lt;br&gt;
but when they cry to him he hears them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24 My praise is of him in the great assembly; *&lt;br&gt;
I will perform my vows  in the presence of those who worship him.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 The poor shall eat and be satisfied, and those who seek the Lord shall praise him:*&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;May your heart live for ever!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26 All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the Lord, *&lt;br&gt;
and all the families of the nations  shall bow before him.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27 For kingship belongs to the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
he rules over the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28 To him alone all who sleep in the earth bow down in worship; *&lt;br&gt;
all who go down to the dust fall before him.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 My soul shall live for him; my descendants shall serve him; *&lt;br&gt;
they shall be known as the Lord&amp;rsquo;s for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30 They shall come and make known to a people yet unborn *&lt;br&gt;
the saving deeds that he has done.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hebrews 10:16-25 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the letter to the Hebrews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Spirit testifies saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is the covenant that I will make with them&lt;br&gt;
after those days, says the Lord:&lt;br&gt;
I will put my laws in their hearts,&lt;br&gt;
and I will write them on their minds,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he also adds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I will remember their sins and their lawless deeds no more.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where there is forgiveness of these, there is no longer any offering for sin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, my friends, since we have confidence to enter the sanctuary by the blood of Jesus, by the new and living way that he opened for us through the curtain (that is, through his flesh), and since we have a great priest over the house of God, let us approach with a true heart in full assurance of faith, with our hearts sprinkled clean from an evil conscience and our bodies washed with pure water. Let us hold fast to the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who has promised is faithful. And let us consider how to provoke one another to love and good deeds, not neglecting to meet together, as is the habit of some, but encouraging one another, and all the more as you see the Day approaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-passion-of-our-lord-jesus-christ-according-to-john-----_john-18-19-nrsv_&#34;&gt;The Passion of our Lord Jesus Christ according to John &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 18-19 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-customary-responses-before-and-after-the-gospel-are-omitted&#34;&gt;The customary responses before and after the Gospel are omitted.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-congregation-may-be-seated-for-the-first-part-of-the-passion-at-the-verse-which-mentions-the-arrival-at-golgotha-john-1917-all-stand&#34;&gt;The congregation may be seated for the first part of the Passion. &lt;strong&gt;At the verse which mentions the arrival at Golgotha (John 19:17) all stand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus had spoken these words, he went out with his disciples across the Kidron valley to a place where there was a garden, which he and his disciples entered. Now Judas, who betrayed him, also knew the place, because Jesus often met there with his disciples. So Judas brought a detachment of soldiers together with police from the chief priests and the Pharisees, and they came there with lanterns and torches and weapons. Then Jesus, knowing all that was to happen to him, came forward and asked them, ‘For whom are you looking?’ They answered, ‘Jesus of Nazareth.’ Jesus replied, ‘I am he.’ Judas, who betrayed him, was standing with them. When Jesus said to them, ‘I am he’, they stepped back and fell to the ground. Again he asked them, ‘For whom are you looking?’ And they said, ‘Jesus of Nazareth.’ Jesus answered, ‘I told you that I am he. So if you are looking for me, let these men go.’ This was to fulfil the word that he had spoken, ‘I did not lose a single one of those whom you gave me.’ Then Simon Peter, who had a sword, drew it, struck the high priest’s slave, and cut off his right ear. The slave’s name was Malchus. Jesus said to Peter, ‘Put your sword back into its sheath. Am I not to drink the cup that the Father has given me?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the soldiers, their officer, and the Jewish police arrested Jesus and bound him. First they took him to Annas, who was the father-in-law of Caiaphas, the high priest that year. Caiaphas was the one who had advised the Jews that it was better to have one person die for the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Peter and another disciple followed Jesus. Since that disciple was known to the high priest, he went with Jesus into the courtyard of the high priest, but Peter was standing outside at the gate. So the other disciple, who was known to the high priest, went out, spoke to the woman who guarded the gate, and brought Peter in. The woman said to Peter, ‘You are not also one of this man’s disciples, are you?’ He said, ‘I am not.’ Now the slaves and the police had made a charcoal fire because it was cold, and they were standing round it and warming themselves. Peter also was standing with them and warming himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the high priest questioned Jesus about his disciples and about his teaching. Jesus answered, ‘I have spoken openly to the world; I have always taught in synagogues and in the temple, where all the Jews come together. I have said nothing in secret. Why do you ask me? Ask those who heard what I said to them; they know what I said.’ When he had said this, one of the police standing nearby struck Jesus on the face, saying, ‘Is that how you answer the high priest?’ Jesus answered, ‘If I have spoken wrongly, testify to the wrong. But if I have spoken rightly, why do you strike me?’ Then Annas sent him bound to Caiaphas the high priest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Simon Peter was standing and warming himself. They asked him, ‘You are not also one of his disciples, are you?’ He denied it and said, ‘I am not.’ One of the slaves of the high priest, a relative of the man whose ear Peter had cut off, asked, ‘Did I not see you in the garden with him?’ Again Peter denied it, and at that moment the cock crowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they took Jesus from Caiaphas to Pilate’s headquarters. It was early in the morning. They themselves did not enter the headquarters, so as to avoid ritual defilement and to be able to eat the Passover. So Pilate went out to them and said, ‘What accusation do you bring against this man?’ They answered, ‘If this man were not a criminal, we would not have handed him over to you.’ Pilate said to them, ‘Take him yourselves and judge him according to your law.’ The Jews replied, ‘We are not permitted to put anyone to death.’ (This was to fulfil what Jesus had said when he indicated the kind of death he was to die.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Pilate entered the headquarters again, summoned Jesus, and asked him, ‘Are you the King of the Jews?’ Jesus answered, ‘Do you ask this on your own, or did others tell you about me?’ Pilate replied, ‘I am not a Jew, am I? Your own nation and the chief priests have handed you over to me. What have you done?’ Jesus answered, ‘My kingdom is not from this world. If my kingdom were from this world, my followers would be fighting to keep me from being handed over to the Jews. But as it is, my kingdom is not from here.’ Pilate asked him, ‘So you are a king?’ Jesus answered, ‘You say that I am a king. For this I was born, and for this I came into the world, to testify to the truth. Everyone who belongs to the truth listens to my voice.’ Pilate asked him, ‘What is truth?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he had said this, he went out to the Jews again and told them, ‘I find no case against him. But you have a custom that I release someone for you at the Passover. Do you want me to release for you the King of the Jews?’ They shouted in reply, ‘Not this man, but Barabbas!’ Now Barabbas was a bandit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Pilate took Jesus and had him flogged. And the soldiers wove a crown of thorns and put it on his head, and they dressed him in a purple robe. They kept coming up to him, saying, ‘Hail, King of the Jews!’ and striking him on the face. Pilate went out again and said to them, ‘Look, I am bringing him out to you to let you know that I find no case against him.’ So Jesus came out, wearing the crown of thorns and the purple robe. Pilate said to them, ‘Here is the man!’ When the chief priests and the police saw him, they shouted, ‘Crucify him! Crucify him!’ Pilate said to them, ‘Take him yourselves and crucify him; I find no case against him.’ The Jews answered him, ‘We have a law, and according to that law he ought to die because he has claimed to be the Son of God.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now when Pilate heard this, he was more afraid than ever. He entered his headquarters again and asked Jesus, ‘Where are you from?’ But Jesus gave him no answer. Pilate therefore said to him, ‘Do you refuse to speak to me? Do you not know that I have power to release you, and power to crucify you?’ Jesus answered him, ‘You would have no power over me unless it had been given you from above; therefore the one who handed me over to you is guilty of a greater sin.’ From then on Pilate tried to release him, but the Jews cried out, ‘If you release this man, you are no friend of the emperor. Everyone who claims to be a king sets himself against the emperor.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Pilate heard these words, he brought Jesus outside and sat on the judge’s bench at a place called The Stone Pavement, or in Hebrew Gabbatha. Now it was the day of Preparation for the Passover; and it was about noon. He said to the Jews, ‘Here is your King!’ They cried out, ‘Away with him! Away with him! Crucify him!’ Pilate asked them, ‘Shall I crucify your King?’ The chief priests answered, ‘We have no king but the emperor.’ Then he handed him over to them to be crucified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So they took Jesus; and carrying the cross by himself, he went out to what is called The Place of the Skull, which in Hebrew is called Golgotha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There they crucified him, and with him two others, one on either side, with Jesus between them. Pilate also had an inscription written and put on the cross. It read, ‘Jesus of Nazareth, the King of the Jews.’ Many of the Jews read this inscription, because the place where Jesus was crucified was near the city; and it was written in Hebrew, in Latin, and in Greek. Then the chief priests of the Jews said to Pilate, ‘Do not write, “The King of the Jews”, but, “This man said, I am King of the Jews.” ’ Pilate answered, ‘What I have written I have written.’ When the soldiers had crucified Jesus, they took his clothes and divided them into four parts, one for each soldier. They also took his tunic; now the tunic was seamless, woven in one piece from the top. So they said to one another, ‘Let us not tear it, but cast lots for it to see who will get it.’ This was to fulfil what the scripture says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘They divided my clothes among themselves,&lt;br&gt;
and for my clothing they cast lots.’&lt;br&gt;
And that is what the soldiers did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, standing near the cross of Jesus were his mother, and his mother’s sister, Mary the wife of Clopas, and Mary Magdalene. When Jesus saw his mother and the disciple whom he loved standing beside her, he said to his mother, ‘Woman, here is your son.’ Then he said to the disciple, ‘Here is your mother.’ And from that hour the disciple took her into his own home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, when Jesus knew that all was now finished, he said (in order to fulfil the scripture), ‘I am thirsty.’ A jar full of sour wine was standing there. So they put a sponge full of the wine on a branch of hyssop and held it to his mouth. When Jesus had received the wine, he said, ‘It is finished.’ Then he bowed his head and gave up his spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was the day of Preparation, the Jews did not want the bodies left on the cross during the sabbath, especially because that sabbath was a day of great solemnity. So they asked Pilate to have the legs of the crucified men broken and the bodies removed. Then the soldiers came and broke the legs of the first and of the other who had been crucified with him. But when they came to Jesus and saw that he was already dead, they did not break his legs. Instead, one of the soldiers pierced his side with a spear, and at once blood and water came out. (He who saw this has testified so that you also may believe. His testimony is true, and he knows that he tells the truth.) These things occurred so that the scripture might be fulfilled, ‘None of his bones shall be broken.’ And again another passage of scripture says, ‘They will look on the one whom they have pierced.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these things, Joseph of Arimathea, who was a disciple of Jesus, though a secret one because of his fear of the Jews, asked Pilate to let him take away the body of Jesus. Pilate gave him permission; so he came and removed his body. Nicodemus, who had at first come to Jesus by night, also came, bringing a mixture of myrrh and aloes, weighing about a hundred pounds. They took the body of Jesus and wrapped it with the spices in linen cloths, according to the burial custom of the Jews. Now there was a garden in the place where he was crucified, and in the garden there was a new tomb in which no one had ever been laid. And so, because it was the Jewish day of Preparation, and the tomb was nearby, they laid Jesus there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you-may-access-a-homily-online-or-you-may-want-to-use-the-following-meditation&#34;&gt;You may access a homily online, or you may want to use the following meditation.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jesus Christ is a root out of dry ground.  By his wounds we are healed.  These paradoxes of Isaiah are echoed in the account in John about his death: he is arrested, yet when he speaks the soldiers fall down; he is tried, yet he is King and Son of God and The Man; he is thirsty and dying, yet he is the source of the Spirit and of water and blood to heal us; finally he is buried, but it is in a garden.  All of this means to tell us that God shares our sorrow and need and death and yet transforms it to life and salvation and hope.  More than just a root out of dry ground, his cross is the great tree of life in which we all may shelter.  You may shelter there today.  And all those things in all the world that we pray for today, God holds together in him.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-solemn-collects&#34;&gt;The Solemn Collects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear People of God: Our heavenly Father sent his Son into the world, not to condemn the world, but that the world through him might be saved; that all who believe in him might be delivered from the power of sin and death, and become heirs with him of everlasting life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, therefore, for people everywhere according to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for the holy Catholic Church of Christ throughout the world; For its unity in witness and service; For all bishops and other ministers and the people whom they serve; For William, our Bishop, and all the people of this diocese; For all Christians in this community; For those about to be baptized particularly Brandon; That God will confirm his Church in faith, increase it in love, and preserve it in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for all nations and peoples of the earth, and for those in authority among them; For Donald, the President of the United States; For the Congress and the Supreme Court; For the Members and Representatives of the United Nations; For all who serve the common good; That by God’s help they may seek justice and truth, and live in peace and concord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-1&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for all who suffer and are afflicted in body or in mind; For the hungry and the homeless, the destitute and the oppressed; For the sick, the wounded, and the crippled; For all who are afflicted by the corona virus; For those in loneliness, fear, and anguish; For those who face temptation, doubt, and despair; For the sorrowful and bereaved; For prisoners and captives, and those in mortal danger; That God in his mercy will comfort and relieve them, and grant them the knowledge of his love, and stir up in us the will and patience to minister to their needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-2&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for all who have not received the Gospel of Christ; For those who have never heard the word of salvation; For those who have lost their faith; For those hardened by sin or indifference; For the contemptuous and the scornful; For those who are enemies of the cross of Christ and persecutors of his disciples; For those who in the name of Christ have persecuted others; That God will open their hearts to the truth, and lead them to faith and obedience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-3&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us commit ourselves to our God, and pray for the grace of a holy life, that, with all who have departed this world and have died in the peace of Christ, and those whose faith is known to God alone, we may be accounted worthy to enter into the fullness of the joy of our Lord, and receive the crown of life in the day of resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-4&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God of unchangeable power and eternal light: Look favorably on your whole Church, that wonderful and sacred mystery; by the effectual working of your providence, carry out in tranquillity the plan of salvation; let the whole world see and know that things which were cast down are being raised up, and things which had grown old are being made new, and that all things are being brought to their perfection by him through whom all things were made, your Son Jesus Christ our Lord; who lives and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-hymn-or-anthem-may-be-sung-here-eg-_the-old-rugged-cross_-levas-38&#34;&gt;A hymn or anthem may be sung here: e.g., &lt;em&gt;The Old Rugged Cross&lt;/em&gt; (LEVAS 38).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-veneration-of-the-cross&#34;&gt;The Veneration of the Cross&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-you-may-sit-or-kneel-before-the-cross-in-silence-and-during-the-anthem-that-follows&#34;&gt;Here you may sit or kneel before the cross in silence, and during the anthem that follows.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anthem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We adore you, O Christ, and we bless you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;because by your holy cross you have redeemed the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we have died with him, we shall also live with him;&lt;br&gt;
if we endure, we shall also reign with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We adore you, O Christ, and we bless you,&lt;br&gt;
because by your holy cross you have redeemed the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom,&lt;br&gt;
and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-service-concludes-with-the-following-prayer&#34;&gt;The service concludes with the following prayer.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Jesus Christ, Son of the living God, we pray you to&lt;br&gt;
set your passion, cross, and death between your judgment and our souls, now and in the hour of our death. Give mercy and grace to the living; pardon and rest to the dead; to your holy Church peace and concord; and to us sinners everlasting life and glory; for with the Father and Holy Spirit you live and reign, one God, now and for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-three-days-continues-tomorrow-with-the-great-vigil-of-easterliturgiesholywk-vigil&#34;&gt;The Three Days continues tomorrow with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-vigil&#34;&gt;Great Vigil of Easter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Vigil of Easter</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-vigil/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-vigil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 285ff.)&lt;br&gt;
11 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearA_RCL/Easter/AEasVigil_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sit before an unlit candle and a bowl of water. Have a bell nearby.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God’s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear friends in Christ: On this most holy night, in which our Lord Jesus passed over from death to life, the Church invites her members, dispersed throughout the world, to gather in vigil and prayer. For this is the Passover of the Lord, in which, by hearing his Word and celebrating his Sacraments, we share in his victory over death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-candle-is-lit&#34;&gt;The candle is lit.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light of Christ, rising in glory, dispel the darkness of our  hearts and minds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-reads-the-exsultet-an-easter-proclamation&#34;&gt;The Officiant reads the Exsultet, an “Easter Proclamation.”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-exsultet&#34;&gt;The Exsultet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice now, heavenly hosts and choirs of angels,&lt;br&gt;
and let your trumpets shout Salvation&lt;br&gt;
for the victory of our mighty King.&lt;br&gt;
Rejoice and sing now, all the round earth,&lt;br&gt;
bright with a glorious splendor,&lt;br&gt;
for darkness has been vanquished by our eternal King.&lt;br&gt;
Rejoice and be glad now, Mother Church,&lt;br&gt;
and let your holy courts, in radiant light,&lt;br&gt;
resound with the praises of your people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is truly right and good, always and everywhere,&lt;br&gt;
with our whole heart and mind and voice, to praise you,&lt;br&gt;
the invisible, almighty, and eternal God,&lt;br&gt;
and your only-begotten Son, Jesus Christ our Lord;&lt;br&gt;
for he is the true Paschal Lamb,&lt;br&gt;
who at the feast of the Passover paid for us the debt of Adam’s sin,&lt;br&gt;
and by his blood delivered your faithful people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the night,&lt;br&gt;
when you brought our fathers, the children of Israel, out of bondage in Egypt,&lt;br&gt;
and led them through the Red Sea on dry land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the night,&lt;br&gt;
when all who believe in Christ are delivered from the gloom of sin,&lt;br&gt;
and are restored to grace and holiness of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the night,&lt;br&gt;
when Christ broke the bonds of death and hell, and rose victorious from the grave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy Father, accept our evening sacrifice,&lt;br&gt;
the offering of this candle in your honor.&lt;br&gt;
May it shine continually to drive away all darkness.&lt;br&gt;
May Christ, the Morning Star who knows no setting,&lt;br&gt;
find it ever burning––he who gives his light to all creation,&lt;br&gt;
and who lives and reigns for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-liturgy-of-the-word&#34;&gt;The Liturgy of the Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the time each year where we tell our family story. These are tales told around a campfire, stories told by candlelight. It is the story of God’s saving work in ages past, the story that continues in our own lives today as God brings each of us to the fullness of redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you-may-choose-from-among-these-old-testament-lessons-reading-at-least-two-and-not-neglecting-to-read-3-from-exodus-the-lessons-are-read-without-the-usual-introduction-or-conclusion&#34;&gt;You may choose from among these Old Testament lessons, reading at least two, and not neglecting to read #3, from Exodus. The lessons are read without the usual introduction or conclusion.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I. The Story of Creation&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Genesis 1:1—2:4a NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning when God created the heavens and the earth, the earth was a formless void and darkness covered the face of the deep, while a wind from God swept over the face of the waters. Then God said, ‘Let there be light’; and there was light. And God saw that the light was good; and God separated the light from the darkness. God called the light Day, and the darkness he called Night. And there was evening and there was morning, the first day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, ‘Let there be a dome in the midst of the waters, and let it separate the waters from the waters.’ So God made the dome and separated the waters that were under the dome from the waters that were above the dome. And it was so. God called the dome Sky. And there was evening and there was morning, the second day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, ‘Let the waters under the sky be gathered together into one place, and let the dry land appear.’ And it was so. God called the dry land Earth, and the waters that were gathered together he called Seas. And God saw that it was good. Then God said, ‘Let the earth put forth vegetation: plants yielding seed, and fruit trees of every kind on earth that bear fruit with the seed in it.’ And it was so. The earth brought forth vegetation: plants yielding seed of every kind, and trees of every kind bearing fruit with the seed in it. And God saw that it was good. And there was evening and there was morning, the third day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, ‘Let there be lights in the dome of the sky to separate the day from the night; and let them be for signs and for seasons and for days and years, and let them be lights in the dome of the sky to give light upon the earth.’ And it was so. God made the two great lights—the greater light to rule the day and the lesser light to rule the night—and the stars. God set them in the dome of the sky to give light upon the earth, to rule over the day and over the night, and to separate the light from the darkness. And God saw that it was good. And there was evening and there was morning, the fourth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, ‘Let the waters bring forth swarms of living creatures, and let birds fly above the earth across the dome of the sky.’ So God created the great sea monsters and every living creature that moves, of every kind, with which the waters swarm, and every winged bird of every kind. And God saw that it was good. God blessed them, saying, ‘Be fruitful and multiply and fill the waters in the seas, and let birds multiply on the earth.’ And there was evening and there was morning, the fifth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And God said, ‘Let the earth bring forth living creatures of every kind: cattle and creeping things and wild animals of the earth of every kind.’ And it was so. God made the wild animals of the earth of every kind, and the cattle of every kind, and everything that creeps upon the ground of every kind. And God saw that it was good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then God said, ‘Let us make humankind in our image, according to our likeness; and let them have dominion over the fish of the sea, and over the birds of the air, and over the cattle, and over all the wild animals of the earth, and over every creeping thing that creeps upon the earth.’&lt;br&gt;
So God created humankind in his image,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the image of God he created them;&lt;br&gt;
male and female he created them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God blessed them, and God said to them, ‘Be fruitful and multiply, and fill the earth and subdue it; and have dominion over the fish of the sea and over the birds of the air and over every living thing that moves upon the earth.’ God said, ‘See, I have given you every plant yielding seed that is upon the face of all the earth, and every tree with seed in its fruit; you shall have them for food. And to every beast of the earth, and to every bird of the air, and to everything that creeps on the earth, everything that has the breath of life, I have given every green plant for food.’ And it was so. God saw everything that he had made, and indeed, it was very good. And there was evening and there was morning, the sixth day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the heavens and the earth were finished, and all their multitude. And on the seventh day God finished the work that he had done, and he rested on the seventh day from all the work that he had done. So God blessed the seventh day and hallowed it, because on it God rested from all the work that he had done in creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the generations of the heavens and the earth when they were created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 136.1–9, 23–26&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Confitemini&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 789)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	Give thanks to the LORD, for he is good, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2	Give thanks to the God of gods, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	Give thanks to the Lord of lords, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4	Who only does great wonders, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	Who by wisdom made the heavens, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6	Who spread out the earth upon the waters, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	Who created great lights, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8	The sun to rule the day, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	The moon and the stars to govern the night, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23	Who remembered us in our low estate, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24	And delivered us from our enemies, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25	Who gives food to all creatures, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26	Give thanks to the God of heaven, *&lt;br&gt;
for his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, who wonderfully created, and yet more wonderfully restored, the dignity of human nature: Grant that we may share the divine life of him who humbled himself to share our humanity, your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II. The Flood&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Genesis 7:1-5, 11-18; 8:6-18; 9:8-13 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord said to Noah, &amp;ldquo;Go into the ark, you and all your household, for I have seen that you alone are righteous before me in this generation. Take with you seven pairs of all clean animals, the male and its mate; and a pair of the animals that are not clean, the male and its mate; and seven pairs of the birds of the air also, male and female, to keep their kind alive on the face of all the earth. For in seven days I will send rain on the earth for forty days and forty nights; and every living thing that I have made I will blot out from the face of the ground.&amp;rdquo; And Noah did all that the Lord had commanded him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the six hundredth year of Noah&amp;rsquo;s life, in the second month, on the seventeenth day of the month, on that day all the fountains of the great deep burst forth, and the windows of the heavens were opened. The rain fell on the earth forty days and forty nights. On the very same day Noah with his sons, Shem and Ham and Japheth, and Noah&amp;rsquo;s wife and the three wives of his sons entered the ark, they and every wild animal of every kind, and all domestic animals of every kind, and every creeping thing that creeps on the earth, and every bird of every kind&amp;ndash; every bird, every winged creature. They went into the ark with Noah, two and two of all flesh in which there was the breath of life. And those that entered, male and female of all flesh, went in as God had commanded him; and the Lord shut him in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flood continued forty days on the earth; and the waters increased, and bore up the ark, and it rose high above the earth. The waters swelled and increased greatly on the earth; and the ark floated on the face of the waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of forty days Noah opened the window of the ark that he had made and sent out the raven; and it went to and fro until the waters were dried up from the earth. Then he sent out the dove from him, to see if the waters had subsided from the face of the ground; but the dove found no place to set its foot, and it returned to him to the ark, for the waters were still on the face of the whole earth. So he put out his hand and took it and brought it into the ark with him. He waited another seven days, and again he sent out the dove from the ark; and the dove came back to him in the evening, and there in its beak was a freshly plucked olive leaf; so Noah knew that the waters had subsided from the earth. Then he waited another seven days, and sent out the dove; and it did not return to him any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the six hundred first year, in the first month, the first day of the month, the waters were dried up from the earth; and Noah removed the covering of the ark, and looked, and saw that the face of the ground was drying. In the second month, on the twenty-seventh day of the month, the earth was dry. Then God said to Noah, &amp;ldquo;Go out of the ark, you and your wife, and your sons and your sons&#39; wives with you. Bring out with you every living thing that is with you of all flesh&amp;ndash; birds and animals and every creeping thing that creeps on the earth&amp;ndash; so that they may abound on the earth, and be fruitful and multiply on the earth.&amp;rdquo; So Noah went out with his sons and his wife and his sons&#39; wives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then God said to Noah and to his sons with him, &amp;ldquo;As for me, I am establishing my covenant with you and your descendants after you, and with every living creature that is with you, the birds, the domestic animals, and every animal of the earth with you, as many as came out of the ark. I establish my covenant with you, that never again shall all flesh be cut off by the waters of a flood, and never again shall there be a flood to destroy the earth.&amp;rdquo; God said, &amp;ldquo;This is the sign of the covenant that I make between me and you and every living creature that is with you, for all future generations: I have set my bow in the clouds, and it shall be a sign of the covenant between me and the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-1&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 46&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Deus noster refugium&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP	649)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	God is our refuge and strength, *&lt;br&gt;
a very present help in trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2	Therefore we will not fear, though the earth be moved, *&lt;br&gt;
and though the mountains be toppled into the&lt;br&gt;
depths of the sea;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	Though its waters rage and foam, *&lt;br&gt;
and though the mountains tremble at its tumult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4	The LORD of hosts is with us; *&lt;br&gt;
the God of Jacob is our stronghold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	There is a river whose streams make glad the city of God, *&lt;br&gt;
the holy habitation of the Most High.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6	God is in the midst of her;&lt;br&gt;
she shall not be overthrown; *&lt;br&gt;
God shall help her at the break of day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	The nations make much ado, and the kingdoms are shaken; *&lt;br&gt;
God has spoken, and the earth shall melt away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8	The LORD of hosts is with us; *&lt;br&gt;
the God of Jacob is our stronghold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	Come now and look upon the works of the LORD, *&lt;br&gt;
what awesome things he has done on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10	It is he who makes war to cease in all the world; *&lt;br&gt;
he breaks the bow, and shatters the spear,&lt;br&gt;
and burns the shields with fire.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11	&amp;ldquo;Be still, then, and know that I am God; *&lt;br&gt;
I will be exalted among the nations;&lt;br&gt;
I will be exalted in the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12	The LORD of hosts is with us; *&lt;br&gt;
the God of Jacob is our stronghold.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, you have placed in the skies the sign of your covenant with all living things: Grant that we, who are saved through water and the Spirit, may worthily offer to you our sacrifice of thanksgiving; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III. Israel’s Deliverance at the Red Sea&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Exodus 14:10–31; 15:20-21 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Pharaoh drew near, the Israelites looked back, and there were the Egyptians advancing on them. In great fear the Israelites cried out to the Lord. They said to Moses, &amp;ldquo;Was it because there were no graves in Egypt that you have taken us away to die in the wilderness? What have you done to us, bringing us out of Egypt? Is this not the very thing we told you in Egypt, &amp;lsquo;Let us alone and let us serve the Egyptians&amp;rsquo;? For it would have been better for us to serve the Egyptians than to die in the wilderness.&amp;rdquo; But Moses said to the people, &amp;ldquo;Do not be afraid, stand firm, and see the deliverance that the Lord will accomplish for you today; for the Egyptians whom you see today you shall never see again. The Lord will fight for you, and you have only to keep still.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the Lord said to Moses, &amp;ldquo;Why do you cry out to me? Tell the Israelites to go forward. But you lift up your staff, and stretch out your hand over the sea and divide it, that the Israelites may go into the sea on dry ground. Then I will harden the hearts of the Egyptians so that they will go in after them; and so I will gain glory for myself over Pharaoh and all his army, his chariots, and his chariot drivers. And the Egyptians shall know that I am the Lord, when I have gained glory for myself over Pharaoh, his chariots, and his chariot drivers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The angel of God who was going before the Israelite army moved and went behind them; and the pillar of cloud moved from in front of them and took its place behind them. It came between the army of Egypt and the army of Israel. And so the cloud was there with the darkness, and it lit up the night; one did not come near the other all night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea. The Lord drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night, and turned the sea into dry land; and the waters were divided. The Israelites went into the sea on dry ground, the waters forming a wall for them on their right and on their left. The Egyptians pursued, and went into the sea after them, all of Pharaoh&amp;rsquo;s horses, chariots, and chariot drivers. At the morning watch the Lord in the pillar of fire and cloud looked down upon the Egyptian army, and threw the Egyptian army into panic. He clogged their chariot wheels so that they turned with difficulty. The Egyptians said, &amp;ldquo;Let us flee from the Israelites, for the Lord is fighting for them against Egypt.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the Lord said to Moses, &amp;ldquo;Stretch out your hand over the sea, so that the water may come back upon the Egyptians, upon their chariots and chariot drivers.&amp;rdquo; So Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and at dawn the sea returned to its normal depth. As the Egyptians fled before it, the Lord tossed the Egyptians into the sea. The waters returned and covered the chariots and the chariot drivers, the entire army of Pharaoh that had followed them into the sea; not one of them remained. But the Israelites walked on dry ground through the sea, the waters forming a wall for them on their right and on their left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus the Lord saved Israel that day from the Egyptians; and Israel saw the Egyptians dead on the seashore. Israel saw the great work that the Lord did against the Egyptians. So the people feared the Lord and believed in the Lord and in his servant Moses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the prophet Miriam, Aaron&amp;rsquo;s sister, took a tambourine in her hand; and all the women went out after her with tambourines and with dancing. And Miriam sang to them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sing to the Lord, for he has triumphed gloriously;&lt;br&gt;
horse and rider he has thrown into the sea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-2&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canticle 8&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;The Song of Moses; Cantemus Domino&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(Exodus 15:1-6, 11-13, 17-18; BCP 85)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will sing to the Lord, for he is lofty and uplifted; *&lt;br&gt;
the horse and its rider has he hurled into the sea.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord is my strength and my refuge; *&lt;br&gt;
the Lord has become my Savior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is my God and I will praise him, *&lt;br&gt;
the God of my people and I will exalt him.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord is a mighty warrior; *&lt;br&gt;
Yahweh is his Name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The chariots of Pharaoh and his army has he hurled into the sea; *&lt;br&gt;
the finest of those who bear armor have been&lt;br&gt;
drowned in the Red Sea.&lt;br&gt;
The fathomless deep has overwhelmed them; *&lt;br&gt;
they sank into the depths like a stone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your right hand, O Lord, is glorious in might; *&lt;br&gt;
your right hand, O Lord, has overthrown the enemy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who can be compared with you, O Lord, among the gods? *&lt;br&gt;
who is like you, glorious in holiness,&lt;br&gt;
awesome in renown, and worker of wonders?&lt;br&gt;
You stretched forth your right hand; *&lt;br&gt;
the earth swallowed them up.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With your constant love you led the people you redeemed; *&lt;br&gt;
with your might you brought them in safety to your holy dwelling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You will bring them in and plant them *&lt;br&gt;
on the mount of your possession,&lt;br&gt;
The resting-place you have made for yourself, O Lord, *&lt;br&gt;
the sanctuary, O Lord, that your hand has established.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord shall reign *&lt;br&gt;
for ever and for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, whose wonderful deeds of old shine forth even to our own day, you once delivered by the power of your mighty arm your chosen people from slavery under Pharaoh, to be a sign for us of the salvation of all nations by the water of Baptism: Grant that all the peoples of the earth may be numbered among the offspring of Abraham, and rejoice in the inheritance of Israel; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV. Salvation Offered Freely to All&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 55:1-11 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ho, everyone who thirsts,&lt;br&gt;
come to the waters;&lt;br&gt;
and you that have no money,&lt;br&gt;
come, buy and eat!&lt;br&gt;
Come, buy wine and milk&lt;br&gt;
without money and without price.&lt;br&gt;
Why do you spend your money for that which is not bread,&lt;br&gt;
and your labour for that which does not satisfy?&lt;br&gt;
Listen carefully to me, and eat what is good,&lt;br&gt;
and delight yourselves in rich food.&lt;br&gt;
Incline your ear, and come to me;&lt;br&gt;
listen, so that you may live.&lt;br&gt;
I will make with you an everlasting covenant,&lt;br&gt;
my steadfast, sure love for David.&lt;br&gt;
See, I made him a witness to the peoples,&lt;br&gt;
a leader and commander for the peoples.&lt;br&gt;
See, you shall call nations that you do not know,&lt;br&gt;
and nations that do not know you shall run to you,&lt;br&gt;
because of the Lord your God, the Holy One of Israel,&lt;br&gt;
for he has glorified you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seek the Lord while he may be found,&lt;br&gt;
call upon him while he is near;&lt;br&gt;
let the wicked forsake their way,&lt;br&gt;
and the unrighteous their thoughts;&lt;br&gt;
let them return to the Lord, that he may have mercy on them,&lt;br&gt;
and to our God, for he will abundantly pardon.&lt;br&gt;
For my thoughts are not your thoughts,&lt;br&gt;
nor are your ways my ways, says the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
For as the heavens are higher than the earth,&lt;br&gt;
so are my ways higher than your ways&lt;br&gt;
and my thoughts than your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For as the rain and the snow come down from heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and do not return there until they have watered the earth,&lt;br&gt;
making it bring forth and sprout,&lt;br&gt;
giving seed to the sower and bread to the eater,&lt;br&gt;
so shall my word be that goes out from my mouth;&lt;br&gt;
it shall not return to me empty,&lt;br&gt;
but it shall accomplish that which I purpose,&lt;br&gt;
and succeed in the thing for which I sent it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-3&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canticle 9&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;The First Song of Isaiah; Ecce, Deus&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(Isaiah 12:2-6; BCP 86)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surely, it is God who saves me; *&lt;br&gt;
I will trust in him and not be afraid.&lt;br&gt;
For the Lord is my stronghold and my sure defense, *&lt;br&gt;
and he will be my Savior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore you shall draw water with rejoicing *&lt;br&gt;
from the springs of salvation.&lt;br&gt;
And on that day you shall say, *&lt;br&gt;
Give thanks to the Lord and call upon his Name;&lt;br&gt;
Make his deeds known among the peoples; *&lt;br&gt;
see that they remember that his Name is exalted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sing the praises of the Lord, for he has done great things, *&lt;br&gt;
and this is known in all the world.&lt;br&gt;
Cry aloud, inhabitants of Zion, ring out your joy, *&lt;br&gt;
for the great one in the midst of you is the Holy One of Israel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you have created all things by the power of your Word, and you renew the earth by your Spirit: Give now the water of life to those who thirst for you, that they may bring forth abundant fruit in your glorious kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V. God’s Wisdom Calls a Renewed Israel&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Proverbs 8.1–8, 19–21; 9.4b–6 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does not wisdom call,&lt;br&gt;
and does not understanding raise her voice?&lt;br&gt;
On the heights, beside the way,&lt;br&gt;
at the crossroads she takes her stand;&lt;br&gt;
beside the gates in front of the town,&lt;br&gt;
at the entrance of the portals she cries out:&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;To you, O people, I call,&lt;br&gt;
and my cry is to all that live.&lt;br&gt;
O simple ones, learn prudence;&lt;br&gt;
acquire intelligence, you who lack it.&lt;br&gt;
Hear, for I will speak noble things,&lt;br&gt;
and from my lips will come what is right;&lt;br&gt;
for my mouth will utter truth;&lt;br&gt;
wickedness is an abomination to my lips.&lt;br&gt;
All the words of my mouth are righteous;&lt;br&gt;
there is nothing twisted or crooked in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My fruit is better than gold, even fine gold,&lt;br&gt;
and my yield than choice silver.&lt;br&gt;
I walk in the way of righteousness,&lt;br&gt;
along the paths of justice,&lt;br&gt;
endowing with wealth those who love me,&lt;br&gt;
and filling their treasuries.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To those without sense she says,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Come, eat of my bread&lt;br&gt;
and drink of the wine I have mixed.&lt;br&gt;
Lay aside immaturity, and live,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in the way of insight.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-4&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 19&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Caeli enarrant&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 606)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	The heavens declare the glory of God, *&lt;br&gt;
and the firmament shows his handiwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2	One day tells its tale to another, *&lt;br&gt;
and one night imparts knowledge to another.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	Although they have no words or language, *&lt;br&gt;
and their voices are not heard,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4	Their sound has gone out into all lands, *&lt;br&gt;
and their message to the ends of the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	In the deep has he set a pavilion for the sun; *&lt;br&gt;
it comes forth like a bridegroom out of his chamber;&lt;br&gt;
it rejoices like a champion to run its course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6	It goes forth from the uttermost edge of the heavens&lt;br&gt;
and runs about to the end of it again; *&lt;br&gt;
nothing is hidden from its burning heat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	The law of the LORD is perfect and revives the soul; *&lt;br&gt;
the testimony of the LORD is sure and gives wisdom to the innocent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8	The statutes of the LORD are just and rejoice the heart; *&lt;br&gt;
the commandment of the LORD is clear and gives light to the eyes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	The fear of the LORD is clean and endures for ever; *&lt;br&gt;
the judgments of the LORD are true and righteous altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10	More to be desired are they than gold,&lt;br&gt;
more than much fine gold, *&lt;br&gt;
sweeter far than honey,&lt;br&gt;
than honey in the comb.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11	By them also is your servant enlightened, *&lt;br&gt;
and in keeping them there is great reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12	Who can tell how often he offends? *&lt;br&gt;
cleanse me from my secret faults.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13	Above all, keep your servant from presumptuous sins;&lt;br&gt;
let them not get dominion over me; *&lt;br&gt;
then shall I be whole and sound,&lt;br&gt;
and innocent of a great offense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14	Let the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart be acceptable in your sight, *&lt;br&gt;
O LORD, my strength and my redeemer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you led your ancient people by a pillar of cloud by day and a pillar of fire by night: Grant that we, who serve you now on earth, may come to the joy of that heavenly Jerusalem, where all tears are wiped away and where your saints for ever sing your praise; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VI. The Valley of Dry Bones&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Ezekiel 37:1-14 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hand of the Lord came upon me, and he brought me out by the spirit of the Lord and set me down in the middle of a valley; it was full of bones. He led me all round them; there were very many lying in the valley, and they were very dry. He said to me, ‘Mortal, can these bones live?’ I answered, ‘O Lord God, you know.’ Then he said to me, ‘Prophesy to these bones, and say to them: O dry bones, hear the word of the Lord. Thus says the Lord God to these bones: I will cause breath to enter you, and you shall live. I will lay sinews on you, and will cause flesh to come upon you, and cover you with skin, and put breath in you, and you shall live; and you shall know that I am the Lord.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I prophesied as I had been commanded; and as I prophesied, suddenly there was a noise, a rattling, and the bones came together, bone to its bone. I looked, and there were sinews on them, and flesh had come upon them, and skin had covered them; but there was no breath in them. Then he said to me, ‘Prophesy to the breath, prophesy, mortal, and say to the breath: Thus says the Lord God: Come from the four winds, O breath, and breathe upon these slain, that they may live.’ I prophesied as he commanded me, and the breath came into them, and they lived, and stood on their feet, a vast multitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he said to me, ‘Mortal, these bones are the whole house of Israel. They say, “Our bones are dried up, and our hope is lost; we are cut off completely.” Therefore prophesy, and say to them, Thus says the Lord God: I am going to open your graves, and bring you up from your graves, O my people; and I will bring you back to the land of Israel. And you shall know that I am the Lord, when I open your graves, and bring you up from your graves, O my people. I will put my spirit within you, and you shall live, and I will place you on your own soil; then you shall know that I, the Lord, have spoken and will act, says the Lord.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-5&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 143&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Domine, exaudi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 798)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	LORD, hear my prayer,&lt;br&gt;
and in your faithfulness heed my supplications; *&lt;br&gt;
answer me in your righteousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2	Enter not into judgment with your servant, *&lt;br&gt;
for in your sight shall no one living be justified.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	For my enemy has sought my life;&lt;br&gt;
he has crushed me to the ground; *&lt;br&gt;
he has made me live in dark places like those who&lt;br&gt;
are long dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4	My spirit faints within me; *&lt;br&gt;
my heart within me is desolate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	I remember the time past;&lt;br&gt;
I muse upon all your deeds; *&lt;br&gt;
I consider the works of your hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6	I spread out my hands to you; *&lt;br&gt;
my soul gasps to you like a thirsty land.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	O LORD, make haste to answer me; my spirit fails me; *&lt;br&gt;
do not hide your face from me&lt;br&gt;
or I shall be like those who go down to the Pit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8	Let me hear of your loving-kindness in the morning,&lt;br&gt;
for I put my trust in you; *&lt;br&gt;
show me the road that I must walk,&lt;br&gt;
for I lift up my soul to you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	Deliver me from my enemies, O LORD, *&lt;br&gt;
for I flee to you for refuge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10	Teach me to do what pleases you, for you are my God; *&lt;br&gt;
let your good Spirit lead me on level ground.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11	Revive me, O LORD, for your Name&amp;rsquo;s sake; *&lt;br&gt;
for your righteousness&#39; sake, bring me out of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12	Of your goodness, destroy my enemies&lt;br&gt;
and bring all my foes to naught, *&lt;br&gt;
for truly I am your servant.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, by the Passover of your Son you have brought us out of sin into righteousness and out of death into life: Grant to those who are sealed by your Holy Spirit the will and the power to proclaim you to all the world; through Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VII. The Gathering of God’s People&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Zephaniah 3:14-20 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sing aloud, O daughter Zion;&lt;br&gt;
shout, O Israel!&lt;br&gt;
Rejoice and exult with all your heart,&lt;br&gt;
O daughter Jerusalem!&lt;br&gt;
The Lord has taken away the judgements against you,&lt;br&gt;
he has turned away your enemies.&lt;br&gt;
The king of Israel, the Lord, is in your midst;&lt;br&gt;
you shall fear disaster no more.&lt;br&gt;
On that day it shall be said to Jerusalem:&lt;br&gt;
Do not fear, O Zion;&lt;br&gt;
do not let your hands grow weak.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord, your God, is in your midst,&lt;br&gt;
a warrior who gives victory;&lt;br&gt;
he will rejoice over you with gladness,&lt;br&gt;
he will renew you in his love;&lt;br&gt;
he will exult over you with loud singing&lt;br&gt;
as on a day of festival.&lt;br&gt;
I will remove disaster from you,&lt;br&gt;
so that you will not bear reproach for it.&lt;br&gt;
I will deal with all your oppressors&lt;br&gt;
at that time.&lt;br&gt;
And I will save the lame&lt;br&gt;
and gather the outcast,&lt;br&gt;
and I will change their shame into praise&lt;br&gt;
and renown in all the earth.&lt;br&gt;
At that time I will bring you home,&lt;br&gt;
at the time when I gather you;&lt;br&gt;
for I will make you renowned and praised&lt;br&gt;
among all the peoples of the earth,&lt;br&gt;
when I restore your fortunes&lt;br&gt;
before your eyes, says the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-6&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 98&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Cantate Domino&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 727)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	Sing to the LORD a new song, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has done marvelous things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2	With his right hand and his holy arm *&lt;br&gt;
has he won for himself the victory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	The LORD has made known his victory; *&lt;br&gt;
his righteousness has he openly shown in&lt;br&gt;
the sight of the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4	He remembers his mercy and faithfulness to&lt;br&gt;
the house of Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
and all the ends of the earth have seen the&lt;br&gt;
victory of our God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	Shout with joy to the LORD, all you lands; *&lt;br&gt;
lift up your voice, rejoice, and sing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6	Sing to the LORD with the harp, *&lt;br&gt;
with the harp and the voice of song.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	With trumpets and the sound of the horn *&lt;br&gt;
shout with joy before the King, the LORD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8	Let the sea make a noise and all that is in it, *&lt;br&gt;
the lands and those who dwell therein.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	Let the rivers clap their hands, *&lt;br&gt;
and let the hills ring out with joy before the LORD,&lt;br&gt;
when he comes to judge the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10	In righteousness shall he judge the world *&lt;br&gt;
and the peoples with equity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God of unchangeable power and eternal light: Look favorably on your whole Church, that wonderful and sacred mystery; by the effectual working of your providence, carry out in tranquillity the plan of salvation; let the whole world see and know that things which were cast down are being raised up, and things which had grown old are being made new, and that all things are being brought to their perfection by him through whom all things were made, your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;our-campfire-tale-climaxes-with&#34;&gt;Our campfire tale climaxes with:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-proclamation-of-the-resurrection&#34;&gt;The Proclamation of the Resurrection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ is risen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord is risen indeed! Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ is risen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord is risen indeed! Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ is risen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord is risen indeed! Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;make-noise-ring-bells-shout-alleluia-stomp-your-feet-rejoice&#34;&gt;Make noise! Ring bells! Shout “Alleluia!” Stomp your feet. Rejoice!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;all-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;All stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;all-sing-or-say-the-gloria&#34;&gt;All sing or say the Gloria.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gloria in excelsis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 356 or Hymnal S-280)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to God in the highest,&lt;br&gt;
and peace to God’s people on earth.&lt;br&gt;
Lord God, heavenly King,&lt;br&gt;
almighty God and Father,&lt;br&gt;
we worship you,&lt;br&gt;
we give you thanks,&lt;br&gt;
we praise you for your glory.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
only Son of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
Lord God, Lamb of God,&lt;br&gt;
you take away the sin of the world:&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us;&lt;br&gt;
you are seated at the right hand of the Father:&lt;br&gt;
receive our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For you alone are the Holy One,&lt;br&gt;
you alone are the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
you alone are the Most High,&lt;br&gt;
Jesus Christ, with the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
in the glory of God the Father. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, who made this most holy night to shine with the glory of the Lord’s resurrection: Stir up in your Church that Spirit of adoption which is given to us in Baptism, that we, being renewed both in body and mind, may worship you in sincerity and truth; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you, in the unity of the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Epistle&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Romans 6:3–11 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the letter to the Romans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you not know that all of us who have been baptized into Christ Jesus were baptized into his death? Therefore we have been buried with him by baptism into death, so that, just as Christ was raised from the dead by the glory of the Father, so we too might walk in newness of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For if we have been united with him in a death like his, we will certainly be united with him in a resurrection like his. We know that our old self was crucified with him so that the body of sin might be destroyed, and we might no longer be enslaved to sin. For whoever has died is freed from sin. But if we have died with Christ, we believe that we will also live with him. We know that Christ, being raised from the dead, will never die again; death no longer has dominion over him. The death he died, he died to sin, once for all; but the life he lives, he lives to God. So you also must consider yourselves dead to sin and alive to God in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Gospel&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Matthew 28.1–10 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Matthew’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the sabbath, as the first day of the week was dawning, Mary Magdalene and the other Mary went to see the tomb. And suddenly there was a great earthquake; for an angel of the Lord, descending from heaven, came and rolled back the stone and sat on it. His appearance was like lightning, and his clothing white as snow. For fear of him the guards shook and became like dead men. But the angel said to the women, ‘Do not be afraid; I know that you are looking for Jesus who was crucified. He is not here; for he has been raised, as he said. Come, see the place where he lay. Then go quickly and tell his disciples, “He has been raised from the dead, and indeed he is going ahead of you to Galilee; there you will see him.” This is my message for you.’ So they left the tomb quickly with fear and great joy, and ran to tell his disciples. Suddenly Jesus met them and said, ‘Greetings!’ And they came to him, took hold of his feet, and worshipped him. Then Jesus said to them, ‘Do not be afraid; go and tell my brothers to go to Galilee; there they will see me.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-renewal-of-baptismal-vows&#34;&gt;The Renewal of Baptismal Vows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you reaffirm your renunciation of evil and renew your commitment to Jesus Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in God the Father?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in God, the Father almighty, creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in Jesus Christ, the Son of God?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in God the Holy Spirit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I believe in the Holy Spirit, the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints, the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body, and the life everlasting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you continue in the apostles’ teaching and fellowship, in the breaking of bread, and in the prayers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you persevere in resisting evil, and, whenever you fall into sin, repent and&lt;br&gt;
return to the Lord?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you proclaim by word and example the Good News of God in Christ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you seek and serve Christ in all persons, loving your neighbor as yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will you strive for justice and peace among all people, and respect the dignity&lt;br&gt;
of every human being?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I will, with God’s help.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May Almighty God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has given us a new birth by water and the Holy Spirit, and bestowed upon us the forgiveness of sins, keep us in eternal life by his grace, in Christ Jesus our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;remembering-your-baptism-make-the-sign-of-the-cross-on-your-forehead-with-water-from-the-bowl&#34;&gt;Remembering your baptism, make the sign of the cross on your forehead with water from the bowl.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this most holy night, we pray for the church, the earth, the world, those in need, and all the members of God’s family, responding to each petition with the words, Hear our prayer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, O God, for all the churches around the globe: for their bishops and clergy; for the newly baptized; for the believers who cannot assemble for worship; for faithful endurance during this time of sorrow and distress; and for a deepening sense of your presence among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-1&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are our Temple: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, O God, for the well-being of creation: for the health of seas and rivers and lakes; for the Delaware and the Atlantic; and for the will to care for your earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-2&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are our Rainbow of promise: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, O God, for peace and justice in the world: for an end to war and international turmoil; for concord in our troubled society; for the heads of state, legislators, and local civic leaders, that they enact wise procedures to deal with the coronavirus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-3&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are our Mighty Fortress: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, O God for all who are facing the coronavirus: for all who mourn their dead; all who have contracted the virus; those who are quarantined or stranded away from home; those who have lost their employment; those who fear the present and the future. We pray for physicians, nurses, and home health aides; medical researchers; the Centers for Disease Control and the World Health Organization. Fill the aching in our hearts with your merciful power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-4&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are our Everlasting Arms: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray, O God, for all in need: for those suffering for the faith; for those who are poor, hungry, and homeless; for those who are sick and those awaiting death; and for those we name before you here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-5&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are the Healer of our every ill: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:	We pray, O God, for the desires of our hearts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-longer-period-of-silence&#34;&gt;A longer period of silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, you are our Heart’s Desire: in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive our thanks for all who died in the faith, and bring us at the final resurrection into your everlasting life, where sorrows will be no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-6&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, our Beginning and our End, in your mercy,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hear our prayer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Into your gracious and mighty hands, O God, we commend all for whom we pray, trusting in your mercy, through your Son Jesus Christ, our Savior and Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom,&lt;br&gt;
and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eternal giver of life and light, this holy night shines with the radiance of the risen Christ. Renew your church with the Spirit given us in baptism, that we may worship you in sincerity and truth and may shine as a light in the world, through your Son, Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and forever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ is Risen!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord is risen indeed, Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord. Alleluia! Alleluia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God. Alleluia! Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maundy Thursday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-maundythurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-maundythurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 274ff.)&lt;br&gt;
9 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/MaundyTh_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Set out a bowl of water and a clean towel. Light a candle. Sit with them before you and then begin by remembering God’s forgiveness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-penitential-order&#34;&gt;A Penitential Order&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bless the Lord who forgives all our sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;God’s mercy endures for ever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear the commandments of God to God’s people: I am the Lord your God who brought you out of bondage. You shall have no other gods but me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not make for yourself any idol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not invoke with malice the Name of the Lord your God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the Sabbath Day and keep it holy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honor your father and your mother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit murder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not commit adultery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not be a false witness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shall not covet anything that belongs to your neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen. Lord have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we have a great high priest who has passed through the heavens, Jesus, the Son of God, let us with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. &lt;em&gt;(Hebrews 4:14, 16 NRSV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-may-be-kept&#34;&gt;Silence may be kept.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done, and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us, forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen us in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy God,&lt;br&gt;
Holy and Mighty,&lt;br&gt;
Holy Immortal One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have mercy upon us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-proper-to-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty Father, whose dear Son, on the night before he suffered, instituted the Sacrament of his Body and Blood: Mercifully grant that we may receive it thankfully in remembrance of Jesus Christ our Lord, who in these holy mysteries gives us a pledge of eternal life; and who now lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Exodus 12:1-14 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Exodus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord said to Moses and Aaron in the land of Egypt: This month shall mark for you the beginning of months; it shall be the first month of the year for you. Tell the whole congregation of Israel that on the tenth of this month they are to take a lamb for each family, a lamb for each household. If a household is too small for a whole lamb, it shall join its closest neighbour in obtaining one; the lamb shall be divided in proportion to the number of people who eat of it. Your lamb shall be without blemish, a year-old male; you may take it from the sheep or from the goats. You shall keep it until the fourteenth day of this month; then the whole assembled congregation of Israel shall slaughter it at twilight. They shall take some of the blood and put it on the two doorposts and the lintel of the houses in which they eat it. They shall eat the lamb that same night; they shall eat it roasted over the fire with unleavened bread and bitter herbs. Do not eat any of it raw or boiled in water, but roasted over the fire, with its head, legs, and inner organs. You shall let none of it remain until the morning; anything that remains until the morning you shall burn. This is how you shall eat it: your loins girded, your sandals on your feet, and your staff in your hand; and you shall eat it hurriedly. It is the passover of the Lord. For I will pass through the land of Egypt that night, and I will strike down every firstborn in the land of Egypt, both human beings and animals; on all the gods of Egypt I will execute judgements: I am the Lord. The blood shall be a sign for you on the houses where you live: when I see the blood, I will pass over you, and no plague shall destroy you when I strike the land of Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day shall be a day of remembrance for you. You shall celebrate it as a festival to the Lord; throughout your generations you shall observe it as a perpetual ordinance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 116:1,10-17&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Dilexi, quoniam&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 759)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1  I love the Lord, because he has heard the voice of my supplication, *&lt;br&gt;
because he has inclined his ear to me whenever I called upon him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 How shall I repay the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
for all the good things he has done for me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 I will lift up the cup of salvation *&lt;br&gt;
and call upon the Name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 I will fulfill my vows to the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
in the presence of all his people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Precious in the sight of the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
is the death of his servants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 O Lord, I am your servant; *&lt;br&gt;
I am your servant and the child of your handmaid; you have freed me from my bonds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 I will offer you the sacrifice of thanksgiving *&lt;br&gt;
and call upon the Name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 I will fulfill my vows to the Lord *&lt;br&gt;
in the presence of all his people,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;17 In the courts of the Lord’s house, *&lt;br&gt;
in the midst of you, O Jerusalem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hallelujah!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;1 Corinthians 11:23-26 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s first letter to the church at Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For I received from the Lord what I also handed on to you, that the Lord Jesus on the night when he was betrayed took a loaf of bread, and when he had given thanks, he broke it and said, ‘This is my body that is for you. Do this in remembrance of me.’ In the same way he took the cup also, after supper, saying, ‘This cup is the new covenant in my blood. Do this, as often as you drink it, in remembrance of me.’ For as often as you eat this bread and drink the cup, you proclaim the Lord’s death until he comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 13:1-17, 31b-35 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before the festival of the Passover, Jesus knew that his hour had come to depart from this world and go to the Father. Having loved his own who were in the world, he loved them to the end. The devil had already put it into the heart of Judas son of Simon Iscariot to betray him. And during supper Jesus, knowing that the Father had given all things into his hands, and that he had come from God and was going to God, got up from the table, took off his outer robe, and tied a towel around himself. Then he poured water into a basin and began to wash the disciples’ feet and to wipe them with the towel that was tied around him. He came to Simon Peter, who said to him, ‘Lord, are you going to wash my feet?’ Jesus answered, ‘You do not know now what I am doing, but later you will understand.’ Peter said to him, ‘You will never wash my feet.’ Jesus answered, ‘Unless I wash you, you have no share with me.’ Simon Peter said to him, ‘Lord, not my feet only but also my hands and my head!’ Jesus said to him, ‘One who has bathed does not need to wash, except for the feet, but is entirely clean. And you are clean, though not all of you.’ For he knew who was to betray him; for this reason he said, ‘Not all of you are clean.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After he had washed their feet, had put on his robe, and had returned to the table, he said to them, ‘Do you know what I have done to you? You call me Teacher and Lord—and you are right, for that is what I am. So if I, your Lord and Teacher, have washed your feet, you also ought to wash one another’s feet. For I have set you an example, that you also should do as I have done to you. Very truly, I tell you, servants are not greater than their master, nor are messengers greater than the one who sent them. If you know these things, you are blessed if you do them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he had gone out, Jesus said, ‘Now the Son of Man has been glorified, and God has been glorified in him. If God has been glorified in him, God will also glorify him in himself and will glorify him at once. Little children, I am with you only a little longer. You will look for me; and as I said to the Jews so now I say to you, “Where I am going, you cannot come.” I give you a new commandment, that you love one another. Just as I have loved you, you also should love one another. By this everyone will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lector:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;you-may-access-a-homily-online-at-the-church-website-or-you-may-want-to-use-the-following-meditation&#34;&gt;You may access a homily online at the church website. Or you may want to use the following meditation.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This word about the love of Jesus is always the beginning of any time.  By remembering the Passover and the Last Supper and the footwashing, we are not trying to get back to an old time.  In the face of the suffering and death with which the world is filled, our trying would not come to much.  But God’s word comes to us now.  To our time.  Even when we cannot meet for the holy supper together, this word — which takes these three nights to say — comes to us: Jesus Christ is our forgiveness.  He is the Lamb whose blood marks the doors of our houses and bodies.  In the power of the Spirit, he has washed our feet and our lives.  And he turns us toward our neighbors.  In this word — and in the cross proclaimed tomorrow and the resurrection proclaimed on Saturday night — Easter comes out to hold us already.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;this-is-the-time-when-we-wash-feet-recalling-jesus-washing-his-disciples-feet-the-washing-of-his-disciples-feet-was-a-demonstration-of-christs-love-for-us-and-was-followed-immediately-with-a-new-commandment-that-we-love-one-another-as-he-loved-them-as-we-work-together-to-suppress-the-death-toll-of-the-covid-19-virus-washing-our-hands-is-an-expression-of-love-for-our-neighbor-here-you-may-wash-your-hands-using-the-water-in-the-bowl&#34;&gt;This is the time when we wash feet, recalling Jesus washing his disciples’ feet. The washing of his disciples’ feet was a demonstration of Christ’s love for us, and was followed immediately with a “new commandment”: that we love one another as he loved them. As we work together to suppress the death toll of the Covid-19 virus, washing our hands is an expression of love for our neighbor. Here you may wash your hands, using the water in the bowl.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United with Christians around the globe on this Maundy Thursday, let us pray for the church, the earth, our troubled world, and all in need, responding to each petition with the words, Your mercy is great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, holy God, for the church. Gather all the baptized around your presence in the Word. Strengthen the body of your people even when we cannot assemble for worship. Grant Bishop Stokes and all our clergy faithfulness and creativity for their ministry in this time, and accompany those preparing for baptism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-1&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, holy God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, bountiful God, for this good earth and for the flowering of springtime. Save dry lands from destructive droughts. Protect the waters from pollution. Allow in this time the planting of fields for food. Make us into care-givers of your plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-2&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, bountiful God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, sovereign God, for our nation. Inspire all people to live in peace and concord. Grant wisdom and courage to heads of state and to legislators as they face the coronavirus. Lead our elected officials to champion the cause of the needy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-3&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, sovereign God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, faithful God, for you accompany suffering humanity with love. Abide wherever the coronavirus has struck. Visit all who mourn their dead; all who have contracted the virus; those who are quarantined or stranded away from home; those who have lost their employment; those who fear the present and the future. Support physicians, nurses, and home health aides; medical researchers; and the World Health Organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-4&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, faithful God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, gracious God, for you care for the needy. We beg you to feed the hungry, protect the refugee, embrace the distressed, house the homeless, nurse the sick, and comfort the dying. Especially we pray for those on our parish prayer list&amp;hellip; and for those others we name before you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-5&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, gracious God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, loving God, that your Son knelt before us, your unworthy servants. Preserve our lives, comfort our anxiety, and receive now the petitions of our hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-longer-period-of-silence&#34;&gt;A longer period of silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hear us, loving God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, eternal God, for all who have died in the faith, especially Marilyn and Donald, and those whom we name before you now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-silence-6&#34;&gt;A brief silence.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end, bring us with them into your everlasting glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hear us, eternal God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mercy is great.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive, merciful God, our prayers, for the sake of Jesus Christ, the host of our meal of life, who died and rose that we might live with you, now and forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord’s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-final-rite-of-the-maundy-thursday-services-is-the-stripping-of-the-altar-herehttpsbuildfaithorgmaundy-thursday-at-home-you-will-find-a-suggestion-for-how-you-might-live-into-this-rite-at-home&#34;&gt;The final rite of the Maundy Thursday services is the stripping of the altar. &lt;a href=&#34;https://buildfaith.org/maundy-thursday-at-home/&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you will find a suggestion for how you might live into this rite at home.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-three-days-continue-tomorrow-with-the-service-for-good-fridayliturgiesholywk-goodfri&#34;&gt;The Three Days continue tomorrow with the service for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sharedprayers.net/liturgies/holywk-goodfri&#34;&gt;Good Friday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Wednesday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-epwed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-epwed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Wednesday, 8 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyWed_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will bless the Lord who gives me counsel; my heart teaches me, night after night.  I have set the Lord always before me; because he is at my right hand, I shall not fall.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 16:7,8)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praises, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 70&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Deus, in adjutorium&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 682&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Be pleased, O God, to deliver me; *&lt;br&gt;
O Lord, make haste to help me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 Let those who seek my life be ashamed&lt;br&gt;
and altogether dismayed; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who take pleasure in my misfortune&lt;br&gt;
draw back and be disgraced.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Let those who say to me &amp;ldquo;Aha!&amp;rdquo; and gloat over me turn back, *&lt;br&gt;
because they are ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Let all who seek you rejoice and be glad in you; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who love your salvation say for ever,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Great is the Lord!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 But as for me, I am poor and needy; *&lt;br&gt;
come to me speedily, O God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 You are my helper and my deliverer; *&lt;br&gt;
O Lord, do not tarry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 50:4&amp;ndash;9a NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has given me&lt;br&gt;
the tongue of a teacher,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that I may know how to sustain&lt;br&gt;
the weary with a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning by morning he wakens&amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;
wakens my ear&lt;br&gt;
to listen as those who are taught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has opened my ear,&lt;br&gt;
and I was not rebellious,&lt;br&gt;
I did not turn backward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave my back to those who struck me,&lt;br&gt;
and my cheeks to those who pulled out the beard;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not hide my face&lt;br&gt;
from insult and spitting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God helps me;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have not been disgraced;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;therefore I have set my face like flint,&lt;br&gt;
and I know that I shall not be put to shame;&lt;br&gt;
he who vindicates me is near.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who will contend with me?&lt;br&gt;
Let us stand up together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are my adversaries?&lt;br&gt;
Let them confront me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the Lord God who helps me;&lt;br&gt;
who will declare me guilty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hebrews 12:1&amp;ndash;3 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Hebrews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight and the sin that clings so closely, and let us run with perseverance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus the pioneer and perfecter of our faith, who for the sake of the joy that was set before him endured the cross, disregarding its shame, and has taken his seat at the right hand of the throne of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider him who endured such hostility against himself from sinners, so that you may not grow weary or lose heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 13:21-32 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At supper with his friends, Jesus was troubled in spirit, and declared, &amp;ldquo;Very truly, I tell you, one of you will betray me.&amp;rdquo; The disciples looked at one another, uncertain of whom he was speaking. One of his disciples&amp;ndash; the one whom Jesus loved&amp;ndash; was reclining next to him; Simon Peter therefore motioned to him to ask Jesus of whom he was speaking. So while reclining next to Jesus, he asked him, &amp;ldquo;Lord, who is it?&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;It is the one to whom I give this piece of bread when I have dipped it in the dish.&amp;rdquo; So when he had dipped the piece of bread, he gave it to Judas son of Simon Iscariot. After he received the piece of bread, Satan entered into him. Jesus said to him, &amp;ldquo;Do quickly what you are going to do.&amp;rdquo; Now no one at the table knew why he said this to him. Some thought that, because Judas had the common purse, Jesus was telling him, &amp;ldquo;Buy what we need for the festival&amp;rdquo;; or, that he should give something to the poor. So, after receiving the piece of bread, he immediately went out. And it was night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he had gone out, Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Now the Son of Man has been glorified, and God has been glorified in him. If God has been glorified in him, God will also glorify him in himself and will glorify him at once.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&#39; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord God, whose blessed Son our Savior gave his body to be whipped and his face to be spit upon: Give us grace to accept joyfully the sufferings of the present time, confident of the glory that shall be revealed; through Jesus Christ your Son our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glory to God whose power, working in us, can do infinitely more than we can ask or imagine:  Glory to him from generation to generation in the Church, and in Christ Jesus for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Ephesians 3:20,21)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Tuesday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-eptue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-eptue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Tuesday, 7 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyTue_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yours is the day, O God, yours also the night; you established the moon and the sun.  You fixed all the boundaries of the earth; you made both summer and winter.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 74:15,16)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praises, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 71:1-14&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;In te, Domine, speravi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 683&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 In you, O Lord, have I taken refuge; *&lt;br&gt;
let me never be ashamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 In your righteousness, deliver me and set me free; *&lt;br&gt;
incline your ear to me and save me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 Be my strong rock, a castle to keep me safe; *&lt;br&gt;
you are my crag and my stronghold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4 Deliver me, my God, from the hand of the wicked, *&lt;br&gt;
from the clutches of the evildoer and the oppressor.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 For you are my hope, O Lord God, *&lt;br&gt;
my confidence since I was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 I have been sustained by you ever since I was born;&lt;br&gt;
from my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb you have been my strength; *&lt;br&gt;
my praise shall be always of you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 I have become a portent to many; *&lt;br&gt;
but you are my refuge and my strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 Let my mouth be full of your praise *&lt;br&gt;
and your glory all the day long.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Do not cast me off in my old age; *&lt;br&gt;
forsake me not when my strength fails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 For my enemies are talking against me, *&lt;br&gt;
and those who lie in wait for my life take counsel together.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 They say, &amp;ldquo;God has forsaken him;&lt;br&gt;
go after him and seize him; *&lt;br&gt;
because there is none who will save.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 O God, be not far from me; *&lt;br&gt;
come quickly to help me, O my God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Let those who set themselves against me be put to shame and be disgraced; *&lt;br&gt;
let those who seek to do me evil be covered with scorn and reproach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 But I shall always wait in patience, *&lt;br&gt;
and shall praise you more and more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 49:1&amp;ndash;7 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to me, O coastlands,&lt;br&gt;
pay attention, you peoples from far away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord called me before I was born,&lt;br&gt;
while I was in my mother&amp;rsquo;s womb he named me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He made my mouth like a sharp sword,&lt;br&gt;
in the shadow of his hand he hid me;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he made me a polished arrow,&lt;br&gt;
in his quiver he hid me away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he said to me, &amp;ldquo;You are my servant,&lt;br&gt;
Israel, in whom I will be glorified.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I said, &amp;ldquo;I have labored in vain,&lt;br&gt;
I have spent my strength for nothing and vanity;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;yet surely my cause is with the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
and my reward with my God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now the Lord says,&lt;br&gt;
who formed me in the womb to be his servant,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to bring Jacob back to him,&lt;br&gt;
and that Israel might be gathered to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for I am honored in the sight of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
and my God has become my strength&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;he says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is too light a thing that you should be my servant&lt;br&gt;
to raise up the tribes of Jacob and to restore the survivors of Israel;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will give you as a light to the nations,&lt;br&gt;
that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
the Redeemer of Israel and his Holy One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to one deeply despised, abhorred by the nations,&lt;br&gt;
the slave of rulers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kings shall see and stand up,&lt;br&gt;
princes, and they shall prostrate themselves,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because of the Lord, who is faithful,&lt;br&gt;
the Holy One of Israel, who has chosen you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;1 Corinthians 1:18&amp;ndash;31 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from Paul&amp;rsquo;s first letter to the church in Corinth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The message about the cross is foolishness to those who are perishing, but to us who are being saved it is the power of God. For it is written,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I will destroy the wisdom of the wise,&lt;br&gt;
and the discernment of the discerning I will thwart.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the one who is wise? Where is the scribe? Where is the debater of this age? Has not God made foolish the wisdom of the world? For since, in the wisdom of God, the world did not know God through wisdom, God decided, through the foolishness of our proclamation, to save those who believe. For Jews demand signs and Greeks desire wisdom, but we proclaim Christ crucified, a stumbling block to Jews and foolishness to Gentiles, but to those who are the called, both Jews and Greeks, Christ the power of God and the wisdom of God. For God&amp;rsquo;s foolishness is wiser than human wisdom, and God&amp;rsquo;s weakness is stronger than human strength.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider your own call, brothers and sisters: not many of you were wise by human standards, not many were powerful, not many were of noble birth. But God chose what is foolish in the world to shame the wise; God chose what is weak in the world to shame the strong; God chose what is low and despised in the world, things that are not, to reduce to nothing things that are, so that no one might boast in the presence of God. He is the source of your life in Christ Jesus, who became for us wisdom from God, and righteousness and sanctification and redemption, in order that, as it is written, &amp;ldquo;Let the one who boasts, boast in the Lord.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;John 12:20-36 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among those who went up to worship at the festival were some Greeks. They came to Philip, who was from Bethsaida in Galilee, and said to him, &amp;ldquo;Sir, we wish to see Jesus.&amp;rdquo; Philip went and told Andrew; then Andrew and Philip went and told Jesus. Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;The hour has come for the Son of Man to be glorified. Very truly, I tell you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains just a single grain; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. Those who love their life lose it, and those who hate their life in this world will keep it for eternal life. Whoever serves me must follow me, and where I am, there will my servant be also. Whoever serves me, the Father will honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now my soul is troubled. And what should I say&amp;ndash; `Father, save me from this hour&#39;? No, it is for this reason that I have come to this hour. Father, glorify your name.&amp;rdquo; Then a voice came from heaven, &amp;ldquo;I have glorified it, and I will glorify it again.&amp;rdquo; The crowd standing there heard it and said that it was thunder. Others said, &amp;ldquo;An angel has spoken to him.&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered, &amp;ldquo;This voice has come for your sake, not for mine. Now is the judgment of this world; now the ruler of this world will be driven out. And I, when I am lifted up from the earth, will draw all people to myself.&amp;rdquo; He said this to indicate the kind of death he was to die. The crowd answered him, &amp;ldquo;We have heard from the law that the Messiah remains forever. How can you say that the Son of Man must be lifted up? Who is this Son of Man?&amp;rdquo; Jesus said to them, &amp;ldquo;The light is with you for a little longer. Walk while you have the light, so that the darkness may not overtake you. If you walk in the darkness, you do not know where you are going. While you have the light, believe in the light, so that you may become children of light.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Jesus had said this, he departed and hid from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&#39; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, by the passion of your blessed Son you made an instrument of shameful death to be for us the means of life: Grant us so to glory in the cross of Christ, that we may gladly suffer shame and loss for the sake of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May the God of hope fill us with all joy and peace in believing through the power of the Holy Spirit.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(Romans 15:13)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evening Prayer for Monday of Holy Week</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-epmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 21:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/holywk-epmon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 115)&lt;br&gt;
Monday, 6 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearABC_RCL/HolyWk/HolyMon_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Preparations for Evening Prayer need not be complex. Light a candle if possible. Invite anyone else who might be in your home to pray with you. There are three traditional roles in Evening Prayer: the officiant, the lector, and the people of God (everyone else). These roles can be combined or traded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-begins-the-service-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant begins the service with the following sentence of Scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let my prayer be set forth in your sight as incense, the lifting up of my hands as the evening sacrifice.  &lt;em&gt;(Psalm 141:2)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-invitatory-and-psalter&#34;&gt;The Invitatory and Psalter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, make speed to save us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Lord, make haste to help us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O Gracious Light&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;   &lt;em&gt;Phos hilaron&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O gracious light,&lt;br&gt;
pure brightness of the everliving Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
O Jesus Christ, holy and blessed!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now as we come to the setting of the sun,&lt;br&gt;
and our eyes behold the vesper light,&lt;br&gt;
we sing your praises, O God:  Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You are worthy at all times to be praised by happy voices,&lt;br&gt;
O Son of God, O Giver of Life,&lt;br&gt;
and to be glorified through all the worlds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-psalm-appointed&#34;&gt;The Psalm Appointed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-psalm-is-sung-or-said-in-a-suitable-manner-eg-responsively-by-verse-or-unison&#34;&gt;The Psalm is sung or said In a suitable manner (e.g., responsively by verse or unison).&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 36.5–11&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Dixit injustus&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;BCP 632&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Your love, O Lord, reaches to the heavens, *&lt;br&gt;
and your faithfulness to the clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6 Your righteousness is like the strong mountains,&lt;br&gt;
your justice like the great deep; *&lt;br&gt;
you save both man and beast, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7 How priceless is your love, O God! *&lt;br&gt;
your people take refuge under the shadow of your wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8 They feast upon the abundance of your house; *&lt;br&gt;
you give them drink from the river of your delights.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 For with you is the well of life, *&lt;br&gt;
and in your light we see light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 Continue your loving-kindness to those who know you, *&lt;br&gt;
and your favor to those who are true of heart.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 Let not the foot of the proud come near me, *&lt;br&gt;
nor the hand of the wicked push me aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-lessons&#34;&gt;The Lessons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 42:1&amp;ndash;9 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my servant, whom I uphold,&lt;br&gt;
my chosen, in whom my soul delights;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have put my spirit upon him;&lt;br&gt;
he will bring forth justice to the nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will not cry or lift up his voice,&lt;br&gt;
or make it heard in the street;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a bruised reed he will not break,&lt;br&gt;
and a dimly burning wick he will not quench;&lt;br&gt;
he will faithfully bring forth justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will not grow faint or be crushed&lt;br&gt;
until he has established justice in the earth;&lt;br&gt;
and the coastlands wait for his teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus says God, the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
who created the heavens and stretched them out,&lt;br&gt;
who spread out the earth and what comes from it,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;who gives breath to the people upon it&lt;br&gt;
and spirit to those who walk in it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the Lord, I have called you in righteousness,&lt;br&gt;
I have taken you by the hand and kept you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have given you as a covenant to the people,&lt;br&gt;
a light to the nations,&lt;br&gt;
to open the eyes that are blind,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to bring out the prisoners from the dungeon,&lt;br&gt;
from the prison those who sit in darkness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the Lord, that is my name;&lt;br&gt;
my glory I give to no other,&lt;br&gt;
nor my praise to idols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, the former things have come to pass,&lt;br&gt;
and new things I now declare;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before they spring forth,&lt;br&gt;
I tell you of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Mary&lt;/strong&gt;	&amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Magnificat&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 1:46-55&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord,&lt;br&gt;
my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; *&lt;br&gt;
for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.&lt;br&gt;
From this day all generations will call me blessed: *&lt;br&gt;
the Almighty has done great things for me,&lt;br&gt;
and holy is his Name.&lt;br&gt;
He has mercy on those who fear him *&lt;br&gt;
in every generation.&lt;br&gt;
He has shown the strength of his arm, *&lt;br&gt;
he has scattered the proud in their conceit.&lt;br&gt;
He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, *&lt;br&gt;
and has lifted up the lowly.&lt;br&gt;
He has filled the hungry with good things, *&lt;br&gt;
and the rich he has sent away empty.&lt;br&gt;
He has come to the help of his servant Israel, *&lt;br&gt;
for he has remembered his promise of mercy,&lt;br&gt;
The promise he made to our fathers, *&lt;br&gt;
to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Hebrews 9:11&amp;ndash;15 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Hebrews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Christ came as a high priest of the good things that have come, then through the greater and perfect tent (not made with hands, that is, not of this creation), he entered once for all into the Holy Place, not with the blood of goats and calves, but with his own blood, thus obtaining eternal redemption. For if the blood of goats and bulls, with the sprinkling of the ashes of a heifer, sanctifies those who have been defiled so that their flesh is purified, how much more will the blood of Christ, who through the eternal Spirit offered himself without blemish to God, purify our conscience from dead works to worship the living God!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason he is the mediator of a new covenant, so that those who are called may receive the promised eternal inheritance, because a death has occurred that redeems them from the transgressions under the first covenant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The People stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Song of Simeon&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Nunc Dimittis&lt;/em&gt;  &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Luke 2:29-32&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, you now have set your servant free *&lt;br&gt;
to go in peace as you have promised;&lt;br&gt;
For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, *&lt;br&gt;
whom you have prepared for all the world to see:&lt;br&gt;
A Light to enlighten the nations, *&lt;br&gt;
and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br&gt;
Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Third Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash;  &lt;em&gt;John 12:1&amp;ndash;11 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from John’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six days before the Passover Jesus came to Bethany, the home of Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. There they gave a dinner for him. Martha served, and Lazarus was one of those at the table with him. Mary took a pound of costly perfume made of pure nard, anointed Jesus&#39; feet, and wiped them with her hair. The house was filled with the fragrance of the perfume. But Judas Iscariot, one of his disciples (the one who was about to betray him), said, &amp;ldquo;Why was this perfume not sold for three hundred denarii and the money given to the poor?&amp;rdquo; (He said this not because he cared about the poor, but because he was a thief; he kept the common purse and used to steal what was put into it.) Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;Leave her alone. She bought it so that she might keep it for the day of my burial. You always have the poor with you, but you do not always have me.&amp;rdquo; When the great crowd of the Jews learned that he was there, they came not only because of Jesus but also to see Lazarus, whom he had raised from the dead. So the chief priests planned to put Lazarus to death as well, since it was on account of him that many of the Jews were deserting and were believing in Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-apostles-creed&#34;&gt;The Apostles&#39; Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-together-all-standing&#34;&gt;Officiant and People together, all standing&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe in God, &lt;strong&gt;the Father almighty,&lt;br&gt;
creator of heaven and earth.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son, our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
and born of the Virgin Mary.&lt;br&gt;
He suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br&gt;
was crucified, died, and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
He descended to the dead.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again.&lt;br&gt;
He ascended into heaven,&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br&gt;
I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
the holy catholic Church,&lt;br&gt;
the communion of saints,&lt;br&gt;
the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br&gt;
the resurrection of the body,&lt;br&gt;
and the life everlasting.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-prayers&#34;&gt;The Prayers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-or-kneel&#34;&gt;The people stand or kneel&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be your Name,&lt;br&gt;
your kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
your will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us today our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
Forgive us our sins&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those&lt;br&gt;
who sin against us.&lt;br&gt;
Save us from the time of trial,&lt;br&gt;
and deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For the kingdom, the power,&lt;br&gt;
and the glory are yours,&lt;br&gt;
now and for ever.  Amen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suffrages&#34;&gt;Suffrages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That this evening may be holy, good, and peaceful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That your holy angels may lead us in paths of peace and goodwill,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be pardoned and forgiven for our sins and offenses,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That there may be peace to your Church and to the whole world,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may depart this life in your faith and fear, and not be condemned before the great judgment seat of Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That we may be bound together by your Holy Spirit in the communion of the Blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Thomas,&lt;/em&gt; and all your saints, entrusting one another and all our life to Christ,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We entreat you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;collects-may-be-said-by-the-officiant-or-by-the-people-together-or-they-may-be-said-in-turn&#34;&gt;Collects may be said by the Officiant or by the people together, or they may be said in turn.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified: Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through Jesus Christ your Son our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Collect for the Presence of Christ&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord Jesus, stay with us, for evening is at hand and the day is past; be our companion in the way, kindle our hearts, and awaken hope, that we may know you as you are revealed in Scripture and the breaking of bread.  Grant this for the sake of your love.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Prayer for Mission&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep watch, dear Lord, with those who work, or watch, or weep this night, and give your angels charge over those who sleep.  Tend the sick, Lord Christ; give rest to the weary, bless the dying, soothe the suffering, pity the afflicted, shield the joyous; and all for your love&amp;rsquo;s sake.  &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;here-may-be-sung-a-hymn-or-anthem&#34;&gt;Here may be sung a hymn or anthem.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;intercessions-and-thanksgivings-may-follow&#34;&gt;Intercessions and thanksgivings may follow.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The General Thanksgiving&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, Father of all mercies,&lt;br&gt;
we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks&lt;br&gt;
for all your goodness and loving-kindness&lt;br&gt;
to us and to all whom you have made.&lt;br&gt;
We bless you for our creation, preservation,&lt;br&gt;
and all the blessings of this life;&lt;br&gt;
but above all for your immeasurable love&lt;br&gt;
in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory.&lt;br&gt;
And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies,&lt;br&gt;
that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise,&lt;br&gt;
not only with our lips, but in our lives,&lt;br&gt;
by giving up our selves to your service,&lt;br&gt;
and by walking before you&lt;br&gt;
in holiness and righteousness all our days;&lt;br&gt;
through Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory throughout all ages.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-officiant-then-concludes-with-the-following-sentence-of-scripture&#34;&gt;The Officiant then concludes with the following sentence of scripture:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, and the love of God, and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit, be with us all evermore. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(2 Corinthians 13:14)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sunday of the Passion --- Palm Sunday</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/palmsunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 16:59:14 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/seasons20212022/holyweek2020/palmsunday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;according to the Book of Common Prayer (p. 270)&lt;br&gt;
5 April 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lectionarypage.net/YearA_RCL/HolyWk/APalmSun_RCL.html&#34;&gt;Click here to see just the lessons for this liturgy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparing-for-the-liturgy&#34;&gt;Preparing for the Liturgy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Palms or other greens may be gathered to carry in procession. Choose a Celebrant and a reader. Light a candle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-liturgy-of-the-palms&#34;&gt;The Liturgy of the Palms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand&#34;&gt;The People stand.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed is the King who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peace in heaven and glory in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;br&gt;
Assist us mercifully with your help, O Lord God of our salvation, that we may enter with joy upon the contemplation of those mighty acts, whereby you have given us life and immortality; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from Matthew’s Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they had come near Jerusalem and had reached Bethphage, at the Mount of Olives, Jesus sent two disciples, saying to them, ‘Go into the village ahead of you, and immediately you will find a donkey tied, and a colt with her; untie them and bring them to me. If anyone says anything to you, just say this, “The Lord needs them.” And he will send them immediately.’ This took place to fulfil what had been spoken through the prophet, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell the daughter of Zion,&lt;br&gt;
Look, your king is coming to you,&lt;br&gt;
humble, and mounted on a donkey,&lt;br&gt;
and on a colt, the foal of a donkey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disciples went and did as Jesus had directed them; they brought the donkey and the colt, and put their cloaks on them, and he sat on them. A very large crowd spread their cloaks on the road, and others cut branches from the trees and spread them on the road. The crowds that went ahead of him and that followed were shouting,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hosanna to the Son of David!&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is the one who comes in the name of the Lord!&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest heaven!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he entered Jerusalem, the whole city was in turmoil, asking, ‘Who is this?’ The crowds were saying, ‘This is the prophet Jesus from Nazareth in Galilee.’ &lt;em&gt;(Matthew 21.1–11 NRSV)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing-of-the-palms&#34;&gt;The Blessing of the Palms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give him thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right to praise you, Almighty God, for the acts of love by which you have redeemed us through your Son Jesus Christ our Lord. On this day he entered the holy city of Jerusalem in triumph, and was proclaimed as King of kings by those who spread their garments and branches of palm along his way. Let these branches be for us signs of his victory, and grant that we who bear them in his name may ever hail him as our King, and follow him in the way that leads to eternal life; who lives and reigns in glory with you and the Holy Spirit, now and for ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-procession&#34;&gt;The Procession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us go forth in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the name of Christ. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hymn 154: All glory, laud, and honor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;hear-this-hymn-playedhttpswwwyoutubecomwatchvh3a8fttrade&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3a8fTTrAdE&#34;&gt;Hear this hymn played&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;while-singing-take-your-palms-and-if-possible-process-out-and-around-your-residence-if-it-is-better-to-stay-inside-process-around-your-living-spaces-bringing-jesus-into-every-space-upon-reaching-the-point-furthest-from-the-worship-space-stop-and-pray-the-following-collect&#34;&gt;While singing, take your palms and, if possible, process out and around your residence. If it is better to stay inside, process around your living spaces, bringing Jesus into every space. Upon reaching the point furthest from the worship space, stop and pray the following Collect:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified: Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;on-the-return-of-the-procession-we-say-aloud&#34;&gt;On the return of the procession, we say aloud:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 118:1-2, 19-29&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Confitemini Domino&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1 Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; *&lt;br&gt;
his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 Let Israel now proclaim, *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;His mercy endures for ever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;19 Open for me the gates of righteousness; *&lt;br&gt;
I will enter them; I will offer thanks to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 &amp;ldquo;This is the gate of the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
he who is righteous may enter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;21 I will give thanks to you, for you answered me *&lt;br&gt;
and have become my salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 The same stone which the builders rejected *&lt;br&gt;
has become the chief cornerstone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;23 This is the Lord&amp;rsquo;s doing, *&lt;br&gt;
and it is marvelous in our eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;24 On this day the Lord has acted; *&lt;br&gt;
we will rejoice and be glad in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25 Hosannah, Lord, hosannah! *&lt;br&gt;
Lord, send us now success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;26 Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord; *&lt;br&gt;
we bless you from the house of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;27 God is the Lord; he has shined upon us; *&lt;br&gt;
form a procession with branches up to the horns of the altar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;28 &amp;ldquo;You are my God, and I will thank you; *&lt;br&gt;
you are my God, and I will exalt you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;29 Give thanks to the Lord, for he is good; *&lt;br&gt;
his mercy endures for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Antiphon: 	Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-find-their-seats-and-remain-standing&#34;&gt;The people find their seats and remain standing.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-liturgy-of-the-word&#34;&gt;The Liturgy of the Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-1&#34;&gt;The People stand.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;salutation&#34;&gt;Salutation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-proper-to-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect Proper to the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty and everliving God, in your tender love for the human race you sent your Son our Savior Jesus Christ to take upon him our nature, and to suffer death upon the cross, giving us the example of his great humility: Mercifully grant that we may walk in the way of his suffering, and also share in his resurrection; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The People are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God’s Word&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The First Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 50:4–9 NRSV&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Reading from the book of Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord God has given me&lt;br&gt;
the tongue of a teacher,&lt;br&gt;
that I may know how to sustain&lt;br&gt;
the weary with a word.&lt;br&gt;
Morning by morning he wakens—&lt;br&gt;
wakens my ear&lt;br&gt;
to listen as those who are taught.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord God has opened my ear,&lt;br&gt;
and I was not rebellious,&lt;br&gt;
I did not turn backwards.&lt;br&gt;
I gave my back to those who struck me,&lt;br&gt;
and my cheeks to those who pulled out the beard;&lt;br&gt;
I did not hide my face&lt;br&gt;
from insult and spitting.&lt;br&gt;
The Lord God helps me;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have not been disgraced;&lt;br&gt;
therefore I have set my face like flint,&lt;br&gt;
and I know that I shall not be put to shame;&lt;br&gt;
he who vindicates me is near.&lt;br&gt;
Who will contend with me?&lt;br&gt;
Let us stand up together.&lt;br&gt;
Who are my adversaries?&lt;br&gt;
Let them confront me.&lt;br&gt;
It is the Lord God who helps me;&lt;br&gt;
who will declare me guilty?&lt;br&gt;
All of them will wear out like a garment;&lt;br&gt;
the moth will eat them up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psalm 31.9–16&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;In te, Domine, speravi&lt;/em&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;(BCP 623)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9 Have mercy on me, O Lord, for I am in trouble; *&lt;br&gt;
my eye is consumed with sorrow,&lt;br&gt;
and also my throat and my belly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 For my life is wasted with grief, and my years with sighing; *&lt;br&gt;
my strength fails me because of affliction,&lt;br&gt;
and my bones are consumed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11 I have become a reproach to all my enemies&lt;br&gt;
and even to my neighbors,&lt;br&gt;
a dismay to those of my acquaintance; *&lt;br&gt;
when they see me in the street they avoid me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 I am forgotten like a dead man, out of mind; *&lt;br&gt;
I am as useless as a broken pot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 For I have heard the whispering of the crowd; fear is all around; *&lt;br&gt;
they put their heads together against me;&lt;br&gt;
they plot to take my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14 But as for me, I have trusted in you, O Lord. *&lt;br&gt;
I have said, &amp;ldquo;You are my God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;15 My times are in your hand; *&lt;br&gt;
rescue me from the hand of my enemies,&lt;br&gt;
and from those who persecute me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16 Make your face to shine upon your servant, *&lt;br&gt;
and in your loving-kindness save me.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Second Lesson&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;mdash; &lt;em&gt;Philippians 2:5–11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the letter to the Philippians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the same mind be in you that was in Christ Jesus,&lt;br&gt;
who, though he was in the form of God,&lt;br&gt;
did not regard equality with God&lt;br&gt;
as something to be exploited,&lt;br&gt;
but emptied himself,&lt;br&gt;
taking the form of a slave,&lt;br&gt;
being born in human likeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And being found in human form,&lt;br&gt;
he humbled himself&lt;br&gt;
and became obedient to the point of death—&lt;br&gt;
even death on a cross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore God also highly exalted him&lt;br&gt;
and gave him the name&lt;br&gt;
that is above every name,&lt;br&gt;
so that at the name of Jesus&lt;br&gt;
every knee should bend,&lt;br&gt;
in heaven and on earth and under the earth,&lt;br&gt;
and every tongue should confess&lt;br&gt;
that Jesus Christ is Lord,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of God the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-passion&#34;&gt;The Passion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;separate-passion-reading-booklets-are-provided-herehttpsisgdpassionmatthew-the-congregation-may-be-seated-for-the-first-part-of-the-passion-at-the-verse-which-mentions-the-arrival-at-golgotha-all-stand&#34;&gt;Separate Passion reading booklets are provided &lt;a href=&#34;https://is.gd/PassionMatthew&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The congregation may be seated for the first part of the Passion. &lt;strong&gt;At the verse which mentions the arrival at Golgotha all stand.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Passion of our Lord according to MATTHEW&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;Matthew 26:14–27:66 (RCL Year A)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dramatis personæ: 	People, Judas, Narrator, Jesus, Peter, High Priest, Witness/Servant/Pilate’s Wife, Pilate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The Passion of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	One of the twelve, who was called Judas Iscariot, went to the chief priests and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	What will you give me if I betray him to you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	They paid him thirty pieces of silver. And from that moment he began to look for an opportunity to betray him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first day of Unleavened Bread the disciples came to Jesus, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt; 	Where do you want us to make the preparations for you to eat the Passover?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Go into the city to a certain man, and say to him, “The Teacher says, My time is near; I will keep the Passover at your house with my disciples.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So the disciples did as Jesus had directed them, and they prepared the Passover meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was evening, he took his place with the twelve; and while they were eating, he said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly I tell you, one of you will betray me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And they became greatly distressed and began to say to him one after another,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt; 	Surely not I, Lord?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	The one who has dipped his hand into the bowl with me will betray me. The Son of Man goes as it is written of him, but woe to that one by whom the Son of Man is betrayed! It would have been better for that one not to have been born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Judas, who betrayed him, said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	Surely not I, Rabbi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You have said so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	While they were eating, Jesus took a loaf of bread, and after blessing it he broke it, gave it to the disciples, and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Take, eat; this is my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he took a cup, and after giving thanks he gave it to them, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Drink from it, all of you; for this is my blood of the covenant, which is poured out for many for the forgiveness of sins. I tell you, I will never again drink of this fruit of the vine until that day when I drink it new with you in my Father’s kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When they had sung the hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives. Then Jesus said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You will all become deserters because of me this night; for it is written,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘I will strike the shepherd,&lt;br&gt;
the sheep of the flock will be&lt;br&gt;
scattered.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after I am raised up, I will go ahead of you to Galilee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Peter said to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	Though all become deserters because of you, I will never desert you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly I tell you, this very night, before the cock crows, you will deny me three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	Even though I must die with you, I will not deny you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And so said all the disciples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Jesus went with them to a place called Gethsemane; and he said to his disciples,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Sit here while I go over there and pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	He took with him Peter and the two sons of Zebedee, and began to be grieved and agitated. Then he said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	I am deeply grieved, even to death; remain here, and stay awake with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And going a little farther, he threw himself on the ground and prayed,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	My Father, if it is possible, let this cup pass from me; yet not what I want but what you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he came to the disciples and found them sleeping; and he said to Peter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	So, could you not stay awake with me one hour? Stay awake and pray that you may not come into the time of trial; the spirit indeed is willing, but the flesh is weak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he went away for the second time and prayed,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	My Father, if this cannot pass unless I drink it, your will be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he came and found them sleeping, for their eyes were heavy. So leaving them again, he went away and prayed for the third time, saying the same words. Then he came to the disciples and said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Are you still sleeping and taking your rest? See, the hour is at hand, and the Son of Man is betrayed into the hands of sinners. Get up, let us be going. See, my betrayer is at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	While he was still speaking, Judas, one of the twelve, arrived; with him was a large crowd with swords and clubs, from the chief priests and the elders of the people. Now the betrayer had given them a sign, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	The one I will kiss is the man; arrest him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At once he came up to Jesus and kissed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	Greetings, Rabbi!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Friend, do what you are here to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then they came and laid hands on Jesus and arrested him. Suddenly, one of those with Jesus put his hand on his sword, drew it, and struck the slave of the high priest, cutting off his ear. Then Jesus said to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Put your sword back into its place; for all who take the sword will perish by the sword. Do you think that I cannot appeal to my Father, and he will at once send me more than twelve legions of angels? But how then would the scriptures be fulfilled, which say it must happen in this way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At that hour Jesus said to the crowds,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Have you come out with swords and clubs to arrest me as though I were a bandit? Day after day I sat in the temple teaching, and you did not arrest me. But all this has taken place, so that the scriptures of the prophets may be fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then all the disciples deserted him and fled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who had arrested Jesus took him to Caiaphas the high priest, in whose house the scribes and the elders had gathered. But Peter was following him at a distance, as far as the courtyard of the high priest; and going inside, he sat with the guards in order to see how this would end. Now the chief priests and the whole council were looking for false testimony against Jesus so that they might put him to death, but they found none, though many false witnesses came forward. At last two came forward and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Witness:&lt;/em&gt;	This fellow said, “I am able to destroy the temple of God and to build it in three days.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The high priest stood up and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	Have you no answer? What is it that they testify against you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But Jesus was silent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	I put you under oath before the living God, tell us if you are the Messiah, the Son of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You have said so. But I tell you,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on you will see the Son of Man&lt;br&gt;
seated at the right hand of Power&lt;br&gt;
and coming on the clouds of heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the high priest tore his clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	He has blasphemed! Why do we still need witnesses? You have now heard his blasphemy. What is your verdict?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	He deserves death.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then they spat in his face and struck him; and some slapped him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Prophesy to us, you Messiah! Who is it that struck you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Now Peter was sitting outside in the courtyard. A servant-girl came to him and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servant:&lt;/em&gt;	You also were with Jesus the Galilean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But he denied it before all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know what you are talking about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When he went out to the porch, another servant-girl saw him, and she said to the bystanders,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Servant:&lt;/em&gt;	This man was with Jesus of Nazareth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Again he denied it with an oath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know the man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	After a little while the bystanders came up and said to Peter,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Certainly you are also one of them, for your accent betrays you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then he began to curse, and he swore an oath,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Peter:&lt;/em&gt;	I do not know the man!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At that moment the cock crowed. Then Peter remembered what Jesus had said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Before the cock crows, you will deny me three times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And he went out and wept bitterly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	When morning came, all the chief priests and the elders of the people conferred together against Jesus in order to bring about his death. They bound him, led him away, and handed him over to Pilate the governor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Judas, his betrayer, saw that Jesus was condemned, he repented and brought back the thirty pieces of silver to the chief priests and the elders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judas:&lt;/em&gt;	I have sinned by betraying innocent blood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	What is that to us? See to it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Throwing down the pieces of silver in the temple, he departed; and he went and hanged himself. But the chief priests, taking the pieces of silver, said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	It is not lawful to put them into the treasury, since they are blood money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	After conferring together, they used them to buy the potter’s field as a place to bury foreigners. For this reason that field has been called the Field of Blood to this day. Then was fulfilled what had been spoken through the prophet Jeremiah, “And they took the thirty pieces of silver, the price of the one on whom a price had been set, on whom some of the people of Israel had set a price, and they gave them for the potter’s field, as the Lord commanded me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Jesus stood before the governor; and the governor asked him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Are you the King of the Jews?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	You say so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But when he was accused by the chief priests and elders, he did not answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Do you not hear how many accusations they make against you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	But he gave him no answer, not even to a single charge, so that the governor was greatly amazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now at the festival the governor was accustomed to release a prisoner for the crowd, anyone whom they wanted. At that time they had a notorious prisoner, called Jesus Barabbas. So after they had gathered, Pilate said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Whom do you want me to release for you, Jesus Barabbas or Jesus who is called the Messiah?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	For he realized that it was out of jealousy that they had handed him over. While he was sitting on the judgment seat, his wife sent word to him,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wife:&lt;/em&gt;	Have nothing to do with that innocent man, for today I have suffered a great deal because of a dream about him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Now the chief priests and the elders persuaded the crowds to ask for Barabbas and to have Jesus killed. The governor again said to them,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Which of the two do you want me to release for you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Barabbas.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt; 	Then what should I do with Jesus who is called the Messiah?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Let him be crucified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	Why, what evil has he done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	(shouting) Let him be crucified!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So when Pilate saw that he could do nothing, but rather that a riot was beginning, he took some water and washed his hands before the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	I am innocent of this man’s blood; see to it yourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the people as a whole answered,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	His blood be on us and on our children!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So he released Barabbas for them; and after flogging Jesus, he handed him over to be crucified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then the soldiers of the governor took Jesus into the governor’s headquarters, and they gathered the whole cohort around him. They stripped him and put a scarlet robe on him, and after twisting some thorns into a crown, they put it on his head. They put a reed in his right hand and knelt before him and mocked him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Hail, King of the Jews!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	They spat on him, and took the reed and struck him on the head. After mocking him, they stripped him of the robe and put his own clothes on him. Then they led him away to crucify him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they went out, they came upon a man from Cyrene named Simon; they compelled this man to carry his cross. And when they came to a place called Golgotha (which means Place of a Skull), they offered him wine to drink, mixed with gall; but when he tasted it, he would not drink it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SILENCE		   (The Congregation stands at this time.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	And when they had crucified him, they divided his clothes among themselves by casting lots; then they sat down there and kept watch over him. Over his head they put the charge against him, which read, “This is Jesus, the King of the Jews.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then two bandits were crucified with him, one on his right and one on his left. Those who passed by derided him, shaking their heads and saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	You who would destroy the temple and build it in three days, save yourself! If you are the Son of God, come down from the cross.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	In the same way the chief priests also, along with the scribes and elders, were mocking him, saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	He saved others; he cannot save himself. He is the King of Israel; let him come down from the cross now, and we will believe in him. He trusts in God; let God deliver him now, if he wants to; for he said, “I am God’s Son.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The bandits who were crucified with him also taunted him in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	From noon on, darkness came over the whole land until three in the afternoon. And about three o’clock Jesus cried with a loud voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jesus:&lt;/em&gt;	Eli, Eli, lema sabachthani?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	That is, “My God, my God, why have you forsaken me?” When some of the bystanders heard it, they said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	This man is calling for Elijah.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	At once one of them ran and got a sponge, filled it with sour wine, put it on a stick, and gave it to him to drink. But the others said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Wait, let us see whether Elijah will come to save him.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Then Jesus cried again with a loud voice and breathed his last. At that moment the curtain of the temple was torn in two, from top to bottom. The earth shook, and the rocks were split. The tombs also were opened, and many bodies of the saints who had fallen asleep were raised. After his resurrection they came out of the tombs and entered the holy city and appeared to many. Now when the centurion and those with him, who were keeping watch over Jesus, saw the earthquake and what took place, they were terrified and said,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People:&lt;/em&gt;	Truly this man was God’s Son!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	Many women were also there, looking on from a distance; they had followed Jesus from Galilee and had provided for him. Among them were Mary Magdalene, and Mary the mother of James and Joseph, and the mother of the sons of Zebedee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it was evening, there came a rich man from Arimathea, named Joseph, who was also a disciple of Jesus. He went to Pilate and asked for the body of Jesus; then Pilate ordered it to be given to him. So Joseph took the body and wrapped it in a clean linen cloth and laid it in his own new tomb, which he had hewn in the rock. He then rolled a great stone to the door of the tomb and went away. Mary Magdalene and the other Mary were there, sitting opposite the tomb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	The next day, that is, after the day of Preparation, the chief priests and the Pharisees gathered before Pilate and said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;H. Priest:&lt;/em&gt;	Sir, we remember what that impostor said while he was still alive, “After three days I will rise again.” Therefore command the tomb to be made secure until the third day; otherwise his disciples may go and steal him away, and tell the people, “He has been raised from the dead,” and the last deception would be worse than the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pilate:&lt;/em&gt;	You have a guard of soldiers; go, make it as secure as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Narrator:&lt;/em&gt;	So they went with the guard and made the tomb secure by sealing the stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There follows a great silence. Please remain standing if you are able.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;text-adapted-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Text adapted from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-prayers-of-the-people&#34;&gt;The Prayers of the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we journey this week with Christ and celebrate the paschal mystery of his death and resurrection, let us earnestly pray to God for those following the way of the cross and for all peoples everywhere, saying: Lord have mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the holy catholic church throughout the world, sharing the death and resurrection of Christ, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Justin, Archbishop of Canterbury, for Michael, Presiding Bishop of the Episcopal Church, for &lt;em&gt;William&lt;/em&gt; our bishop, for all bishops, presbyters and deacons and all who minister in Christ, and for all the holy people of God, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all catechumens and their sponsors, for all seeking baptism, confirmation, or reaffirmation, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all nations, peoples, tribes, clans, and families, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all nations and their leaders, including Donald, our President; members of the U.S. Congress, &lt;em&gt;Phil,&lt;/em&gt; our Governor, and &lt;em&gt;John, our Mayor&lt;/em&gt;; for justice, mercy, and peace in all the world, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who are tempted, oppressed, afflicted, or in need, especially&amp;hellip; let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all those who have suffered and have been affected by the Covid-19 Virus; for healing in mind, body, spirit and community;  for our governing bodies that they may respond with dignity and respect for all citizens, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the dying and the dead, remembering&amp;hellip; and for those who mourn, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our families, friends, and companions, and for all those we love, let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lord, have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remembering the blessed Virgin Mary, &lt;em&gt;blessed Thomas&lt;/em&gt;, and all the saints, let us offer ourselves and one another to the living God through Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To you, O Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed are you, Lord our God, who sent your Son among us to bear the pain and grief of humankind. Receive the prayers we offer this day for all those in need in every place and as we near the holy mountain grant us strength on our journey; through Jesus Christ our Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officiant and People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-and-absolution&#34;&gt;Confession and Absolution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your&lt;br&gt;
Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on us,&lt;br&gt;
forgive us all our sins through our Lord Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
strengthen us in all goodness,&lt;br&gt;
and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep us in eternal life. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;prayer-over-the-people&#34;&gt;Prayer Over the People&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, we pray you graciously to behold this your family, for whom our Lord Jesus Christ was willing to be betrayed, and given into the hands of sinners, and to suffer death upon the cross; who lives and reigns for ever and ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dismissal&#34;&gt;Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officiant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us bless the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
