<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>weekday on Shared Prayers</title>
    <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/tags/weekday/</link>
    <description>Recent content in weekday on Shared Prayers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sharedprayers.net/tags/weekday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for Kamehameha and Emma of Hawaii, King and Queen, 1863 and 1885</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2023/lff2018-kamehameha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2023/lff2018-kamehameha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, who called your servants Kamehameha and Emma to an earthly throne that they might advance your heavenly kingdom, and gave them zeal for your church and love for your people: Mercifully grant that we also may be fruitful in good works, and attain to the glorious crown of your saints; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_acts-1722-31_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Acts 17:22-31&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the Acts of the Apostles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul stood in front of the Areopagus and said, “Athenians, I see how extremely religious you are in every way. For as I went through the city and looked carefully at the objects of your worship, I found among them an altar with the inscription, ‘To an unknown god.’ What therefore you worship as unknown, this I proclaim to you. The God who made the world and everything in it, he who is Lord of heaven and earth, does not live in shrines made by human hands, nor is he served by human hands, as though he needed anything, since he himself gives to all mortals life and breath and all things. From one ancestor he made all nations to inhabit the whole earth, and he allotted the times of their existence and the boundaries of the places where they would live, so that they would search for God and perhaps grope for him and find him—though indeed he is not far from each one of us. For ‘In him we live and move and have our being’; as even some of your own poets have said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘For we too are his offspring.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since we are God’s offspring, we ought not to think that the deity is like gold, or silver, or stone, an image formed by the art and imagination of mortals. While God has overlooked the times of human ignorance, now he commands all people everywhere to repent, because he has fixed a day on which he will have the world judged in righteousness by a man whom he has appointed, and of this he has given assurance to all by raising him from the dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-3312-22&#34;&gt;Psalm 33:12-22&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exultate, justi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;12 Happy is the nation whose God is the LORD! *&lt;br&gt;
happy the people he has chosen to be his own!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;13 The LORD looks down from heaven, *&lt;br&gt;
and beholds all the people in the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;14 From where he sits enthroned he turns his gaze *&lt;br&gt;
on all who dwell on the earth.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;15 He fashions all the hearts of them *&lt;br&gt;
and understands all their works.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;16 There is no king that can be saved by a mighty army; *&lt;br&gt;
a strong man is not delivered by his great strength.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;17 The horse is a vain hope for deliverance; *&lt;br&gt;
for all its strength it cannot save.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;18 Behold, the eye of the LORD is upon those who fear him, *&lt;br&gt;
on those who wait upon his love,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;19 To pluck their lives from death, *&lt;br&gt;
and to feed them in time of famine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 Our soul waits for the LORD; *&lt;br&gt;
he is our help and our shield.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;21 Indeed, our heart rejoices in him, *&lt;br&gt;
for in his holy Name we put our trust.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22 Let your loving-kindness, O LORD, be upon us, *&lt;br&gt;
as we have put our trust in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_matthew-2514-29_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Matthew 25:14-29&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘For it is as if a man, going on a journey, summoned his slaves and entrusted his property to them; to one he gave five talents, to another two, to another one, to each according to his ability. Then he went away. The one who had received the five talents went off at once and traded with them, and made five more talents. In the same way, the one who had the two talents made two more talents. But the one who had received the one talent went off and dug a hole in the ground and hid his master’s money. After a long time the master of those slaves came and settled accounts with them. Then the one who had received the five talents came forward, bringing five more talents, saying, “Master, you handed over to me five talents; see, I have made five more talents.” His master said to him, “Well done, good and trustworthy slave; you have been trustworthy in a few things, I will put you in charge of many things; enter into the joy of your master.” And the one with the two talents also came forward, saying, “Master, you handed over to me two talents; see, I have made two more talents.” His master said to him, “Well done, good and trustworthy slave; you have been trustworthy in a few things, I will put you in charge of many things; enter into the joy of your master.” Then the one who had received the one talent also came forward, saying, “Master, I knew that you were a harsh man, reaping where you did not sow, and gathering where you did not scatter seed; so I was afraid, and I went and hid your talent in the ground. Here you have what is yours.” But his master replied, “You wicked and lazy slave! You knew, did you, that I reap where I did not sow, and gather where I did not scatter? Then you ought to have invested my money with the bankers, and on my return I would have received what was my own with interest. So take the talent from him, and give it to the one with the ten talents. For to all those who have, more will be given, and they will have an abundance; but from those who have nothing, even what they have will be taken away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for [Catherine of Alexandria, Barbara of Nicomedia, and Margaret of Antioch], Martyrs, c.305</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-catherine-of-alexandria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-catherine-of-alexandria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embolden your church, O God, with the stories of your saints Catherine, Barbara, and Margaret, that we might face all trials and adversities with a fearless mind and an unbroken spirit, knowing that we are more than conquerors through Jesus Christ who strengthens us. Through the same Jesus Christ our Lord,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_judith-1216-1310_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Judith 12:16-13:10&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Judith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Judith came in and lay down. Holofernes’ heart was ravished with her and his passion was aroused, for he had been waiting for an opportunity to seduce her from the day he first saw her. So Holofernes said to her, ‘Have a drink and be merry with us!’ Judith said, ‘I will gladly drink, my lord, because today is the greatest day in my whole life.’ Then she took what her maid had prepared and ate and drank before him. Holofernes was greatly pleased with her, and drank a great quantity of wine, much more than he had ever drunk in any one day since he was born.&lt;br&gt;
When evening came, his slaves quickly withdrew. Bagoas closed the tent from outside and shut out the attendants from his master’s presence. They went to bed, for they all were weary because the banquet had lasted so long. But Judith was left alone in the tent, with Holofernes stretched out on his bed, for he was dead drunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Judith had told her maid to stand outside the bedchamber and to wait for her to come out, as she did on the other days; for she said she would be going out for her prayers. She had said the same thing to Bagoas. So everyone went out, and no one, either small or great, was left in the bedchamber. Then Judith, standing beside his bed, said in her heart, ‘O Lord God of all might, look in this hour on the work of my hands for the exaltation of Jerusalem. Now indeed is the time to help your heritage and to carry out my design to destroy the enemies who have risen up against us.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She went up to the bedpost near Holofernes’ head, and took down his sword that hung there. She came close to his bed, took hold of the hair of his head, and said, ‘Give me strength today, O Lord God of Israel!’ Then she struck his neck twice with all her might, and cut off his head. Next she rolled his body off the bed and pulled down the canopy from the posts. Soon afterwards she went out and gave Holofernes’ head to her maid, who placed it in her food bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the two of them went out together, as they were accustomed to do for prayer. They passed through the camp, circled around the valley, and went up the mountain to Bethulia, and came to its gates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-11997-104&#34;&gt;Psalm 119:97-104&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quomodo dilexi!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;97 Oh, how I love your law! *&lt;br&gt;
all the day long it is in my mind.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;98 Your commandment has made me wiser than my enemies, *&lt;br&gt;
and it is always with me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;99 I have more understanding than all my teachers, *&lt;br&gt;
for your decrees are my study.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;100 I am wiser than the elders, *&lt;br&gt;
because I observe your commandments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;101 I restrain my feet from every evil way, *&lt;br&gt;
that I may keep your word.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;102 I do not shrink from your judgments, *&lt;br&gt;
because you yourself have taught me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;103 How sweet are your words to my taste! *&lt;br&gt;
they are sweeter than honey to my mouth.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;104 Through your commandments I gain understanding; *&lt;br&gt;
therefore I hate every lying way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_mark-942-50_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Mark 9:42-50&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘If any of you put a stumbling-block before one of these little ones who believe in me, it would be better for you if a great millstone were hung around your neck and you were thrown into the sea. If your hand causes you to stumble, cut it off; it is better for you to enter life maimed than to have two hands and to go to hell, to the unquenchable fire. And if your foot causes you to stumble, cut it off; it is better for you to enter life lame than to have two feet and to be thrown into hell., And if your eye causes you to stumble, tear it out; it is better for you to enter the kingdom of God with one eye than to have two eyes and to be thrown into hell, where their worm never dies, and the fire is never quenched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘For everyone will be salted with fire. Salt is good; but if salt has lost its saltiness, how can you season it? Have salt in yourselves, and be at peace with one another.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for Thanksgiving Day</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/thanksgiving-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/thanksgiving-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;entrance-hymn-_come-ye-thankful-people-come_-hymnal-290&#34;&gt;Entrance Hymn: &lt;em&gt;Come, ye thankful people come&lt;/em&gt; (Hymnal 290)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty and gracious Father, we give you thanks for the fruits of the earth in their season and for the labors of those who harvest them. Make us, we pray, faithful stewards of your great bounty, for the provision of our necessities and the relief of all who are in need, to the glory of your Name; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_deuteronomy-261-11_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Deuteronomy 26:1-11&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the book of Deuteronomy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have come into the land that the LORD your God is giving you as an inheritance to possess, and you possess it, and settle in it, you shall take some of the first of all the fruit of the ground, which you harvest from the land that the LORD your God is giving you, and you shall put it in a basket and go to the place that the LORD your God will choose as a dwelling for his name. You shall go to the priest who is in office at that time, and say to him, &amp;ldquo;Today I declare to the LORD your God that I have come into the land that the LORD swore to our ancestors to give us.&amp;rdquo; When the priest takes the basket from your hand and sets it down before the altar of the LORD your God, you shall make this response before the LORD your God: &amp;ldquo;A wandering Aramean was my ancestor; he went down into Egypt and lived there as an alien, few in number, and there he became a great nation, mighty and populous. When the Egyptians treated us harshly and afflicted us, by imposing hard labor on us, we cried to the LORD, the God of our ancestors; the LORD heard our voice and saw our affliction, our toil, and our oppression. The LORD brought us out of Egypt with a mighty hand and an outstretched arm, with a terrifying display of power, and with signs and wonders; and he brought us into this place and gave us this land, a land flowing with milk and honey. So now I bring the first of the fruit of the ground that you, O LORD, have given me.&amp;rdquo; You shall set it down before the LORD your God and bow down before the LORD your God. Then you, together with the Levites and the aliens who reside among you, shall celebrate with all the bounty that the LORD your God has given to you and to your house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-100&#34;&gt;Psalm 100&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jubilate Deo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	Be joyful in the LORD, all you lands; *&lt;br&gt;
serve the LORD with gladness&lt;br&gt;
and come before his presence with a song.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2	Know this: The LORD himself is God; *&lt;br&gt;
he himself has made us, and we are his;&lt;br&gt;
we are his people and the sheep of his pasture.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	Enter his gates with thanksgiving;&lt;br&gt;
go into his courts with praise; *&lt;br&gt;
give thanks to him and call upon his Name.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4	For the LORD is good;&lt;br&gt;
his mercy is everlasting; *&lt;br&gt;
and his faithfulness endures from age to age.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-second-lesson-_philippians-44-9_&#34;&gt;The Second Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Philippians 4:4-9&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-2&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s epistle to the church in Phillipi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, Rejoice. Let your gentleness be known to everyone. The Lord is near. Do not worry about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, beloved, whatever is true, whatever is honorable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is pleasing, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence and if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things. Keep on doing the things that you have learned and received and heard and seen in me, and the God of peace will be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-3&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sequence-hymn-_we-plow-the-field-and-scatter_-hymnal-291&#34;&gt;Sequence Hymn: &lt;em&gt;We plow the field and scatter&lt;/em&gt; (Hymnal 291)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_john-625-35_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;John 6:25-35&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the crowd found Jesus on the other side of the sea, they said to him, &amp;ldquo;Rabbi, when did you come here?&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;Very truly, I tell you, you are looking for me, not because you saw signs, but because you ate your fill of the loaves. Do not work for the food that perishes, but for the food that endures for eternal life, which the Son of Man will give you. For it is on him that God the Father has set his seal.&amp;rdquo; Then they said to him, &amp;ldquo;What must we do to perform the works of God?&amp;rdquo; Jesus answered them, &amp;ldquo;This is the work of God, that you believe in him whom he has sent.&amp;rdquo; So they said to him, &amp;ldquo;What sign are you going to give us then, so that we may see it and believe you? What work are you performing? Our ancestors ate the manna in the wilderness; as it is written, &amp;lsquo;He gave them bread from heaven to eat.&#39;&amp;rdquo; Then Jesus said to them, &amp;ldquo;Very truly, I tell you, it was not Moses who gave you the bread from heaven, but it is my Father who gives you the true bread from heaven. For the bread of God is that which comes down from heaven and gives life to the world.&amp;rdquo; They said to him, &amp;ldquo;Sir, give us this bread always.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said to them, &amp;ldquo;I am the bread of life. Whoever comes to me will never be hungry, and whoever believes in me will never be thirsty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-358&#34;&gt;BCP 358&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-nicene-creed&#34;&gt;The Nicene Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;the Father, the Almighty,&lt;br&gt;
maker of heaven and earth,&lt;br&gt;
of all that is, seen and unseen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
the only Son of God,&lt;br&gt;
eternally begotten of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
God from God,&lt;br&gt;
Light from Light, true God from true God,&lt;br&gt;
begotten, not made,&lt;br&gt;
of one Being with the Father.&lt;br&gt;
Through him all things were made.&lt;br&gt;
For us and for our salvation&lt;br&gt;
he came down from heaven:&lt;br&gt;
by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,&lt;br&gt;
and was made man.&lt;br&gt;
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;&lt;br&gt;
he suffered death and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again&lt;br&gt;
in accordance with the Scriptures;&lt;br&gt;
he ascended into heaven&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and his kingdom will have no end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,&lt;br&gt;
who proceeds from the Father and the Son.&lt;br&gt;
With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.&lt;br&gt;
He has spoken through the Prophets.&lt;br&gt;
We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.&lt;br&gt;
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.&lt;br&gt;
We look for the resurrection of the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and the life of the world to come. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-3&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;offertory-hymn-_praise-to-god-immortal-praise_-hymnal-288&#34;&gt;Offertory Hymn: &lt;em&gt;Praise to God, immortal praise&lt;/em&gt; (Hymnal 288)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hymnal-s-154&#34;&gt;Hymnal S-154&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communion-hymn-_we-gather-together-to-ask-the-lord39s-blessing_-hymnal-433&#34;&gt;Communion Hymn: &lt;em&gt;We gather together to ask the Lord&#39;s blessing&lt;/em&gt; (Hymnal 433)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;processional-hymn-_now-thank-we-all-our-god_-hymnal-397&#34;&gt;Processional Hymn: &lt;em&gt;Now thank we all our God&lt;/em&gt; (Hymnal 397)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-24&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for Hilda of Whitby, Abbess, 680</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-hilda-of-whitby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-hilda-of-whitby/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God of peace, by whose grace the abbess Hilda was endowed with gifts of justice, prudence, and strength to rule as a wise mother over the nuns and monks of her household: Raise up these gifts in us, that we, following her example and prayers, may build up one another in love to the benefit of your church; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_ephesians-41-6_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Ephesians 4:1-6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s epistle to the church in Ephesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I therefore, the prisoner in the Lord, beg you to lead a life worthy of the calling to which you have been called, with all humility and gentleness, with patience, bearing with one another in love, making every effort to maintain the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace. There is one body and one Spirit, just as you were called to the one hope of your calling, one Lord, one faith, one baptism, one God and Father of all, who is above all and through all and in all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-122&#34;&gt;Psalm 122&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lœtatus sum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	I was glad when they said to me, *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Let us go to the house of the LORD.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2	Now our feet are standing *&lt;br&gt;
within your gates, O Jerusalem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	Jerusalem is built as a city *&lt;br&gt;
that is at unity with itself;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4	To which the tribes go up,&lt;br&gt;
the tribes of the LORD, *&lt;br&gt;
the assembly of Israel,&lt;br&gt;
to praise the Name of the LORD.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	For there are the thrones of judgment, *&lt;br&gt;
the thrones of the house of David.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;6	Pray for the peace of Jerusalem: *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;May they prosper who love you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	Peace be within your walls *&lt;br&gt;
and quietness within your towers.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;8	For my brethren and companions&amp;rsquo; sake, *&lt;br&gt;
I pray for your prosperity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	Because of the house of the LORD our God, *&lt;br&gt;
I will seek to do you good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_matthew-1927-29_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Matthew 19:27-29&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Peter said in reply, ‘Look, we have left everything and followed you. What then will we have?’ Jesus said to them, ‘Truly I tell you, at the renewal of all things, when the Son of Man is seated on the throne of his glory, you who have followed me will also sit on twelve thrones, judging the twelve tribes of Israel. And everyone who has left houses or brothers or sisters or father or mother or children or fields, for my name’s sake, will receive a hundredfold, and will inherit eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Church in the Woods / Holy Eucharist (Proper 28)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/churchinwoods20221110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/churchinwoods20221110/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holy God,&lt;br&gt;
Holy and Mighty,&lt;br&gt;
Holy Immortal One,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have mercy upon us.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed Lord, who caused all holy Scriptures to be written for our learning: Grant us so to hear them, read, mark, learn, and inwardly digest them, that we may embrace and ever hold fast the blessed hope of everlasting life, which you have given us in our Savior Jesus Christ; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_isaiah-6517-25_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 65:17-25&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am about to create new heavens and a new earth;&lt;br&gt;
the former things shall not be remembered or come to mind.&lt;br&gt;
But be glad and rejoice forever in what I am creating;&lt;br&gt;
for I am about to create Jerusalem as a joy, and its people as a delight.&lt;br&gt;
I will rejoice in Jerusalem, and delight in my people;&lt;br&gt;
no more shall the sound of weeping be heard in it, or the cry of distress.&lt;br&gt;
No more shall there be in it an infant that lives but a few days, or an old person who does not live out a lifetime;&lt;br&gt;
for one who dies at a hundred years will be considered a youth, and one who falls short of a hundred will be considered accursed.&lt;br&gt;
They shall build houses and inhabit them; they shall plant vineyards and eat their fruit.&lt;br&gt;
They shall not build and another inhabit; they shall not plant and another eat;&lt;br&gt;
for like the days of a tree shall the days of my people be, and my chosen shall long enjoy the work of their hands.&lt;br&gt;
They shall not labor in vain, or bear children for calamity;&lt;br&gt;
for they shall be offspring blessed by the Lord&amp;ndash; and their descendants as well.&lt;br&gt;
Before they call I will answer, while they are yet speaking I will hear.&lt;br&gt;
The wolf and the lamb shall feed together, the lion shall eat straw like the ox; but the serpent&amp;ndash; its food shall be dust!&lt;br&gt;
They shall not hurt or destroy on all my holy mountain, says the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-2&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;canticle-9&#34;&gt;Canticle 9&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surely, it is God who saves me; *&lt;br&gt;
I will trust in him and not be afraid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;For the Lord is my stronghold and my sure defense, *&lt;br&gt;
and he will be my Savior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Therefore you shall draw water with rejoicing *&lt;br&gt;
from the springs of salvation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;And on that day you shall say, *&lt;br&gt;
Give thanks to the Lord and call upon his Name;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Make his deeds known among the peoples; *&lt;br&gt;
see that they remember that his Name is exalted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sing the praises of the Lord, for he has done great things, *&lt;br&gt;
and this is known in all the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cry aloud, inhabitants of Zion, ring out your joy, *&lt;br&gt;
for the great one in the midst of you is the Holy One of Israel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-3&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_luke-215-19_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Luke 21:5-19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Luke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When some were speaking about the temple, how it was adorned with beautiful stones and gifts dedicated to God, Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;As for these things that you see, the days will come when not one stone will be left upon another; all will be thrown down.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked him, &amp;ldquo;Teacher, when will this be, and what will be the sign that this is about to take place?&amp;rdquo; And he said, &amp;ldquo;Beware that you are not led astray; for many will come in my name and say, &amp;lsquo;I am he!&amp;rsquo; and, &amp;lsquo;The time is near!&amp;rsquo; Do not go after them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you hear of wars and insurrections, do not be terrified; for these things must take place first, but the end will not follow immediately.&amp;rdquo; Then he said to them, &amp;ldquo;Nation will rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom; there will be great earthquakes, and in various places famines and plagues; and there will be dreadful portents and great signs from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But before all this occurs, they will arrest you and persecute you; they will hand you over to synagogues and prisons, and you will be brought before kings and governors because of my name. This will give you an opportunity to testify. So make up your minds not to prepare your defense in advance; for I will give you words and a wisdom that none of your opponents will be able to withstand or contradict. You will be betrayed even by parents and brothers, by relatives and friends; and they will put some of you to death. You will be hated by all because of my name. But not a hair of your head will perish. By your endurance you will gain your souls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-389&#34;&gt;BCP 389&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form V&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In peace, let us pray to the Lord, saying, “&lt;em&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the holy Church of God, that it may be filled with truth and love, and be found without fault at the day of your coming, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;People&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Michael our Presiding Bishop, for William our own Bishop, for all bishops and other ministers, and for all the holy people of God, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who fear God and believe in you, Lord Christ, that our divisions may cease, and that all may be one as you and the Father are one, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the mission of the Church, that in faithful witness it may preach the Gospel to the ends of the earth, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who do not yet believe, and for those who have lost their faith, that they may receive the light of the Gospel, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the peace of the world, that a spirit of respect and forbearance may grow among nations and peoples, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those in positions of public trust especially Joseph, our President, Phillip, our Governor, John, our Mayor, that they may serve justice, and promote the dignity and freedom of every person, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who live and work in this community, especially Ali, our President, and all the Deans, Faculty, Trustees, and Students of Rowan University, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a blessing upon all human labor, and for the right use of the riches of creation, that the world may be freed from poverty, famine, and disaster, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-9&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the poor, the persecuted, the sick, and all who suffer; for refugees, prisoners, and all who are in danger; that they may be relieved and protected, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-10&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For we who are present, and for&lt;br&gt;
those who are absent from among us today, that we may be delivered from hardness of heart, and show forth your glory in all that we do, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-11&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our enemies and those who wish us harm; and for all whom we have injured or offended, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-12&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ourselves; for the forgiveness of our sins, and for the grace of the Holy Spirit to amend our lives, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-13&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who have commended themselves to our prayers; for our families, friends, and neighbors; that being freed from anxiety, they may live in joy, peace, and health, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-14&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For ___________ , we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-15&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all who have died in the communion of your Church, and those whose faith is known to you alone, that, with all the saints, they may have rest in that place where there is no pain or grief, but life eternal, we pray to you, O Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyrie eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-16&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rejoicing in the fellowship of the ever-blessed Virgin Mary, Thomas and all the saints, let us commend ourselves, and one another, and all our life to Christ our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To you, O Lord our God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect-or-the-following-doxology&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect, or the following Doxology&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For yours is the majesty, O Father, Son, and Holy Spirit; yours is the kingdom and the power and the glory, now and for ever. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-24&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-25&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-26&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-27&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-28&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-4&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-29&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-5&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-30&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-31&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist at Cardinal Village (Proper 28)</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/cardinalvillage20221110/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/cardinalvillage20221110/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord have mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christ have mercy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lord have mercy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed Lord, who caused all holy Scriptures to be written for our learning: Grant us so to hear them, read, mark, learn, and inwardly digest them, that we may embrace and ever hold fast the blessed hope of everlasting life, which you have given us in our Savior Jesus Christ; who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, for ever and ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_isaiah-6517-25_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Isaiah 65:17-25&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the prophet Isaiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am about to create new heavens and a new earth;&lt;br&gt;
the former things shall not be remembered or come to mind.&lt;br&gt;
But be glad and rejoice forever in what I am creating;&lt;br&gt;
for I am about to create Jerusalem as a joy, and its people as a delight.&lt;br&gt;
I will rejoice in Jerusalem, and delight in my people;&lt;br&gt;
no more shall the sound of weeping be heard in it, or the cry of distress.&lt;br&gt;
No more shall there be in it an infant that lives but a few days, or an old person who does not live out a lifetime;&lt;br&gt;
for one who dies at a hundred years will be considered a youth, and one who falls short of a hundred will be considered accursed.&lt;br&gt;
They shall build houses and inhabit them; they shall plant vineyards and eat their fruit.&lt;br&gt;
They shall not build and another inhabit; they shall not plant and another eat;&lt;br&gt;
for like the days of a tree shall the days of my people be, and my chosen shall long enjoy the work of their hands.&lt;br&gt;
They shall not labor in vain, or bear children for calamity;&lt;br&gt;
for they shall be offspring blessed by the Lord&amp;ndash; and their descendants as well.&lt;br&gt;
Before they call I will answer, while they are yet speaking I will hear.&lt;br&gt;
The wolf and the lamb shall feed together, the lion shall eat straw like the ox; but the serpent&amp;ndash; its food shall be dust!&lt;br&gt;
They shall not hurt or destroy on all my holy mountain, says the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-2&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;canticle-9&#34;&gt;Canticle 9&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surely, it is God who saves me; *&lt;br&gt;
I will trust in him and not be afraid.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;For the Lord is my stronghold and my sure defense, *&lt;br&gt;
and he will be my Savior.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Therefore you shall draw water with rejoicing *&lt;br&gt;
from the springs of salvation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;And on that day you shall say, *&lt;br&gt;
Give thanks to the Lord and call upon his Name;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Make his deeds known among the peoples; *&lt;br&gt;
see that they remember that his Name is exalted.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sing the praises of the Lord, for he has done great things, *&lt;br&gt;
and this is known in all the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cry aloud, inhabitants of Zion, ring out your joy, *&lt;br&gt;
for the great one in the midst of you is the Holy One of Israel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: *&lt;br&gt;
as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-second-lesson-_2-thessalonians-36-13_&#34;&gt;The Second Lesson: &lt;em&gt;2 Thessalonians 3:6-13&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-2&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s second epistle to the Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we command you, beloved, in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, to keep away from believers who are living in idleness and not according to the tradition that they received from us. For you yourselves know how you ought to imitate us; we were not idle when we were with you, and we did not eat anyone&amp;rsquo;s bread without paying for it; but with toil and labor we worked night and day, so that we might not burden any of you. This was not because we do not have that right, but in order to give you an example to imitate. For even when we were with you, we gave you this command: Anyone unwilling to work should not eat. For we hear that some of you are living in idleness, mere busybodies, not doing any work. Now such persons we command and exhort in the Lord Jesus Christ to do their work quietly and to earn their own living. Brothers and sisters, do not be weary in doing what is right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-3&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_luke-215-19_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Luke 21:5-19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Luke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When some were speaking about the temple, how it was adorned with beautiful stones and gifts dedicated to God, Jesus said, &amp;ldquo;As for these things that you see, the days will come when not one stone will be left upon another; all will be thrown down.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They asked him, &amp;ldquo;Teacher, when will this be, and what will be the sign that this is about to take place?&amp;rdquo; And he said, &amp;ldquo;Beware that you are not led astray; for many will come in my name and say, &amp;lsquo;I am he!&amp;rsquo; and, &amp;lsquo;The time is near!&amp;rsquo; Do not go after them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you hear of wars and insurrections, do not be terrified; for these things must take place first, but the end will not follow immediately.&amp;rdquo; Then he said to them, &amp;ldquo;Nation will rise against nation, and kingdom against kingdom; there will be great earthquakes, and in various places famines and plagues; and there will be dreadful portents and great signs from heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But before all this occurs, they will arrest you and persecute you; they will hand you over to synagogues and prisons, and you will be brought before kings and governors because of my name. This will give you an opportunity to testify. So make up your minds not to prepare your defense in advance; for I will give you words and a wisdom that none of your opponents will be able to withstand or contradict. You will be betrayed even by parents and brothers, by relatives and friends; and they will put some of you to death. You will be hated by all because of my name. But not a hair of your head will perish. By your endurance you will gain your souls.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-358&#34;&gt;BCP 358&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-nicene-creed&#34;&gt;The Nicene Creed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe in one God,&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;the Father, the Almighty,&lt;br&gt;
maker of heaven and earth,&lt;br&gt;
of all that is, seen and unseen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in one Lord, Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
the only Son of God,&lt;br&gt;
eternally begotten of the Father,&lt;br&gt;
God from God,&lt;br&gt;
Light from Light, true God from true God,&lt;br&gt;
begotten, not made,&lt;br&gt;
of one Being with the Father.&lt;br&gt;
Through him all things were made.&lt;br&gt;
For us and for our salvation&lt;br&gt;
he came down from heaven:&lt;br&gt;
by the power of the Holy Spirit&lt;br&gt;
he became incarnate from the Virgin Mary,&lt;br&gt;
and was made man.&lt;br&gt;
For our sake he was crucified under Pontius Pilate;&lt;br&gt;
he suffered death and was buried.&lt;br&gt;
On the third day he rose again&lt;br&gt;
in accordance with the Scriptures;&lt;br&gt;
he ascended into heaven&lt;br&gt;
and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br&gt;
He will come again in glory to judge the living and the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and his kingdom will have no end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We believe in the Holy Spirit, the Lord, the giver of life,&lt;br&gt;
who proceeds from the Father and the Son.&lt;br&gt;
With the Father and the Son he is worshiped and glorified.&lt;br&gt;
He has spoken through the Prophets.&lt;br&gt;
We believe in one holy catholic and apostolic Church.&lt;br&gt;
We acknowledge one baptism for the forgiveness of sins.&lt;br&gt;
We look for the resurrection of the dead,&lt;br&gt;
and the life of the world to come. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-3&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-3&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-4&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-5&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-24&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for [Ammonius], Hermit, c.403</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-ammonius/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-ammonius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drive far from your church, O God, every vain spirit of clerical ambition, that, like your servant Ammonius, we may refuse to conflate ordination and leadership, and may never confuse rank with holiness; in the name of your son Jesus Christ our Lord, who alone is our great High Priest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_1-samuel-1020-27_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;1 Samuel 10:20-27&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from first Samuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Samuel brought all the tribes of Israel near, and the tribe of Benjamin was taken by lot. He brought the tribe of Benjamin near by its families, and the family of the Matrites was taken by lot. Finally he brought the family of the Matrites near man by man, and Saul the son of Kish was taken by lot. But when they sought him, he could not be found. So they inquired again of the Lord, ‘Did the man come here?’ and the Lord said, ‘See, he has hidden himself among the baggage.’ Then they ran and brought him from there. When he took his stand among the people, he was head and shoulders taller than any of them. Samuel said to all the people, ‘Do you see the one whom the Lord has chosen? There is no one like him among all the people.’ And all the people shouted, ‘Long live the king!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samuel told the people the rights and duties of the kingship; and he wrote them in a book and laid it up before the Lord. Then Samuel sent all the people back to their homes. Saul also went to his home at Gibeah, and with him went warriors whose hearts God had touched. But some worthless fellows said, ‘How can this man save us?’ They despised him and brought him no present. But he held his peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Nahash, king of the Ammonites, had been grievously oppressing the Gadites and the Reubenites. He would gouge out the right eye of each of them and would not grant Israel a deliverer. No one was left of the Israelites across the Jordan whose right eye Nahash, king of the Ammonites, had not gouged out. But there were seven thousand men who had escaped from the Ammonites and had entered Jabesh-gilead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-24&#34;&gt;Psalm 24&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Domini est terra&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	The earth is the LORD&amp;rsquo;S and all that is in it, *&lt;br&gt;
the world and all who dwell therein.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2	For it is he who founded it upon the seas *&lt;br&gt;
and made it firm upon the rivers of the deep.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	&amp;ldquo;Who can ascend the hill of the LORD? *&lt;br&gt;
and who can stand in his holy place?&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4	&amp;ldquo;Those who have clean hands and a pure heart, *&lt;br&gt;
who have not pledged themselves to falsehood,&lt;br&gt;
nor sworn by what is a fraud.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	They shall receive a blessing from the LORD *&lt;br&gt;
and a just reward from the God of their salvation.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;6	Such is the generation of those who seek him, *&lt;br&gt;
of those who seek your face, O God of Jacob.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	Lift up your heads, O gates;&lt;br&gt;
lift them high, O everlasting doors; *&lt;br&gt;
and the King of glory shall come in.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;8	&amp;ldquo;Who is this King of glory?&amp;rdquo; *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;The LORD, strong and mighty,&lt;br&gt;
the LORD, mighty in battle.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9	Lift up your heads, O gates;&lt;br&gt;
lift them high, O everlasting doors; *&lt;br&gt;
and the King of glory shall come in.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;10	&amp;ldquo;Who is he, this King of glory?&amp;rdquo; *&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;The LORD of hosts,&lt;br&gt;
he is the King of glory.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_matthew-231-12_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;Matthew 23:1-12&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to Matthew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesus said to the crowds and to his disciples, “The scribes and the Pharisees sit on Moses&amp;rsquo; seat; therefore, do whatever they teach you and follow it; but do not do as they do, for they do not practice what they teach. They tie up heavy burdens, hard to bear, and lay them on the shoulders of others; but they themselves are unwilling to lift a finger to move them. They do all their deeds to be seen by others; for they make their phylacteries broad and their fringes long. They love to have the place of honor at banquets and the best seats in the synagogues, and to be greeted with respect in the marketplaces, and to have people call them rabbi. But you are not to be called rabbi, for you have one teacher, and you are all students. And call no one your father on earth, for you have one Father&amp;ndash; the one in heaven. Nor are you to be called instructors, for you have one instructor, the Messiah. The greatest among you will be your servant. All who exalt themselves will be humbled, and all who humble themselves will be exalted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holy Eucharist for All Souls/All the Faithful Departed</title>
      <link>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-all-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.sharedprayers.net/archive/2022/lff2018-all-souls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-gather-in-gods-name&#34;&gt;We Gather in God&amp;rsquo;s Name&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-355&#34;&gt;BCP 355&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;greeting&#34;&gt;Greeting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blessed be God: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And blessed be God’s kingdom, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-for-purity&#34;&gt;The Collect for Purity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-1&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God, to you all hearts are open, all desires known, and from you no secrets are hid: Cleanse the thoughts of our hearts by the inspiration of your Holy Spirit, that we may perfectly love you, and worthily magnify your holy Name; through Christ our Lord. &lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-356&#34;&gt;BCP 356&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kyrie&#34;&gt;Kyrie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-2&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-1&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Christe, eleison.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-3&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kyrie, eleison.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;translated-lord-have-mercy-christ-have-mercy-lord-have-mercy&#34;&gt;(translated: Lord, have mercy. Christ, have mercy. Lord, have mercy.)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-collect-of-the-day&#34;&gt;The Collect of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-4&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-5&#34;&gt;Officiant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O God, the Maker and Redeemer of all believers: Grant to the faithful departed the unsearchable benefits of the passion of your Son; that on the day of his appearing they may be manifested as your children; through Jesus Christ our Lord, who lives and reigns with you and the Holy Spirit, one God, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-hear-gods-word&#34;&gt;We Hear God&amp;rsquo;s Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-first-lesson-_wisdom-31-9_&#34;&gt;The First Lesson: &lt;em&gt;Wisdom 3:1-9&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from the Wisdom of Solomon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The souls of the righteous are in the hand of God, 				and no torment will ever touch them. 				In the eyes of the foolish they seemed to have died, 				and their departure was thought to be a disaster, 				and their going from us to be their destruction; 				but they are at peace. 				For though in the sight of others they were punished, 				their hope is full of immortality. 				Having been disciplined a little, they will receive great good, 				because God tested them and found them worthy of himself; 				like gold in the furnace he tried them, 				and like a sacrificial burnt offering he accepted them. 				In the time of their visitation they will shine forth, 				and will run like sparks through the stubble. 				They will govern nations and rule over peoples, 				and the Lord will reign over them forever. 				Those who trust in him will understand truth, 				and the faithful will abide with him in love, 				because grace and mercy are upon his holy ones, 			and he watches over his elect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-1&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-4&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;psalm-130&#34;&gt;Psalm 130&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;De profundis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1	Out of the depths have I called to you, O LORD;&lt;br&gt;
LORD, hear my voice; *&lt;br&gt;
let your ears consider well the voice of my supplication.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;2	If you, LORD, were to note what is done amiss, *&lt;br&gt;
O LORD, who could stand?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3	For there is forgiveness with you; *&lt;br&gt;
therefore you shall be feared.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;4	I wait for the LORD; my soul waits for him; *&lt;br&gt;
in his word is my hope.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5	My soul waits for the LORD,&lt;br&gt;
more than watchmen for the morning, *&lt;br&gt;
more than watchmen for the morning.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;6	O Israel, wait for the LORD, *&lt;br&gt;
for with the LORD there is mercy;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7	With him there is plenteous redemption, *&lt;br&gt;
and he shall redeem Israel from all their sins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-second-lesson-_1-thessalonians-413-18_&#34;&gt;The Second Lesson: &lt;em&gt;1 Thessalonians 4:13-18&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-2&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reading from Paul’s first epistle to the Thessalonians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not want you to be uninformed, brothers and sisters, about those who have died, so that you may not grieve as others do who have no hope. For since we believe that Jesus died and rose again, even so, through Jesus, God will bring with him those who have died. For this we declare to you by the word of the Lord, that we who are alive, who are left until the coming of the Lord, will by no means precede those who have died. For the Lord himself, with a cry of command, with the archangel&amp;rsquo;s call and with the sound of God&amp;rsquo;s trumpet, will descend from heaven, and the dead in Christ will rise first. Then we who are alive, who are left, will be caught up in the clouds together with them to meet the Lord in the air; and so we will be with the Lord forever. Therefore encourage one another with these words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lector-3&#34;&gt;Lector:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-5&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-1&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-holy-gospel-_john-524-27_&#34;&gt;The Holy Gospel: &lt;em&gt;John 5:24-27&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Holy Gospel of our Lord Jesus Christ according to John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-6&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glory to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-1&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very truly, I tell you, anyone who hears my word and believes him who sent me has eternal life, and does not come under judgement, but has passed from death to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Very truly, I tell you, the hour is coming, and is now here, when the dead will hear the voice of the Son of God, and those who hear will live. For just as the Father has life in himself, so he has granted the Son also to have life in himself; and he has given him authority to execute judgement, because he is the Son of Man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-2&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gospel of the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-7&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Praise to you, Lord Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-1&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-brief-homily-spiritual-conversation-or-moment-of-silence-may-be-placed-here&#34;&gt;A brief homily, spiritual conversation, or moment of silence may be placed here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence-follows-the-homily&#34;&gt;Silence follows the homily.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-respond-in-faith&#34;&gt;We Respond in Faith&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-387&#34;&gt;BCP 387&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Form III&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father, we pray for your holy Catholic Church;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-8&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That we all may be one.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-1&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grant that every member of the Church may truly and humbly serve you;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-9&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That your Name may be glorified by all people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-2&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all bishops, priests, and deacons;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-10&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be faithful ministers of your Word and Sacraments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-3&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray for all who govern and hold authority in the nations of the world;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-11&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That there may be justice and peace on the earth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-4&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give us grace to do your will in all that we undertake;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-12&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That our works may find favor in your sight.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-5&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have compassion on those who suffer from any grief or trouble;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-13&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That they may be delivered from their distress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-6&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give to the departed eternal rest;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-14&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let light perpetual shine upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-7&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We praise you for your saints who have entered into joy;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-15&#34;&gt;People:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May we also come to share in your heavenly kingdom.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;leader-8&#34;&gt;Leader:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray for our own needs and those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;Silence&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-may-add-their-own-petitions&#34;&gt;The People may add their own petitions.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-adds-a-concluding-collect&#34;&gt;The Celebrant adds a concluding Collect.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-360&#34;&gt;BCP 360&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confession-of-sin&#34;&gt;Confession of Sin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-3&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-kneel-or-stand-as-able-silence-may-be-kept-officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;The people kneel or stand as able. Silence may be kept. Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most merciful God,&lt;br&gt;
we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br&gt;
in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br&gt;
by what we have done,&lt;br&gt;
and by what we have left undone.&lt;br&gt;
We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br&gt;
we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br&gt;
We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br&gt;
For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br&gt;
have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br&gt;
that we may delight in your will,&lt;br&gt;
and walk in your ways,&lt;br&gt;
to the glory of your Name. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;priest&#34;&gt;Priest:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you  in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-16&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-peace&#34;&gt;The Peace&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peace of the Lord be always with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-17&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;we-greet-one-another-in-the-name-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;We greet one another in the name of the Lord.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-are-seated-2&#34;&gt;The people are seated.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-announcements&#34;&gt;The Announcements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;we-offer-ourselves-to-god&#34;&gt;We Offer Ourselves To God&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-altar-is-prepared&#34;&gt;The altar is prepared&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-people-stand-as-able-2&#34;&gt;The people stand as able.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-367&#34;&gt;BCP 367&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-thanksgiving-eucharistic-prayer-b&#34;&gt;The Great Thanksgiving: Eucharistic Prayer B&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord be with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-18&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And also with you.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lift up your hearts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-19&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We lift them to the Lord.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-2&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us give thanks to the Lord our God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-20&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It is right to give God thanks and praise.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is right, and a good and joyful thing, always and everywhere to give thanks to you, Father Almighty, Creator of heaven and earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-proper-preface-may-be-used-here&#34;&gt;A Proper Preface may be used here.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore we praise you, joining our voices with Angels and Archangels and with all the company of heaven, who for ever sing this hymn to proclaim the glory of your Name:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sanctus&#34;&gt;Sanctus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br&gt;
heaven and earth are full of your glory.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;br&gt;
Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord.&lt;br&gt;
Hosanna in the highest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-1&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We give thanks to you, O God, for the goodness and love which you have made known to us in creation; in the calling of Israel to be your people; in your Word spoken through the prophets; and above all in the Word made flesh, Jesus, your Son. For in these last days you sent him to be incarnate from the Virgin Mary, to be the Savior and Redeemer of the world. In him, you have delivered us from evil, and made us worthy to stand before you. In him, you have brought us out of error into truth, out of sin into righteousness, out of death into life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the night before he died for us, our Lord Jesus Christ took bread; and when he had given thanks to you, he broke it, and gave it to his disciples, and said, “Take, eat: This is my Body, which is given for you. Do this for the remembrance of me.” After supper he took the cup of wine; and when he had given thanks, he gave it to them, and said, “Drink this, all of you: This is my Blood of the new Covenant, which is shed for you and for many for the forgiveness of sins. Whenever you drink it, do this for the remembrance of me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, according to his command, O Father,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-and-people-1&#34;&gt;Celebrant and &lt;em&gt;People&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We remember his death,&lt;br&gt;
We proclaim his resurrection,&lt;br&gt;
We await his coming in glory;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-celebrant-continues-2&#34;&gt;The Celebrant continues:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we offer our sacrifice of praise and thanksgiving to you, O Lord of all; presenting to you, from your creation, this bread and this wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We pray you, gracious God, to send your Holy Spirit upon these gifts that they may be the Sacrament of the Body of Christ and his Blood of the new Covenant. Unite us to your Son in his sacrifice, that we may be acceptable through him, being sanctified by the Holy Spirit. In the fullness of time, put all things in subjection under your Christ, and bring us to that heavenly country where, with  blessed Thomas, the Blessed Virgin Mary, and all your saints, we may enter the everlasting heritage of your sons and daughters; through Jesus Christ our Lord, the firstborn of all creation, the head of the Church, and the author of our salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;celebrant-3&#34;&gt;Celebrant:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By him, and with him, and in him, in the unity of the Holy Spirit all honor and glory is yours, Almighty Father, now and for ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-21&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AMEN.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-364&#34;&gt;BCP 364&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lords-prayer&#34;&gt;The Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-1&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now, as our Savior Christ has taught us, we are bold to say,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;officiant-and-people&#34;&gt;Officiant and &lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Father, &lt;strong&gt;who art in heaven,&lt;br&gt;
hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br&gt;
thy kingdom come,&lt;br&gt;
thy will be done,&lt;br&gt;
on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br&gt;
Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br&gt;
And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br&gt;
as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br&gt;
And lead us not into temptation,&lt;br&gt;
but deliver us from evil.&lt;br&gt;
For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br&gt;
for ever and ever.  Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-breaking-of-the-bread&#34;&gt;The Breaking of the Bread&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-2&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alleluia! Christ our Passover is sacrificed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-22&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore let us keep the feast. Alleluia!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-3&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gifts of God for the People of God. Take them in remembrance that Christ died for you, and feed on him in your hearts by faith, with thanksgiving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;pb-1&#34;&gt;pb&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-receive-the-gift-of-god&#34;&gt;We Receive the Gift of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;if-a-person-desires-to-receive-the-sacrament-but-by-reason-of-extreme-sickness-or-physical-disability-is-unable-to-eat-and-drink-the-bread-and-wine-the-celebrant-is-to-assure-that-person-that-all-the-benefits-of-communion-are-received-even-though-the-sacrament-is-not-received-with-the-mouth-bcp-457&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;If a person desires to receive the Sacrament, but, by reason of extreme sickness or physical disability, is unable to eat and drink the Bread and Wine, the Celebrant is to assure that person that all the benefits of Communion are received, even though the Sacrament is not received with the mouth.&amp;rdquo; (BCP, 457)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-ministers-receive-the-sacrament-in-both-kinds-and-then-immediately-deliver-it-to-the-people-all-are-welcome-to-receive-at-christs-table-if-you-would-prefer-to-receive-a-verbal-blessing-instead-of-communion-cross-your-arms-over-your-chest-to-indicate-this&#34;&gt;The ministers receive the Sacrament in both kinds, and then immediately deliver it to the people. All are welcome to receive at Christ&amp;rsquo;s table. If you would prefer to receive a verbal blessing instead of communion, cross your arms over your chest to indicate this.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-post-communion-prayer&#34;&gt;The Post-communion Prayer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;presider-4&#34;&gt;Presider:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us pray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-23&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Almighty and everliving God,&lt;br&gt;
we thank you for feeding us with the spiritual food&lt;br&gt;
of the most precious Body and Blood&lt;br&gt;
of your Son our Savior Jesus Christ;&lt;br&gt;
and for assuring us in these holy mysteries&lt;br&gt;
that we are living members of the Body of your Son,&lt;br&gt;
and heirs of your eternal kingdom.&lt;br&gt;
And now, Father, send us out&lt;br&gt;
to do the work you have given us to do,&lt;br&gt;
to love and serve you&lt;br&gt;
as faithful witnesses of Christ our Lord.&lt;br&gt;
To him, to you, and to the Holy Spirit,&lt;br&gt;
be honor and glory, now and for ever. Amen.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-blessing&#34;&gt;The Blessing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;bcp-366-1&#34;&gt;BCP 366&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dismissal&#34;&gt;The Dismissal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;deacon-4&#34;&gt;Deacon:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go in peace to love and serve the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;people-24&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks be to God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;scriptures-from-new-revised-standard-version-bible-anglicized-edition-copyright--1989-1995-national-council-of-the-churches-of-christ-in-the-united-states-of-america-used-by-permission-all-rights-reserved-worldwide-httpnrsvbiblesorg&#34;&gt;Scriptures from New Revised Standard Version Bible: Anglicized Edition, Copyright © 1989, 1995 National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Used by permission. All rights reserved worldwide. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrsvbibles.org&#34;&gt;http://nrsvbibles.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
